[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50，这是第3周。
This is CS50, and this is week 3.
您会记得上周，我们为您提供了更多工具
And you'll recall that last week, we equipped you with a lot more tools
解决问题的方法-不仅是我们提出的问题，
by which to solve problems-- not only problems that we had proposed,
但是您自己的代码中存在问题，那就是错误。
but problems in your own code, that is to say bugs.
回想一下，这些工具涉及诸如help50之类的命令行工具。
And recall that those tools involve command line tools like help50
获得有关编译器可能发出的隐式错误消息的帮助；
for help with cryptic error messages that the compiler might spit out;
style50，可以给您一些反馈
style50 which, gives you a bit of feedback
关于代码的风格，其美观性；
on the stylization of your code, the aesthetics thereof;
check50，它根据规范检查代码的正确性
check50, which checks the correctness of your code against the specifications
在给定的问题或实验室中； printf，其中
in a given problem set or lab; printf, which
是几乎在任何编程中都以某种形式存在的函数
is a function that it exists in some form in almost any programming
您可能最终会学习的语言
language that you might ultimately learn, and this
只是从计算机的计算机上打印出您想要的任何内容的一种方式
is simply a way of printing out anything you might want from the computer's
内存到屏幕上。
memory onto the screen.
那么也许是这些工具中最强大的
Then perhaps the most powerful of these tools
是debug50，这是此交互式调试器。
was debug50, which was this interactive debugger.
即使此命令debug50特定于CS50，
And even though this command debug50 is a little specific to CS50,
它触发了什么，那个小小的侧窗
what it triggers to happen, that little side window
在这里您可以看到您所使用的功能栈
where you can see the stack of functions that you
可能在某个断点时打电话了，
might have called during some break point,
并且您可以看到您可能在某个时候定义的局部变量
and you can see the local variables that you might have defined at some point
在执行代码的过程中
during the execution of your code, that's
这是使用大多数语言编写的任何调试器的非常常见的常规功能。
a very common conventional feature of any debugger with most any language.
最后，回想一下，有一个ddb，duck调试器，
And then lastly, recall there was this ddb, duck debugger, which
当然，如果您碰巧躺着橡皮鸭，那就采取这种物理形式
of course, takes this physical form, if you happen to have a rubber duck lying
你可以和谁聊天。
around with whom you can talk.
但我很高兴地说，如果你缺乏
But I'm so pleased to say that if you lack
目前在家中，CS50自己的Kareem，Brenda和Sophie
that currently while at home, CS50's own Kareem and Brenda and Sophie
添加了精彩的内容，如果您还没有注意到的话，
have wonderfully added, if you haven't noticed already,
与CS50 IDE相同的虚拟鸭子。
that same virtual duck to CS50 IDE.
因此，如果您单击右上角的
So if you click in the top corner, you can actually
开始和橡皮鸭聊天。
begin to have a chat of sorts with the rubber duck.
虽然这肯定是同一想法的更好玩的化身，
And while this is a certainly more playful incarnation of that same idea,
我们真的不能强调足够的价值
we really can't emphasize enough the value
与某人一起在代码中遇到问题时谈论问题的技巧
of talking through problems when you're experiencing them in code with someone
否则或其他。
else or with something else.
这只鸭子，不是那么大的词汇量，
This particular duck, not all that large of a vocabulary,
但这不是别人所说的，而是你所说的
but it's not so much what the other person says but what you say
和你听到的自己的话无疑是
and what you hear yourself saying that is undoubtedly
这个过程中最有价值的部分。
the most valuable part of the process.
因此，我们感谢Kareem，Brenda和Sophie。
So our thanks to Kareem and Brenda and Sophie on that.
回想上个星期2，我们在引擎盖下看了一眼，
Recall last week, 2, that we took a look underneath the hood,
从某种意义上说，实际上是笔记本电脑中的计算机内存
literally in some sense, at the computer's memory in your laptop
或台式机或手机。
or desktop or phone.
然后我们决定再考虑一下
And then we decided to think about this more
在艺术上只是一个字节的网格。
artistically as just a grid of bytes.
因此，在该芯片中，有一堆比特。
So within that chip, there's a whole bunch of bits.
而且，如果一次查看八个，那么会有一大堆字节。
And if you look at eight of them at a time, there's a whole bunch of bytes.
我们可以认为这是有理由的
And it stands to reason that we could think
作为第一个字节，第二个字节，第三个字节，
of this as the first byte, the second byte, the third byte,
依此类推，然后以图形方式将其切碎
and so forth, and sort of chop this up pictorially
放入计算机内存中的整个字节序列。
into just a whole sequence of bytes in the computer's memory.
回想一下，如果我们放大并仅关注一个连续的块
And recall that if we zoom in on that and focus on just one continuous block
内存，也称为“数组”
of memory, otherwise known as an "array,"
我们可以在此数组中执行操作，例如存储一堆不同的值。
we can do things within this array like storing a bunch of different values.
所以回想一下上周，我们首先定义了一些
So recall last week, we started by defining a little--
愚蠢地，多个几乎完全相同名称的变量，
goofily, multiple variables that were almost identically names,
像scores1，score2，score3。
like scores1, scores2, scores3.
然后，我们开始通过引入数组来清理代码设计，
And then we began to clean up the design of our code by introducing an array,
所以我们只能有一个称为scores的变量，其大小为3
so we can have just one variable called scores, that is of size 3
并且有多个值的余地。
and has room for multiple values.
因此，今天，我们将继续利用许多编程的功能
So today, we'll continue to leverage this feature of many programming
语言-能够连续存储事物，
languages-- being able to store things continuously,
背对背背对背，在计算机的内存中，
back to back to back to back, in a computer's memory,
因为这种非常简单的布局，这种语言的非常简单的功能，
because this very simple layout, this very simple feature of the language,
将开放各种强大的功能。
is going to open up all sorts of powerful features.
实际上，我们甚至可以回顾一些问题
And in fact, we can even revisit some of the problems
我们试图在第0周解决问题。
we tried to solve way back in week 0.
但是数组有一个陷阱。
But there is a catch with arrays.
上周我们并没有真正强调这一点。
And we didn't really emphasize this much last week.
那是因为，即使你我能
And that's because, even though you and I can
瞥了一眼屏幕上的这张图片，马上看到，哦，
glance at this picture on the screen and see immediately that, oh, there's
屏幕上有七个框，您可以在其中七个位置
seven boxes on the screen, there are seven locations in which you
可以存储值，您和我可以对所有事物都具有这种鸟瞰图
can store values, you and I can sort of have this bird's eye view of everything
并立即查看整个阵列中的内容。
and just see what's inside that entire array all at once.
但是，回忆起来，计算机更具方法性，算法性，
But computers, recall, are much more methodical, more algorithmic,
如果可以的话。
if you will.
因此，一台功能强大的计算机，
And so a computer, as powerful as they are,
从技术上讲，一次只能查看一个阵列中的一个位置。
can technically only look at one location in an array at a time.
因此，尽管您和我可以一目了然
So whereas you and I can glance at this and sort of
一口气把它全部收起来一台电脑根本无法看一眼它的内存
take it all in at once a computer just can't glance at its memory
并一次吸收其中的所有值，
and take in all at once all of the values therein,
它必须更加有条理地这样做，例如，从左到右，也许
it has to do so more methodically, for instance, from left to right, maybe
从右到左，也许在中间向前。
right to left, maybe middle onward.
但这必须是一种算法。
But it has to be an algorithm.
因此，今天我们将这一概念形式化，并确实掩盖了以下事实：
And so today we'll formalize that notion and really kind of hide the fact that
无法一次看到所有数组，只能查看一个位置
this array cannot be seen all at once, you can only look at one location
在给定时间的数组中。
in an array at a given time.
这将具有非常实际的意义。
And this is going to have very real implications.
例如，如果我们考虑第一个问题
For instance, if we consider that very first problem
在我们尝试在电话簿中查找我的电话号码的第一周，
in the very first week where we tried to find my phone number in a phone book,
最幼稚的方法是从头开始，从左开始搜索
the very naive approach was to start at the beginning and search from left
在右边。
to right.
此后，我们尝试了几种变体。
And we tried a couple of variants thereafter.
但是，问题很简单，就是搜索问题。
But the problem, quite simply, is that of searching.
这是计算机科学中的艺术术语，
And this is a term of art in computer science,
超级普通，当然对您和我（作为Google用户）
super common, certainly for you and I as users on Google
并喜欢整天搜索事物。
and the like to search for things all day long.
因此，当然可以很好地进行搜索，并精心设计搜索算法，
And so certainly searching well, designing a search algorithm well,
无疑是当今许多工具的引人注目的功能
is certainly a compelling feature of so many of today's tools
你和我用的
that you and I use.
因此，如果我们真的认为这是要解决的问题，
So if we think of this really as a problem to solve,
我们得到了一些输入，例如，可能是数字数组，
we've got some input, which, for instance, might be an array of numbers,
或是Google的一系列网页。
or maybe an array of web pages in the case of Google.
目标是获得一些输出。
And the goal is to get some output.
因此，如果问题的输入是一个值数组，则输出，
So if the input to the problem is an array of values, the output,
希望它会像布尔值一样简单，真的-
hopefully, is going to be something as simple, really, as a bool--
是还是不是。
yes or no.
您寻找的价值是否可以发现？
Is the value you're looking for discoverable?
您是否可以搜索并找到该值，是或否，是或否？
Can you search for and find that value, yes or no, true or false?
现在，回想一下，在这个黑匣子中，将成为某种算法。
Now, within this black box, recall, is going to be some algorithm.
这就是今天我们将花费大部分时间的地方。
And that's where today we'll spend most of our time.
确实，我们不会真正介绍C的更多功能。
Indeed, we won't really introduce that many more features of C.
我们不会介绍更多代码。
We won't introduce that much more code.
我们将再次专注于想法，现在您已经认为是理所当然的了
We'll focus again on ideas, just taking for granted now that you
您的工具箱中还有其他工具。
have some more tools in your toolkit.
除了循环和条件以及布尔表达式之外，
Beyond loops and conditions and Boolean expressions,
现在，我们有了另一种称为数组的工具。
we now have this other tool known as arrays.
但是，让我们先介绍一些其他艺术术语，如果可以的话，用一些术语，
But let's first introduce some other terms of art, some jargon if you will,
与我们称为运行时间有关。
related to what we'll call running time.
因此，我们已经提到了几次。
So we've alluded to this a few times.
当我们在考虑算法的优劣时，
When we're thinking about just how good or bad an algorithm is,
我们描述了运行需要多长时间。
we describe how long it takes to run.
那就是它的运行时间。
That is its running time.
算法的运行时间是需要多长时间-
The running time of an algorithm is how long it takes--
需要多少步骤，需要多少秒，需要多少次迭代
how many steps it takes, how many seconds it takes, how many iterations
它需要。
it takes.
您的度量单位是什么并不重要。
It doesn't really matter what your unit of measure is.
也许是时候了，也许是迭代或其他。
Maybe it's time, maybe it's iterations or something else.
但是运行时间只是指算法要花费多长时间。
But running time just refers to how long does an algorithm take.
我们可以通过一些方式来对此进行更正式的思考。
And there are ways that we can think about this a little more formally.
我们在第一周就已经做到了这一点，
And we kind of did this already in the first week,
但是我们没有给它起这个名字，这个斜体字O，
but we didn't give it this name, this italicized O,
屏幕上的大写O，也称为Big O表示法。
this capital O on the screen, is otherwise known as Big O notation.
还有计算机科学家和一些数学家
And computer scientists and some mathematicians
从字面上看，它将经常使用该符号
will very frequently use, literally, this symbol
描述算法的运行时间，
to describe the running times of algorithms,
或在数学上像一个函数。
or mathematically like a function.
因此，事实上，请记住这张照片。
So recall this picture, in fact.
当我们搜索电话簿时，我们做到了很好，更好，最好。
When we were searching that phone book, we did it sort of good, better, best.
我们是线性进行的-即一次搜索一页，
We did it linearly-- that is, searching one page at a time,
我们一次完成两页的速度是它的两倍-
we did it twice as fast by doing two pages at a time--
然后我们通过对数划分和征服来对数地做到这一点，
and then we did it logarithmically by dividing and conquering,
在一半和一半。
in half and half and half.
当时，我提议如果我们想到电话簿
And at the time, I proposed that if we think of a phone book
如n页，其中n只是计算机科学中的一个数字，
as having n pages, where n is just a number in computer science vernacular,
我们可能会描述运行时间或步骤数
we might describe the running time, or the number of steps
涉及到第一个算法，因为在最坏的情况下可能需要n步。
involved for that first algorithm, as being maybe in the worst case n steps.
如果您正在电话簿中寻找的人
If the person you're looking for in a phone book maybe
英文字母的姓氏以Z开头，
alphabetically has the last name starting with Z in English,
好吧，Z可能一直在电话簿的末尾。
well, the Z might be all the way at the end of the phone book.
因此，在最坏的情况下，您可能会采取n步
So at the worst case, you might be taking n steps
在电话簿中找到像我这样的人。
to find someone like myself in that phone book.
不过，第二种算法的速度是后者的两倍，
The second algorithm, though, was twice as fast,
因为我们一次走了两页。
because we went two pages at a time.
因此，我们可以将其运行时间描述为n除以2。
So we might describe its running time as n divided by 2.
然后是第三种算法，我们将问题分成两半
And then the third algorithm, where we divided the problem in half and half
一半，一次又一次地抛弃了一半的问题，
and half, literally throwing half of the problem away again and again,
是对数的-从技术上讲，以n为底的对数2
was logarithmic-- technically log base 2 of n, which, again, is just
一个数学公式，指的是再减半
a mathematical formula that refers to halving something again
一遍又一遍。
and again and again.
在这种情况下，当然要从n页开始。
And you start with, of course, n pages in that scenario.
好吧，事实证明，计算机科学家实际上会
Well, it turns out that a computer scientist would actually
在其中一些数学细节上挥手致意。
wave their hands at some of these mathematical details.
确实，我们不会养成写作的习惯
Indeed, we're not going to get into the habit of writing
非常精确的数学公式。
very precise mathematical formulas.
相反，我们要做的就是尝试获得
What we're instead going to do is try to get
一种算法运行时间的顺序感
a sense of the order on which the running time of an algorithm
大概是快或慢，但仍然
is, just roughly how fast or how slow it is, but still
使用像n这样的符号作为占位符。
using some symbology like n as a placeholder.
因此，计算机科学家会描述这三个系统的运行时间
And so a computer scientist would describe the running time of all three
从第0周起的那些算法是n的大O或n / 2的大O，
of those algorithms from week 0 as being big O of n, or big O of n/2,
或n的以2为底的对数O。
or big O of log base 2 of n.
因此，“大O”仅表示“按顺序”。
So "big O" just means "on the order of."
有点像挥手。
It's sort of a wave of the hand.
也许是n减1，也许是n加1，也许甚至是2n。
Maybe it's n minus 1, maybe it's n plus 1, maybe it's even 2n.
但这是n或其他值的数量级。
But it's on the order of n or these other values.
但实际上，也要注意此图表
But in fact, too, notice that this chart,
有点好奇，就像前两种算法一样
there's something kind of curious. , Like these first two algorithms from
第0周的图片看起来几乎一样。
week 0 kind of pictorially look pretty much the same.
毫无疑问，黄线稍低
Like undoubtedly, the yellow line is a little lower
因此比红线好一点，快一点。
and therefore a little better and a little faster than the red line.
但是它们具有相同的形状。
But they have the same shape.
实际上，我敢打赌，如果我们将这两条直线缩小，
And in fact, I bet if we zoomed way out, these two straight lines
看起来几乎一样。
would pretty much look identical.
如果您将轴更改为既足够大又足够高，
If you change your axis to be big enough and tall enough,
这些将开始一起模糊。
these would start to blur together.
但显然，绿线是根本不同的。
But clearly, the green line is fundamentally different.
因此，这说明了计算机科学家的趋势
And so this speaks to a computer scientist's tendency
不会真正质疑这些细节。
to not really quibble over these details.
就像是的，第0周的第二种算法更好。
Like, yes, the second algorithm in week 0 was better.
是的，这条黄线更好。
Yes, this yellow line is better.
但是，让我们仅将这两种算法的运行时间称为
But, eh, let's just call both of those algorithms running times
在n的数量级上
on the order of n.
就是说，计算机科学家倾向于抛弃不变的因素，
That is to say, a computer scientist tends to throw away constant factors,
例如1/2或2分频。
like the 1/2 or the divided by 2.
他们倾向于只关注主导因素，
And they tend to focus only on the dominant factor,
就像那个数学表达式中哪个值增长最快，
like which value in that mathematical expression is going to grow the most,
增长最快。
grow the fastest.
n除以2n会逐渐占主导地位。
And n divided by 2n it's going to dominate over time.
电话簿越大，您拥有的页面就越多。
The bigger the phone book gets, the more pages you have.
实际上，n的重要性要小于2的总和。
It's really n that's going to matter less so than that divided by 2.
还有同样的事情。
And same thing over here.
如果您熟悉并记住对数，
If you're familiar with and remember your logarithms,
我们甚至根本不必关心该对数的底数。
we don't really have to even care about the base of that logarithm.
是的，以2为底，但是，我们可以乘以该对数
Yes, it's base 2, but eh, we can just multiply that logarithm
用其他一些数字将其转换为我们想要的任何基数-
by some other number to convert it to any base we want--
以10为底，以3为底，以7为底的任何东西。
base 10, base 3, base 7, anything.
因此，我们只说它在log n的顺序上。
So let's just say it's on the order of log n.
所以这很好，因为这意味着我们不是真的
So this is good, because it means we're not really
会浪费时间真正进入杂草
going to waste time getting really into the weeds
数学上，当我们谈论算法的效率时。
mathematically when we talk about the efficiency of algorithms.
只需用变量n来描述事物就足够了，在这种情况下，
It suffices to describe things really in terms of the variable, n in this case,
如果愿意的话，随着时间的流逝，它会占主导地位。
if you will, that dominates over time.
确实，让我们缩小。
And indeed, let's zoom out.
如果我放大这张照片，请开始
If I zoom out on this picture, boom, you begin
是的，这些真的开始看起来几乎完全相同。
to see that, yeah, these are really starting to look almost identical.
如果我们继续缩小，您会发现它们本质上是
And if we kept zooming out, you would see that they're essentially
一个在同一。
one in the same.
但是绿色的一个引人注目，所以确实在n的对数的顺序上
But the green one stands out, so that's indeed on the order of log of n
与n本身相反。
as opposed to n itself.
所以这是一个小备忘单。
So here's a little cheat sheet.
事实证明，在计算机科学中，
It turns out that within computer science,
在分析算法的过程中，我们
and within the analysis of algorithms, we're
会倾向于看到一些像这样的通用公式。
going to tend to see some common formulas like this.
因此，我们刚刚看到了n的数量级。
So we've just seen on the order of n.
我们已经看到了log n的顺序。
We've seen on the order of log n.
原来，最常见的两次将是n次
It turns out that the very common two is going to be n times
对数n，甚至n平方，然后甚至为1的大O。
log n, maybe even n squared, and then even big O of 1.
最后的那些只是意味着一个算法
And the last of those just means that an algorithm
迈出了精彩的一步-
takes, wonderfully, one step--
或也许两步，甚至十步，但步数不变。
or maybe two steps, maybe even 10 steps, but a constant number of steps.
因此，至少在这些选项中，这是最好的情况。
So that's sort of the best case scenario, at least among these options.
而n平方将开始花费很长时间。
Whereas, n squared is going to start to take a long time.
它会开始变得缓慢，因为如果您
It's going to start to feel slow, because if you
取n的任何值并将其平方，即
take any value of n and square it, that's
将意味着越来越多的步骤。
going to imply more and more steps.
所以，从今天开始，只是一点行话，
So just a bit of jargon, then, to start off today,
现在我们有了这种词汇
whereby we now have this sort of vocabulary
用这个大O来描述算法的运行时间
with which to describe the running times of an algorithm in terms of this Big O
符号。
notation.
但是还有另一种表示法。
But there's one other notation.
就像大O代表上限一样
And just as big O refers to an upper bound
在运行时间方面，例如最大步数
on running times, like how many steps maximally,
一个算法最多可能花费多少时间，
how much time maximally might an algorithm take,
这种欧米茄表示法则相反。
this omega notation refers to the opposite.
算法运行时间的下限是多少？
What's a lower bound on the running time of an algorithm?
而且我们不需要其他图片或其他公式。
And we don't need another picture or other formulas.
我们可以重用相同的一个。
We can reuse the same one.
所以这里的备忘单只是建议
So this cheat sheet here just proposes that,
描述算法的效率或低效率时
when describing the efficiency or inefficiency of an algorithm
而您想提出一个下限-
and you want to come up with a lower bound--
就像最低限度一样，我的算法需要执行多少步骤-
like minimally, how many steps does my algorithm take--
我们可以使用相同的数学公式
we can use the same mathematical formulas,
但我们可以注意到，使用omega而不是bigO。
but we can note that with omega instead of big O.
再说一次，看起来很花哨，但这实际上只是指
So again, looks fancy, but it really just refers
挥动一下手，试图精确地计算出运行时间
to a wave of the hand trying to sort of ballpark exactly what the running time
是一种算法。
is of an algorithm.
幸运的是，我们已经看到了一些算法，
And thankfully, we've seen a few algorithms already,
包括那一周的0，现在我们给它起一个更正式的名字。
including in that week 0, and now we're going to give it a more formal name.
线性搜索就是我们对电话簿的处理
Linear search is what we did with that phone book
首先，逐页搜索，
first off by searching it page by page by page,
在该特定示例中查找我的电话号码。
looking for my phone number in that particular example.
因此，今天的不同之处在于，与我们人类不同，
And so the difference today is that, unlike us humans, who
可以往下看电话簿页面，看到一大堆名字和电话号码
can look down at a phone book page and see a whole bunch of names and numbers
一次不像一个人，他刚才可以看板上的一个阵列
at once, unlike a human who can look at an array on the board a moment ago
并立即看到一切，我们需要
and sort of see everything at once, we need
今天要更加有条理，更深思熟虑
to be more methodical, more deliberate today so
我们现在可以将第0周的想法转化为伪代码，
that we can translate week 0's ideas now, not into even pseudocode,
但是实际的C代码。
but actual C code.
奇妙的是，这里是美国话剧团
And so wonderfully, here at the American Repertory Theater
就像本学期我们在哈佛大学校园里一样，
as we are on Harvard's campus this semester,
我们一直在与整个团队合作
we've been collaborating with the whole team
在这里，我比我更倾向于艺术
here who are much more artistically inclined than certainly I
可能是我一个人在这里。
could be on my own here.
我们有这七个美妙的门
And we have these seven wonderful doors that
以前曾在这里举行的各种戏剧表演中使用
were previously used in various theatrical shows that took place here
在这家剧院。
in this theater.
我们甚至与剧院的道具店进行了合作，
And we've even collaborated with the theater's prop shop,
后面的人美妙地制造了一些令人愉快的数字
who in back have wonderfully manufactured some delightful numbers
并使它们栩栩如生。
and brought them to life.
也就是说，在这七个门的每一个后面都有一个数字。
Which is to say that, behind each of these seven doors is a number.
现在这将是一个机会，可以真正阐明这一点
And this is going to be an opportunity now to really hammer home the point
当我们想在数组中搜索某个数字时，
that when we want to search for some number in an array,
这相当于必须搜索一个号码，在这种情况下，
it's pretty equivalent to having to search for a number, in this case,
在原本关着的门后面。
behind an otherwise closed door.
你和我不能只看所有这些门
You and I can't just look at all of these doors
现在找出数字在哪里。
now and figure out where a number is.
我们必须更有条理。
We have to be more methodical.
我们必须开始搜索这些门，也许
We have to start searching these doors, maybe
从左到右，也许从右到左，也许从中间到外面。
from left to right, maybe from right to left, maybe from the middle on out.
但是，我们需要提出一种算法，并最终将其转换为代码。
But we need to come up with an algorithm and ultimately translate that to code.
例如，假设我要搜索数字0。
So for instance, suppose I were to search for the number 0.
我们如何才能有条不紊地搜索这七个木门
How could we go about searching, methodically, these seven wooden doors
为数字0？
for the number 0?
让我听取观众的建议。
Let me take a suggestion from the audience.
您会采取什么方法？
What approach might you take?
您建议我带着这些门独自在这里采取什么第一步？
What first step would you propose I take here on my own with these doors?
有什么建议吗？
Any recommendations?
我如何开始发现自己的数字为0？
How do I begin to find myself the number 0?
佛罗伦萨，你有什么建议？
Florence, what do you propose?
听众：我建议从左边开始，因为0是一个较小的数字。
AUDIENCE: I would propose starting form the left, since 0 is a smaller number.
大卫·马兰：好的，很好。
DAVID MALAN: OK, good.
和我在那里呆一会儿。
And hang in there for with me for just a moment.
让我继续前进，按照佛罗伦萨的建议从最左边开始。
Let me go ahead and started on the left edge as Florence proposes.
继续并打开门，希望-
Go ahead and open the door, and hopefully, voila--
不。
no.
这是数字4。
It's a number 4.
所以它不是0。
So it's not a 0.
那么佛罗伦萨，你会建议我下一步做什么？
So Florence, what would you propose I do next?
听众：我可能会从中间某处开始，
AUDIENCE: I'd probably start in the middle somewhere,
如果，例如，如果我不知道，它正在下降1。
if, like, in case, I don't know, it's going down by 1.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以也许它正在下降。
So maybe it's going down.
因此，让我继续尝试。
So let me go ahead and try that.
所以您建议中点，我可以在这里过去，瞧……
So you propose middle, I could go over here, and voila--
没有。
nope.
那是数字2。
That's the number 2.
我想知道，我还应该去哪里。
And I wonder, where else should I look.
让我-我有点好奇。
Let me-- I'm a little curious.
我有点不敢理会这些门。
I'm a little nervous that I ignored these doors.
因此，佛罗伦萨，如果您不介意，让我们继续看看这里，并且-
So Florence, if you don't mind, let's go ahead and look here and--
不，这就是数字6。
no, that's the number 6, it seems.
让我们继续前进，在这里检查数字8。
Let's go ahead and check in here, the number 8.
因此，它们有点起伏。
So they're kind of going up and down.
那么佛罗伦萨，我怎么能完成这个号码的搜索呢？
So Florence, how might I finish searching for this number?
您会说还有什么要做？
What remains to be done, would you say?
听众：可能是从现在开始。
AUDIENCE: Probably start from the right now.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以我可以从现在开始，也许只是在这里。
So I could start from the right now, and maybe just go over here.
瞧-就在那里。
And voila-- and there it is.
因此我们找到了数字0。
So we found the number 0.
因此，让我问佛罗伦萨，您的算法是什么？
So let me ask Florence, what was your algorithm?
您如何成功为我们找到数字0？
How did you go about so successfully finding the number 0 for us?
听众：我想我最初是想开始时降低1。
AUDIENCE: I guess I initially tried starting, like, by going down by 1.
就像，如果数字不在左边，
So like, if the number was not at the left,
然后去中间，就像中间
then going to the center, which is, like, halfway in between
然后转到[音频不清晰]。
and then going to [INAUDIBLE].
我不知道。
I don't know.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：有趣的是，这如何为您解决问题，发展到中间？
DAVID MALAN: And playfully, how did that work out for you, going to the middle?
好还是坏，没什么不同？
Better or worse, no different?
听众：我的意思是，我想这可能会有所帮助
AUDIENCE: I mean, I guess maybe it helped a little bit
然后一直向右走。
to then go all the way to the right.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
是的，我们可能已经收集了一些信息。
Yeah, we might have gleaned some information.
但是，让我们继续看一下所有的门。
But let's go ahead and take a look at all of the doors for a moment.
再有4和6。
There's that 4 and the 6 again.
这又是8点。
Here is that 8 again.
在中间，我们又有2个。
Over in the middle we have the 2 again.
在这里，我们第一次有7。
Over here we have a 7 for the first time.
在这里，我们有一个5。
Over here we have a 5.
然后，当然，我们有一个0。
And then of course, we have a 0.
老实说，如果您把所有这些都带进了佛罗伦萨，您和我，
And if you took all of that in, honestly, Florence, you and I,
我们真的无法做得更好。
we couldn't really have done any better.
因为这些门-这些数字证明，
Because these door-- these numbers, it turns out,
只是随机地排列在这些门的后面。
are just randomly arranged behind these doors.
因此，您跳来跳去也算不错。
So it wasn't bad at all that you kind of hopped around.
虽然缺点是如果您跳来跳去，
Although, the downside is if you hop around,
您和我作为人类可以很容易地记住我们去过的地方。
you and I as humans can pretty easily remember where we've been before.
但是，如果您考虑我们如何将其转换为代码，
But if you think about how we would translate that to code,
我觉得我们开始积累一堆变量
I feel like we're starting to accumulate a bunch of variables
也许是因为您必须对此进行跟踪。
maybe, because you have to keep track of that.
坦率地说，也许最简单的解决方案-哎呀-
So frankly, maybe the simplest solution-- whoops--
也许最简单的解决方案应该是我们在第0周开始的地方，
maybe the simplest solution would have been where we started in week 0,
在这里，我们只是采取一种非常简单但简单的方法来开始
where we just take a very simple if naive approach of starting
与我们的数组，这次的大小为7，后面是一些数字。
with our array, this time of size 7, behind which are some numbers.
如果您对这些数字一无所知，
And if you don't know anything about those numbers,
老实说，您可以做的最好的事情就是从第0周开始进行相同的线性搜索，
honestly the best you can do is just that same linear search from week 0,
然后一次检查每个门后面的值
and just check, one at a time, the values behind each of these doors
并希望最终您能找到它。
and just hope that eventually you will find it.
因此，这已经花费了很多时间，对吗？
So this is already sort of taking a lot of time, right?
如果像第0周一样进行这种线性搜索，
If I do this linear search approach like I did in week 0,
我可能将不得不在所有这些门后面进行搜索。
I'm potentially going to have to search behind all of those doors.
我将不得不在所有这些门后面进行搜索。
I'm going to have to search behind all of those doors.
因此，让我们更正式地考虑一下我至少应该如何实现
So let's consider a little more formally exactly how I could at least implement
该算法。
that algorithm.
因为我可以采取佛罗伦萨
Because I could take the approach that Florence
建议的，只是有点跳来跳去，也许使用
proposed, and just kind of jumping around and maybe using
有点直觉。
a bit of intuition.
但这又不是一个真正的算法。
But again, that's not really an algorithm.
我们确实需要逐步做更多的事情。
We really need to do something more step by step.
同时，让我们继续前进，乔，让我们闭上帷幕
And in the meantime, let's go ahead, Joe, and let's close the curtain
看看我们是否无法马上解决另一个问题，
and see if we can't clean those up with another problem in a moment,
现在我们考虑线性搜索及其分析。
while we consider now linear search and the analysis thereof.
因此，对于线性搜索，我建议
So with linear search, I would propose that we
如果可以的话，可以先用伪代码实现它。
could implement it in pseudocode first, if you will, like this.
对于从0到n减去1的i--
For i from 0 to n minus 1--
我们将看到我们要去的地方-如果数字在第i门的后面，
we'll see where we're going with this-- if the number is behind the i-th door,
返回true，否则最后返回false。
return true, otherwise at the very end return false.
所以这是一个相对简单的伪代码翻译，
So it's a relatively simple translation into pseudocode,
就像我们前一段时间使用电话簿一样。
much like we did with the phone book some time ago.
但是，为什么要使用这些值呢？
And why, though, these values?
因为我现在开始更像C来表达自己，
Because I'm now starting to express myself a little more like C,
即使它仍然是伪代码。
even though it's still pseudocode.
因此，对于我，从0到n减去1。
So for i from 0 to n minus 1.
因此，计算机科学家倾向于从0开始计数。
So computer scientists tend to start counting from 0.
如果有n个门，或在这种情况下为7个门，则您要从0一直上升到6，
If there's n doors, or 7 doors in this case, you want to go from 0 on up to 6,
或从0到n减1。
or from 0 on up to n minus 1.
因此，这只是使用for循环进行设置的一种非常常见的方式，
So this is just a very common way of setting yourself up with a for loop,
也许在C中，在这种情况下可能在伪代码中，
maybe in C, maybe in pseudocode in this case, that
会逐步从算法上使您从左到右。
just gets you from left to right, algorithmically step by step.
如果有条件，数字在第i门后面-
If a condition, number is behind the i-th door--
我只是口语化的说法，
i-th just being a colloquial way of saying,
第i个位置的门后面是什么-
what is behind the door at location i--
继续并返回true。
go ahead and return true.
我发现自己想要的号码，例如，号码0。
I have found myself the number I want, for instance, the number 0.
然后请注意，此return false不属于else的一部分，
And then notice that this return false is not part of an else,
因为我不想过早地中止该算法而只是中止
because I don't want to abort this algorithm prematurely and abort simply
因为数字不在当前门后面。
because a number is not behind the current door.
我本质上想一直等到算法结束，
I essentially want to wait all the way to the end of the algorithm,
在我检查了所有n扇门之后，如果仍然没有找到
after I've checked all n doors, and if I have still not found
我关心的数字，然后只有这样，我才返回false。
the number I care about, then and only then am I going to return false.
所以很常见的编程错误
So a very common programming mistake might
将其内部嵌套，并根据if和else来思考事物。
be to nest this internally and think about things in terms of ifs and elses.
但是您不需要其他。
But you don't need to have an else.
在最后，这是一个包罗万象的地方。
This is kind of a catchall here at the very end.
但是现在让我们考虑一下，如果这是线性搜索的伪代码，那么
But now let's consider, if this is the pseudocode for linear search, just what
搜索的效率是多少？
is the efficiency of linear search?
线性搜索的效率是多少，也就是说，
What is the efficiency of linear search, which is to say,
该算法的设计水平如何？
how well-designed is this algorithm?
我们刚才放了一个框架，或者给了我们一个框架，
We put or gave ourselves a framework a moment ago,
大O表示法，这是一个上限，我们现在可以想到
Big O notation, which is an upper bound, which we can think of for now
就像最坏的情况一样。
as meaning like a worst case.
在最坏的情况下，找到数字0可能需要花费几步-
In the worst case, how many steps might it take me to find the number 0--
或任何与此有关的数字-
or any number for that matter--
在n门之间？
among n doors?
是n的大O平方，n的大O是log n，n的大O，
Is it big O of n squared, big O of n times log n, big O of n,
log n的大O或1的大O，这再次意味着
big O of log n, or big O of one, which, again, just means
固定数量的步骤？
a constant fixed number of steps?
布莱恩，我们可以继续提出这个问题吗？
Brian, could we go ahead and pull up this question?
让我继续并将其拉到屏幕上。
Let me go ahead and pull it up on my screen as well.
如果您访问我们常用的网址来提出您认为的上限
If you go to our usual URL to propose what you think an upper bound
是线性搜索的运行时间。
is on the running time of linear search.
好的。
OK.
确实，如果我们现在考虑线性搜索的运行时间，
Indeed, if we consider now the running time of linear search,
这将是n的大O。
it's going to be big O of n.
这是为什么？
Why is that?
所以在最坏的情况下，我要寻找的号码
So in the worst case, the number I'm looking for,
0，很可能位于该列表的末尾，即
0, might very well be at the end of that list, which
将以n步为单位，或者在这种情况下恰好是n步。
is going to be on the order of n steps, or in this case precisely n steps.
因此，这是考虑此问题的一种方法。
So that's one way to think about this.
好吧，现在让我问一个后续问题。
Well, now let me ask a follow-up question.
相反，建议我们考虑欧米茄符号，这是一个下限
Proposing instead that we consider omega notation, which is a lower bound
在算法的运行时间上
on the running time of an algorithm--
布莱恩，我们可以继续问下这个问题吗？
Brian, could we go ahead and ask this question next?
在相同的网址，我们现在会看到一个问题
At that same URL, we'll see a question asking now
对于运行时间的可能答案-
for the possible answers for the running time--
线性搜索运行时间的下限。
for a lower bound on the running time of linear search.
因此，让我们继续来看这里。
So let's go ahead and take a look at this one here.
片刻之内，我们将看到响应的出现，
And in just a moment, we'll see as the responses come in,
大约有百分之七十五以上的人在提议
about 75-plus percent of you are proposing
实际上是1的欧米茄
that it's actually omega of 1.
因此，欧米茄是一个下限。
So omega is a lower bound.
1表示恒定时间。
1 refers to constant time.
那为什么呢？
And why is that?
让我就这一点做一个简短的回答。
Let me just take a quick answer on this point.
在您说一个步骤或固定步骤数的75％的人中，
Among the 75% of you who said one step, or a constant number of steps,
这是为什么？
why is that?
您如何看待运行时间的下限？
How do you think about this lower bound on running time?
从基思那里怎么样？
How about from Keith?
为什么是1的欧米茄？
Why omega of 1?
听众：是的，您可以打开它，很幸运，可以在第一扇门找到它。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, you can just open it and be lucky and find it in the first door.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
所以这确实说明了这一点。
So it really speaks to just that.
您可能会很幸运，而且正在寻找所需的电话号码
You might just get lucky, and the number you're looking for
可能在第一扇门。
might be at the very first door.
因此，在最佳情况下，如果可能的话，此算法的下限是
So the lower bound, in the best case, if you will, of this algorithm,
正是由于这个原因，线性搜索很可能是1的Ω
linear search might very well be omega of 1 for exactly that reason--
拥有的-幸运的是，元素
that you have-- get lucky and the element
可能一开始就在那里。
might be there at the beginning.
很好。
So that's pretty good.
您确实不能做得更好。
You really can't do any better than that.
所以我们现在的这个范围的下限从1的欧米茄到n的大O
So we this range now of a lower bound from omega of 1 on up to big O of n
是线性搜索运行时间的上限。
being an upper bound on the running time of linear search.
但是，当然，我们的工具包中还有其他算法。
But of course, we have this other algorithm in our toolkit.
回想第0周的内容，我们研究了二进制搜索-尽管，
And recall from week 0 that we looked at binary search-- although,
不一定是名字。
not necessarily by name.
那是第三个分治法，我们拿了电话簿
It was that divide-and-conquer third algorithm, where we took the phone book
然后再将它一分为二
and split it in half and half and half again.
现在，当我在那儿摸索的时候，乔好心地给了我们一套新的门。
Now, while I fumbled there, Joe kindly has given us a new set of doors.
如果是乔，您可以继续说出我们的七扇门，
If Joe, you could go ahead and reveal our seven doors again,
后面我们还有一些数字。
behind which we still have some numbers.
但是我认为这一次，我会变得更好。
But I think this time, I'm going to be a little better off.
提示乔和后面的门。
Cue Joe and the doors behind.
好了
There we go.
因此，我们有七个相同的门。
So we have our same seven doors.
但是，在这些门后面现在是一个不同的数字排列方式。
But behind those doors now is a different arrangement of numbers.
假设这次，我想找到自己的数字6。
And suppose this time, I want to find myself the number 6.
因此，数字6 –我们将稍作更改，
So the number 6-- we'll change the problem slightly--
但是这次我要再给你一种成分
but I'm going to give you one other ingredient this time,
这将是这项工作的关键。
which is going to be key to this working.
为什么佛罗伦萨和我之前做不到线性搜索？
Why were Florence and I able to do no better than linear search before?
为什么佛罗伦萨和我不能做得更好
Why were Florence and I able to do no better
比上次随机搜索还多？
than randomly searching even last time?
关于数字数组或数组是什么
What was it about the array of numbers, or the array
门，那以前不允许我使用二进制搜索？
of doors, that did not allow me previously to use binary search?
虹膜，您怎么看？
Iris, what do you think?
听众：因为我们不知道数字是否排序。
AUDIENCE: Because we didn't know the numbers are sorted or not.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
我们不知道数字是否已排序。
We didn't know if the numbers were sorted or not.
的确，除非如此，佛罗伦萨和我
And indeed, barring that detail, Florence and I
确实比线性搜索做得更好。
really couldn't have done any better than, say, linear search.
所以这次，乔帮了一些忙
So this time, though, Joe has kindly sorted some numbers
这些门后面对我们来说。
behind these doors for us.
因此，如果我想搜索数字6，
And so if I want to search for the number 6,
现在我可以开始使用这些信息了。
now I can begin to use a bit of that information.
所以，您知道吗，我将像对待电话簿一样开始
So you know what, I'm going to start just like we did with the phone book
然后从中间开始
and start roughly in the middle.
瞧，第5位。
And voila, number 5.
好的。
All right.
所以我们非常接近，我们也非常接近。
So we're pretty close, we're pretty close.
但是关于二分查找，回想，
But the thing about binary search, recall,
就是现在这是有用的信息。
is that this is now useful information.
如果这些数字都排在这些门的后面，则所有门都在左侧
If the numbers are sorted behind these doors all, of the doors to the left
应该小于5，并且所有门都在右边
should presumably be lower than 5, and all of the doors to the right
应该大于5。
should presumably be larger than 5.
现在，我可能会在这里偷工减料，好吧，如果是5岁，
Now, I might kind of cut a corner here and be like, well, if this is 5,
从字面上看，6可能就在隔壁。
6 is probably right next door, literally.
但是再次，从算法上讲，我们应该怎么做呢？
But again, algorithmically, how might we do this?
我们不想考虑这些特殊情况。
We don't want to necessarily consider these special cases.
因此，更一般地说，我现在有一个大小为3的数组。
So more generally, it looks like I now have an array of size 3.
因此，让我继续并将相同的算法voila应用于中间。
So let me go ahead and apply that same algorithm, voila, to the middle.
现在我有数字7。
Now I have the number 7.
现在非常清楚的是，如果存在数字6，
And now it's becoming pretty clear that if the number 6 is present,
它可能在这扇门后面。
it's probably behind this door.
确实，如果我现在看一下剩下的1号阵列，瞧，
And indeed, if I now look at my remaining array of size 1, and voila,
中间有那个数字6。
in the middle there is that number 6.
所以这一次，我只需要打开三扇门，而不是全部打开七扇门，
So this time, I only had to open up three doors instead of all seven,
可能，或者可能是所有六个门找到通往该数字的方式，
potentially, or maybe all six doors to find my way to that number,
因为我得到了所有这些额外的成分
because I was given this additional ingredient of all
这些数字中进行排序。
of those numbers being sorted.
这样看来，您可以申请
So it would seem, then, that you can apply
更好，更高效，设计更完善的算法，现已广为人知
the better, more efficient, better designed algorithm, now known
作为二进制搜索，如果只有像Joe这样的人会为您对数字进行排序
as binary search, if only someone like Joe would sort the numbers for you
提前。
in advance.
现在让我们考虑一下算法
So let's consider now a little more algorithmically
我们如何实现这一目标。
how we might implement this.
因此，对于二进制搜索，让我提出这个伪代码。
So with binary search, let me propose this pseudocode.
如果数字在中间门后面，请返回true-我们找到了。
If the number is behind the middle door, return true-- we found it.
因此，如果我们很幸运，那么我们可能会很好
So if we got lucky, then we might very well
在中间门后面找到了6号，
have found the number 6 behind the middle door,
而且我们会做的很好。
and we would have been done.
但是那没有发生。
But that didn't happen.
在一般情况下，这可能不会发生。
And in the general case that probably won't happen.
因此，如果数量少于中间门后面的数量，则
So if the number is less than that behind the middle door, then
就像电话簿一样，我要走到左边，
just like with the phone book, I'm going to go to the left,
我将搜索阵列中其余门的左半部分。
and I'm going to search the left half of the remaining doors in the array.
否则，如果这个数字大于中间门后面的数字，
Else if the number is greater than that behind the middle door,
然后像电话簿一样，我将继续搜索
then like the phone book I'm going to go ahead and search
电话簿的右半部分。
the right half of the phone book.
但是可能仍然有最后一种情况，
But there might still be one final case potentially,
因此，如果根本没有门，或者一开始就没有门，
whereby if there's no doors left at all, or no doors in the first place,
我至少应该有一种特殊情况，我确实说return false。
I should at least have this one special case where I do say return false.
例如，如果6，无论出于何种原因，都不在这些门之列
For instance, if 6, for whatever reason, weren't be among those doors
我一直在寻找它，我仍然需要
and I were searching for it, I still need
能够处理我可以明确地说的那种情况
to be able to handle that situation where I can say definitively
如果我没有其他可搜索的门，则返回false。
return false if I'm left with no further doors to search.
因此，这里可能更正式地是该算法的伪代码。
So here, then, might be the pseudocode for this algorithm a bit more formally.
现在让我们考虑对其进行分析。
Now let's consider the analysis thereof.
在此之前，线性搜索是n的大O。
Before, where we left off, linear search was big O of n.
线性搜索为n的大O。
Linear search was big O of n.
这次让我们考虑一下二进制搜索的实际位置
This time let's consider where binary search actually falls into place
通过问一个不同的问题。
by asking a different question.
我要继续前进，现在回问这个问题-
I'm going to go ahead and go back and ask this question now--
二进制搜索的运行时间上限是多少？
what's an upper bound on the running time of binary search?
二进制搜索运行时间的上限-
An upper bound on the running time of binary search--
并继续嗡嗡作响，如果您愿意的话，也可以像以前一样。
and go ahead and buzz in, if you'd like, similarly to before.
二进制搜索的运行时间上限是多少？
What's an upper bound on the running time of binary search?
并且您可以看到在这里，答案在log n周围变得相当占主导地位。
And you can see here answers are getting pretty dominant around log n.
确实，这与我们在第0周所做的事情息息相关。
And indeed, that jives with exactly what we did in week 0.
正确答案的确是n的对数，因为那是
The correct answer is indeed log of n, because that's
将是您的最大次数
going to be the maximum number of times that you
可以获取给定大小的列表或数组
can take a list or an array of a given size
并分成一半一半，直到你
and split it in half and half and half, until you
找到您要寻找的号码，或者最终找到您
find the number you're looking for, or ultimately you
根本找不到那个数字。
don't find that number at all.
同时，如果我们现在不仅仅考虑该算法的上限，
Meanwhile, if we consider now not just the upper bound on this algorithm--
因此，在最坏的情况下，二进制搜索会占用log n的大O--
so in the worst case, binary search takes big O of log n--
现在让我们考虑一个相关的问题
now let's consider a related question which
是，相同算法的运行时间的下限是多少？
is, what's a lower bound on the running time of this same algorithm?
运行时间的下限是多少？
What's a lower bound on the running time?
我会继续把这个摘下来
I'll go ahead and pluck this one off myself
然后回到到目前为止的一些建议。
and go back to some of the suggestions thus far.
在最好的情况下，也许您也很幸运，
In the best case, maybe, too, you do get lucky,
以及您要查找的号码6或其他号码，
and the number you're looking for, 6 or some other number,
在阵列中间打点DAB。
is smack dab in the middle of the array.
因此，也许您确实可以只迈出一步。
And so maybe indeed you can get away with just one step.
确实，现在二进制搜索的下限可能会很好
And indeed, a lower bound on binary search now might very well just
等于1的欧米茄，因为在最佳情况下，您会很幸运，
be an omega of 1, because in that best case you just get lucky,
在这里碰巧是正确的起点，就在中间。
and it's right where you happen to start, in this case in the middle.
因此，我们似乎有一个范围。
So we seem to have a range there.
但是严格来说，二进制搜索似乎更好。
But strictly speaking, it would seem that binary search is better.
二进制搜索优于线性搜索，
Binary search is better than linear search,
因为随着n变大，变大，变大，您真的可以感觉到这种差异。
because as n gets big, big, big, you can really feel that difference.
实际上，从第0周起，我们就使用了这些灯泡。
In fact, recall from week 0 we played a little bit with these light bulbs.
现在，所有这些灯泡中的全部64个都已打开。
And right now, all 64 of these light bulbs are on.
让我们考虑一下，只是为了了解这一点，
And let's consider for a moment, just to put this into perspective,
使用线性搜索查找需要多长时间
how long it would take to use linear search to find
在这64个灯泡中，只有一个灯泡。
one light bulb among these 64.
并记得在最坏的情况下，可能是灯泡或数字
And recall that in the worst case, maybe the light bulb, or the number
我们正在寻找的是在最后
that we're looking for, is way down there at the end,
但我们事先不知道。
but we don't know in advance.
因此，萨姆纳（Sumner），如果您不介意执行线性搜索
And so Sumner, if you wouldn't mind executing linear search
在这些灯泡上，让我们来感受一下效率
on these light bulbs, let's just get a feel for the efficiency
或此算法效率低下。
or inefficiency of this algorithm.
灯泡形式的线性搜索。
Linear search in light bulb form.
因此，您会一次注意到一个灯泡
So you'll notice that one light bulb at a time
出门了，暗示我已经搜索了那扇门，搜索了那扇门，
is going out, implying that I've searched that door, searched that door,
搜索那扇门。
searched that door.
但是我们只经历了10个左右的灯泡，
But we've only gone through 10 or so bulbs,
我们还有50多个。
and we've got another 50-plus to go.
您会看到，如果我们每秒看一眼这些门，
And you can see that if we look inside of these doors one per second,
或每秒关掉这些灯泡，这将需要很长时间。
or turn off these light bulbs one per second, it's going to take a long time.
实际上，似乎没有必要等到最后。
In fact, it doesn't seem worthwhile to even wait until the very end.
所以萨姆纳，如果您不介意，让我们把所有的灯光都放回原处，
So Sumner, if you wouldn't mind, let's bring all the lights back up,
然后再尝试另一种算法，这个二进制搜索，
and let's try once more another algorithm, this one binary search, just
再次感觉到算法的运行时间是多少，
to get, again, a feel of what the running time is of an algorithm,
例如以对数时间运行的二进制搜索。
like binary search that runs in logarithmic time.
因此，稍后，我们将继续执行二进制搜索
So in just a moment, we'll go ahead and execute binary search
在这些灯泡上，想法是我们关心一个灯泡。
on these light bulbs, the idea being that there's one bulb we care about.
让我们看看我们能以多快的速度降到64个灯泡中的一个。
Let's see how fast we can get down to just one bulb out of 64.
因此，萨姆纳（Sumner），以您的意愿，开始前进。
So Sumner, on your marks, get set, go.
几步后，我们就完成了。
And we're done just a few steps later.
然后有这个唯一的灯泡。
And then have this sole light bulb.
那快得多了。
That was so much faster.
实际上，我们一次故意进行了一次迭代。
And in fact, we did this deliberately one iteration at a time.
我们刚刚在萨姆纳和马特的帮助下执行的算法，
The algorithm that we just executed with Sumner's and Matt's help,
在算法上以1赫兹，1赫兹的频率运行
algorithmically was operating at what's called 1 hertz, 1 hertz.
而且，如果您不熟悉赫兹，那么每秒仅是一件事。
And if you're unfamiliar with hertz, it's just one something per second.
它非常常用于物理学中或仅用于电的讨论中
It's very often used in physics or just in discussions of electricity
更普遍。
more generally.
实际上，在这种情况下，如果您每秒要做一件事，
And indeed, in this case if you're doing one thing per second,
第一个算法，线性搜索，可能要花我们64秒
that first algorithm, linear search, might have taken us like 64 seconds
一直到最后一个灯泡。
to get all the way to that final light bulb.
但是第二种算法是对数的。
But that second algorithm was logarithmic.
因此，从64到32到16到8到4到2到1，
And so by going from 64 to 32 to 16 to 8 to 4 to 2 to 1,
即使以相同的速度前进，我们也能更快地获得最终结果。
we get to the final result much faster, even going at the same pace.
因此，实际上，如果您想到计算机的CPU，
So in fact, if you think of your computer's CPU,
CPU的单位也是赫兹
CPUs are also measured in hertz--
赫兹。大概以千兆赫为单位
H-E-R-T-Z. Probably measured in gigahertz,
每秒数十亿赫兹。
which is billions of hertz per second.
因此，您的CPU，计算机的大脑如果是1 GHz，
So your CPU, the brain of your computer, If it's 1 gigahertz,
这意味着它一次可以完成10亿件事情。
that means it can literally do 1 billion things at a time.
在这里，我们使用灯泡进行这种更简单的设置
And here we have this sort of simpler setup of just light bulbs doing
每秒一件事。
one thing per second.
您的计算机可以一次执行10亿种此类操作。
Your computer can do 1 billion of these kinds of operations at once.
因此，请想象一下，这些节省的趋势有多大
So just imagine, therefore, how much these savings tend
如果您可以一次从这些问题中解脱出来，那么随着时间的推移就会加起来，
to add up over time if you can take big bites out of these problems at once,
而不是像我们一周所做的那样
as opposed to doing things like we did in week
0，一次仅一步。
0, just one single step at a time.
好的。
All right.
好吧，现在让我们开始将其转换为代码。
Well, let's now go ahead and start to translate this to code.
我认为C语言的工具包中有足够的工具，
We have enough tools in our toolkit in C that I think,
根据我们上周对数组的讨论，
based on our discussion of arrays last week,
现在，我们实际上可以开始自己构建代码了。
we can now actually start to build something in code on our own.
所以我将继续在这里创建一个文件，
So I'm going to go ahead and create a file here in just a moment,
在CS50 IDE中，例如，称为number.c。
in CS50 IDE, called, for instance, numbers.c.
让我继续将其转换为C数字文件，称为numbers.c。
Let me go ahead and translate this to a file in C code called numbers.c.
目前的目标只是在代码中实现线性搜索，
The goal at hand is just to implement linear search in code,
只是为了让我们不再对伪代码挥手
just so that we're no longer waving our hands at the pseudocode
但做些更具体的事情。
but doing things a little more concretely.
因此，我将继续包含cs50.h。
So I'm going to go ahead and include cs50.h.
我将继续添加stdio.h。
I'm going to go ahead and include stdio.h.
我将从没有命令行参数开始，
And I'm going to start with no command line arguments,
就像我们上周离开时一样，但主要是无效的。
like we left off last week, but just with main void.
我要继续给自己一些数字，
And I'm going to go ahead and give myself an array of numbers,
七个数字，就像门一样。
seven numbers, just like the doors.
我将继续讲int数。
And I'm going to go ahead and say int numbers.
然后这是我们上周没有看到的小技巧，
And then this is a little trick that we didn't see last week,
但是在以下情况下创建数组很方便
but it's handy for creating an array when
你事先知道你想要什么号码，我要做什么，
you know in advance what numbers you want, which I do,
因为我要模仿乔在这里为我们设置的门，我是
because I'm going to mimic the doors that Joe kindly set up for us here, I'm
继续说给我一个等于4、6、8、2、7的数组
going to go ahead and say give me an array that is equal to 4, 6, 8, 2, 7,
5、0。
5, 0.
这是我们上周没有看到的功能。
And this is the feature we didn't see last week.
如果您事先知道要分配给数组的数字，
If you know in advance the numbers that you want to assign to an array,
您实际上不必费心指定数组的大小
you actually don't have to bother specifying the size of the array
明确地。
explicitly.
编译器可以为您明智地解决这一问题。
The compiler can figure that out intelligently for you.
但是您可以将这些花括号与逗号一起使用
But you can use these curly braces with commas
内部从左到右枚举值
inside to enumerate from left to right the values
您想要放入该数组中。
that you want to put into that array.
因此，在我的计算机中执行了第6行之后，
So after this line 6 has executed in my computer,
我将剩下一个叫做数字的数组，
I'm going to be left with an array called numbers,
其中列出了七个整数
inside of which are seven integers listed
可以这么说，从左到右在计算机的内存中。
from left to right in the computer's memory, so to speak, in this way.
现在，我要如何处理这些数字？
Now, what do I want to do with these numbers?
好吧，让我们实现线性搜索。
Well, let's implement linear search.
线性搜索，正如我们之前提到的，
Linear search, as we latched on to earlier,
是从左到右或等效地从右到左的搜索-
is a searching from left to right or equivalently right to left--
但惯例倾向于从左到右。
but convention tends to go left to right.
因此，我将为循环做一个标准。
So I'm going to do a standard for loop.
对于int我得到0，我小于-
For int i gets 0, i is less than--
我现在将其简化并对此进行硬编码，
I'm going to keep it simple for now and hardcode this,
但是我们可以根据需要清理它，我将在每一个上执行i ++
but we could clean this up if we want, and I'm going to do i++ on each
迭代。
iteration.
所以我很确定我的第8行会引发一个for循环，
So I'm pretty sure that my line 8 will induce a for loop that
总共重复八次。
iterates eight total times.
在每次迭代中我想问什么问题？
And what question do I want to ask on each iteration?
好吧，如果位置i处的数字数组等于-
Well, if the numbers array at location i equals equals--
例如，我最初搜索的号码，
for instance, the number I was searching for initially,
让我们继续搜索0-
let's go ahead and search for 0--
那我想怎么办？
then what do I want to do?
让我继续打印出一些任意但有用的内容，
Let me go ahead and print out something arbitrary but useful,
就像“找到”，引用，取消引用一样，因此人类知道。
like "Found," quote, unquote, so the human knows.
然后，让我继续前进，只是为了好措施，让我继续前进
And then let me go ahead, and just for good measure, let me go ahead
并返回0。
and return 0.
我们将在片刻后再谈到这一点。
And we'll come back to that in just a moment.
但在该程序结束时，我还将执行此操作– printf“未找到”
But at the end of this program, I'm also going to do this-- printf "Not found"
反斜杠
with a backslash n.
然后我将继续并返回1。
And then I'm going to go ahead and return 1.
但是在我们梳理那些回报之前，
But before we tease apart those returns, just
考虑汇总中的代码。
consider the code in the aggregate.
这是我的整个主要功能。
Here's my entire main function.
在第6行，回顾一下，我初始化了数组，
And on line 6, to recap, I initialized the array,
就像我们一开始所做的那样，看似随机的数字列表
just as we did at the very beginning, with a seemingly random list of numbers
在门后面。
behind the doors.
然后在第8行，我将使用此for循环进行迭代
Then on line 8, I'm going to iterate with this for loop
共七个时间，每回合增加i。
seven total times, incrementing i in each turn.
然后是10号线，就像我一次打开一扇门一样，
And then line 10, just like I was opening the doors one at a time,
我要检查此数组中的第i个数字
I'm going to check if the i-th number in this array
equals等于我在第一个演示中关心的数字0。
equals equals the number I care about, 0, with that first demo.
我将打印“找到”。
I'm going to print "Found."
否则-本身不是其他-否则，
Otherwise-- not else, per se-- but otherwise,
如果我经历了整个循环，请检查是否，是否，是否，是否和
if I go through this entire loop, checking if, if, if, if, if, and I
从来没有真正找到0，我将在最后使用这个包包
never actually find 0, I'm going to have this catchall at the end that just
表示无论如何，如果到达第16行，则打印“未找到”，
says no matter what, if you reach line 16, print "Not found,"
然后返回1。
and then return 1.
现在，这有点微妙。
Now, this is a bit of a subtlety.
但是有人可以提醒我们返回0到底是怎么回事
But could someone remind us what's going on with the return 0
在第13行，在行17返回1？
on line 13 and the return 1 on line 17?
为什么0比1，为什么我要返回？
Why 0 in 1, and why am I returning at all?
这对我来说解决了什么问题？
What problem is this solving for me?
即使到目前为止我们的大多数程序
Even though most of our programs thus far,
我们对此并没有太在意。
we haven't bothered too much with this.
黛咪，是吗？
Demi, is it?
你怎么认为？
What do you think?
听众：是黛咪，但基本上是返回0
AUDIENCE: It's Demi, but basically, return 0
就像它已正确执行，还是找到了，
is like it was executed correctly, or it found it,
并存在一个退出循环，说已找到它。
and it kind of exits that loop saying that it was found.
然后return 1就像return false一样，它也退出。
And then return 1 is like the return false, and it exits as well.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
而“退出”确实是有效的词。
And "exit" really is the operative word.
总的来说，当您完成后-
In main, when you are done--
准备退出程序，就像我们用单词做完一样
ready to quit the program, as we've done with the word
过去在某些伪代码中“退出”后，您可以按字面值返回一个值。
"quit" in some of our pseudocode in the past, you can literally return a value.
回想上周末，我们介绍了事实
And recall at the end of last week, we introduced the fact
该main始终返回一个int。
that main always returns an int.
您和我至少一两个星期都忽略了这一点，
You and I have ignored that for at least a week or two,
但是有时候返回一个明确的值很有用，
but sometimes it's useful to return an explicit value,
是否用于自动分级，是否
whether it's for autograding purposes, whether it's
用于在现实世界中自动测试您的代码，
for automated testing of your code in the real world,
或只是向用户发出信号，表明确实发生了某些情况
or just so it's a signal to the user that something indeed went
错误的。
Wrong.
因此，您可以从main返回一个值。
So you can return a value from main.
正如Demi所提议的，0表示“一切都很好”。
And as Demi proposed, 0 means "all is well."
这有点违反直觉，因为
And it's a little counter-intuitive, because
到目前为止，正确往往是一件好事。
thus far true tends to be a good thing.
但是在这种情况下，0是一件好事。
But in this case, 0 is a good thing.
一切都很好。
All is well.
成功了
It's success.
如果您返回任何其他值，例如1，
And if you return any other value, for instance 1,
这表明出了点问题。
that indicates that something went wrong.
所以我打印出来的原因是，在“找到”一词之后，我返回0，
So the reason I'm printing out, after the word "Found" I'm returning 0,
这样程序才能在该点有效退出。
is so that effectively the program exits at that point.
我已经不想再走一遍了
I don't want to keep going again and again if I already
找到了我关心的电话号码。
found the number I care about.
在这里，这绝对不是必需的，
And down here, this one admittedly isn't strictly necessary,
因为如果我点击第16行并且可能删除了第17行，
because if I hit line 16 and maybe deleted line 17,
该程序将要结束。
the program's going to end anyway.
但是不会有所谓的退出状态
But there wouldn't be that so-called exit status
我们在上周简要讨论过，
that we discussed last week briefly, whereby
您可以向计算机发出某种信号
you can kind of signal to the computer whether something
是成功还是失败。
was successful or unsuccessful.
而0是好东西而1或其他任何数字都不是的原因，
And the reason that 0 is a good thing and 1 or any other number is not,
考虑在您编写的程序中有多少事情可能出错
consider how many things can go wrong in programs that you write
或现实世界中的公司写
or that companies in the real world write
当您收到这些错误消息时，有时
when you get those error messages, sometimes
与那些神秘的错误代码。
with those cryptic error codes.
有成千上万的问题
There are hundreds, thousands of problems
在计算机程序中可能会发生那么多错误
that might happen in a computer program that could be that many error
您在屏幕上看到的代码，原因
codes that you see on the screen, reasons
解释为什么程序崩溃或冻结等。
explaining why the program crashed or froze or the like.
但是0有点特殊，因为它只是世界所拥有的一个价值
But 0 is sort of special in that it's just one value that the world has
决定的意思是“成功”。
decided means "success."
因此，从某种意义上说，只有一种方法可以使您的程序正确无误，
So there's only one way to get your program right, in a sense,
但是有数百万种可能出错的方法。
but there's so many millions of ways in which things can go wrong.
这就是为什么人类采用了该特定约定的原因。
And that's why humans have adopted that particular convention.
好的。
All right.
但是，现在让我们不仅考虑数字，还要让事情变得更有趣。
But let's consider now not just numbers, but let's make things more interesting.
除了门，假设我们实际上
Besides the doors, suppose that we actually
后面有人们的名字。
had people's names behind them.
好吧，这次我们继续编写程序
Well, let's go ahead and write a program this time
不仅搜索数字，而且搜索名称。
that not only searches for numbers, but instead searches for names.
因此，我将继续在此处创建一个名为names.c的其他文件。
So I'm going to go ahead and create a different file here called names.c.
我将以类似的方式开始。
And I'm going to start a little similarly.
我将在顶部包含cs50.h，在顶部将包含stdio。
I'm going to include cs50.h at the top, I'm going to include stdio at the top.
但是我这次也要包含string.h，
But I'm also this time going to include string.h,
这是我们上周简要介绍的，因此
which we introduced briefly last week, so
我们可以使用strlen来获取字符串的长度，
that we have access to strlen for getting the length of a string,
事实证明，还有其他一些功能。
and, it turns out, some other functions.
让我继续照常声明int main void。
Let me go ahead and declare int main void as usual.
然后在这里，我需要一些任意名称。
And then inside here, I need some arbitrary names.
因此，我们在这里拿出七个名字。
So let's come up with seven names here.
在这里，我也可以像以前一样声明一个数组。
And here, too, I can declare an array just as I did before.
但是它不必只存储整数。
But it doesn't have to store only ints.
它可以存储字符串。
It can store strings instead.
因此，我将数据类型从int更改为string，
So I've changed the data type from int to string,
并且我已经将变量名称从数字更改为名称。
and I've changed the variable name from numbers to names.
而且我仍然可以使用这种新的花括号符号，
And I can still use this new curly brace notation,
我可以给自己起个名字，例如比尔（Bill），也许是查理（Charlie），也许是弗雷德（Fred），
and I can give myself a name like Bill, and maybe Charlie, and maybe Fred,
也许是乔治，也许是金妮，也许是珀西，最后，
and maybe George, and maybe Ginny, and maybe Percy, and lastly,
也许像罗恩这样的名字。
maybe a name like Ron.
而且它几乎不适合我的屏幕。
And it just barely fits on my screen.
这样说，我现在有了这个名称数组。
So with that said, I now have this array of names.
除此之外，对于他们来说，也许还有一个显而易见的模式，
And beyond there being a perhaps obvious pattern to them,
对他们来说，还有第二种不太明显的，或者也许是显而易见的模式。
there's a second less obvious, or maybe obvious, pattern to them.
您将如何描述我刚刚想出的名字列表？
How would you describe the list of names I arbitrarily just came up with?
它们的有用特性是什么？
What's a useful characteristic of them?
您对这些名字有什么注意？
What do you notice about these names?
我认为这个问题至少有两个正确答案。
And there's at least two right answers to this question, I think.
您对这些名字有什么注意？
What do you notice about these names?
杰克？
Jack?
听众：它们是按字母顺序排列的。
AUDIENCE: They're in alphabetical order.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
因此，除了成为哈利·波特（Harry Potter）中的韦斯莱（Weasley）孩子的名字之外，
So beyond being the names of the Weasley children in Harry Potter,
它们也按字母顺序排列。
they're also in alphabetical order.
这是更重要的细节。
And that's the more salient detail.
为了我们的目的，我已经有了深谋远虑
For our purposes, I've had the forethought
这次要预先对这些名称进行排序。
this time to sort these names in advance.
如果我对这些名称进行了排序，则意味着
And if I've sorted these names, that means implicitly
我可以使用比线性搜索更好的算法。
I can use a better algorithm than linear search.
例如，我可以使用旧的二进制搜索。
I can use, for instance, our old binary search.
但是，让我们先进行一下，然后就立即对其进行天真搜索。
But let's go ahead first and just search them naively for now.
让我们继续应用线性搜索，因为您知道，
Let's still apply linear search, because, you know,
我们还没有做的是必须将字符串相互比较。
what we haven't yet done is necessarily compare strings against one another.
我们已经做了大量的数字比较，例如整数。
We've done a lot of comparisons of numbers like integers.
但是名字呢？
But what about names?
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以对于int来说，我得到0，就像以前一样，我小于7，我++-
So for int i gets 0, just like before, i less than 7, i++--
我之所以这样做，是因为我事先知道有七个名字。
and I'm doing this only because I know in advance there are seven names.
我认为我们可能可以改进此代码的设计，
I think we could probably improve the design of this code,
也可以通过具有存储该值的变量或常量来实现。
too, by having a variable or a constant storing that value.
但是我将保持简单，现在仅关注新细节。
But I'm going to keep it simple and focus only on the new details for now.
事实证明，由于某些原因，我们将在下周进行更详细的探讨，
And it turns out, for reasons we'll explore in more detail next week,
仅仅做我们以前做的事情并做这样的事情是不够的
it is not sufficient to do what we did before and do something like this
如果我要搜索“罗恩”。
if I'm searching for "Ron."
事实证明，在C语言中，不能使用equals equals来比较两个字符串。
It turns out that in C, you can't use equals equals to compare two strings.
您可以为整数，也可以为字符。
You can for an int, you can for a char.
过去，我们都做到了。
And we've done both of those in the past.
但是有一个微妙之处，我们下周将详细介绍，
But there's a subtlety that we'll dive into in more detail next week that
表示您实际上无法执行此操作。
means you can't actually do this.
这很好奇，因为如果您事先进行过编程
And this is curious, because if you have prior programming
具备Python之类的语言经验，您可以执行此操作。
experience in languages like Python or the like, you can do this.
因此，在C语言中您不能这样做，但是下次我们将看到原因。
So in C you can't, but we'll see next time why.
但是现在，事实证明C可以解决这个问题，
But for now, it turns out that C can solve this problem,
从历史上看，您执行此操作的方法是使用函数。
and historically the way you do this is with a function.
因此，在string.h头文件中，
So inside of the string.h header file, there
不仅是strlen的声明，还像上周一样是字符串的长度。
is not only a declaration for strlen, the length of a string like last week.
还有另一个名为strcmp的函数。
There's another function called strcmp.
简称为STRCMP的“搅拌比较”，
And "stir compare," for short, S-T-R-C-M-P,
允许我传递两个字符串，一个要与之比较的字符串
allows me to pass in two strings, one string that I want to compare against
另一个字符串。
another string.
因此语法并不完全相同。
So it's not quite the same syntax.
确实，这有点难读。
Indeed, it's a little harder to read.
它不像平等一样简单。
It's not quite as simple as equals equals.
但是strcmp，如果我们阅读了它的文档，
But strcmp, if we read the documentation for it,
会告诉我们这比较两个字符串。
will tell us that this compares two strings.
并且它返回三个可能值之一。
And it returns one of three possible values.
如果这两个字符串相等，即字母对字母相同，
If those two strings are equal, that is, identically the same letter for letter,
然后该函数将返回0，结果是。
then this function is going to return 0, it turns out.
如果第一个字符串应该在第二个字符串之前
If the first string is supposed to come before the second string
从某种意义上讲，按字母顺序排列
alphabetically, in some sense, then this function
将返回负值。
is going to return a negative value.
如果第一个字符串应该按字母顺序排在第二个字符串之后，
If the first string is supposed to come after the second string alphabetically,
如果可以的话，它将返回一个正值。
if you will, then it's going to return a positive value.
因此，存在三种可能的结果-等于0或小于0，
So there's three possible outcomes-- either equal to 0, or less than 0,
或大于0。
or greater than 0.
但是您会注意到，实际上，如果您看了一段时间的文档，
But you'll notice, and in fact, if you look at the documentation some time,
它不会指定小于0的值或大于0的值。
it doesn't specify what value less than 0 or what value greater than 0.
您只需要检查任何负值或正值即可。
You have to just check for any negative value or any positive value.
我刚才也讲了一个白色的谎言。
And I also told a bit of a white lie a moment ago.
这不会按字母顺序检查内容，
This does not check things alphabetically,
即使有时碰巧也是如此。
even though it coincidentally does sometimes.
实际上是按所谓的ASCII顺序比较字符串，
Actually compares strings in what's called ASCII order,
或ASCIIbetically，这是一种愚蠢的描述方式
or ASCIIbetically which is kind of a goofy way of describing
此函数从左到右查看两个字符串中的每个字符，
this function looks at every character in the two strings, from left to right,
它检查它们的ASCII值，然后比较那些ASCII值
it checks the ASCII values of them, and then it compares those ASCII values
逐个字符。
character by character.
如果ASCII值小于另一个，
And if the ASCII value is less than the other,
然后返回负值，反之亦然。
then it returns a negative value or vice versa.
因此，例如，如果字符串中包含字母A，大写A，
So if you have, for instance, the letter A, capital A in the string,
首先转换为65。
that gets converted first to 65.
然后，如果另一个字符串中的A大写，
And then if you have an A in the other string capitalized,
它也被比较为65，这将是相等的。
it, too, gets compared to 65, and those would be equal.
但是，当然，所有这些名称都有一个以上的字符，
But of course, all of these names have more than one character,
因此，此ASCII顺序（即ASCIIbetical）在从左到右的前面
so this ASCII order, or ASCIIbetical, precedes left to right
这样strcmp会为您检查名称中的每个字符。
so that strcmp checks every character in the names for you.
当它碰到终止的空字符时，它将停止。
And it stops when it hits that terminating null character.
回想一下引擎盖下面的琴弦，
Recall that strings, underneath the hood,
总是以这个反斜杠0或8个0位以C结尾。
always end in C with this backslash 0, or eight 0 bits.
这就是strcmp知道何时停止比较值的方式。
So that's how strcmp knows when to stop comparing values.
但是如果我继续寻找像罗恩这样的人，那就让我继续吧
But if I go ahead and find someone like Ron, let me go ahead
并打印出引号，取消引号“ Found”。
and print out quote, unquote, "Found."
和以前一样，我会继续前进，就像黛咪建议的那样，
And like before, I'll go ahead and return, like Demi proposed,
0，仅表示一切成功。
0, just to imply that all is successful.
否则，如果我们一直深入到代码的底部，
Otherwise, if we get all the way to the bottom of my code,
我将打印出“未找到”的故事，以告诉我们我们没有
I'm going to print out "Not found" to tell the story that we did not
即使罗恩碰巧在那儿，也能找到罗恩
find Ron in this array, even though he does happen to be there,
我将继续并返回1。
and I'm going to go ahead and return 1.
因此，即使我已经对所有内容进行了硬编码-
So even though I've hardcoded everything--
在程序中对某些内容进行硬编码意味着要明确输入-
to hardcode something in a program means to type it out explicitly--
您可以想象使用上周这样的命令行参数
you could imagine using a command line argument like last week
获取用户的输入。
to get user's input.
您想搜寻谁？
Who would you like to search for?
您可以想象使用get_string来获取用户的输入并询问他们，
You could imagine using get_string to get user's input and ask them,
您想搜寻谁？
who would you like to search for?
但是现在，仅出于演示目的，我仅使用了罗恩的名字。
But for now, just for demonstration sake, I've used only Ron's name.
如果我没有打错字，
And if I haven't made any typos--
让我继续输入make name，Enter，到目前为止，。/ names很好。
let me go ahead and type in make names, Enter, so far so good, ./names.
希望我们会看到的确是“发现”
And hopefully, we'll see, indeed, "Found,"
因为“罗恩”在七个兄弟姐妹的数组中非常多。
because "Ron" is very much in this array of seven siblings.
但是这里的新组成部分
But the building blocks that are new here
再次是当我们声明某个固定大小的数组时
are, again, the fact that when we declare an array of some fixed size
我们严格不需要在这里输入数字，
we don't strictly need to put a number here,
当我们有大括号表示法时
and we have this curly brace notation when we
事先了解数组的内容。
know the array's contents in advance.
但也许最后也是最有力的是，我们
But perhaps lastly and most powerfully, we
在C中确实有一个称为strcmp的函数，它将允许我们实际
do have this function in C called strcmp that will allow us to actually
以这种方式存储和比较字符串。
store and compare strings in this way.
所以让我在这里暂停一下，只是问是否有
So let me pause here and just ask if there's
关于我们如何将这些想法转换为数字编码的任何疑问，
any questions about how we translated these ideas to code for numbers,
以及我们现在如何将这些想法转换为代码
and how we translated these ideas to code for now
名称，每次使用线性搜索，而不是二进制。
names, each time using linear search, not, binary.
迦勒，有问题吗？
Caleb, question?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
因此，如果“ Ron”就像所有大写字母一样，该程序仍然可以正常工作，
So would that program still work if "Ron," for example, was like all caps,
例如，如果您要搜索-
like if you're trying to search--
例如，如果大小写不同，情况是否相同？
like, if the cases are different in terms of uppercase and lowercase?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
让我提出一个对总体而言很有用的本能-
And let me propose an instinct that's useful to acquire in general--
如有疑问，请尝试。
when in doubt, try it.
因此，我将确切地做到这一点。
So I'm going to do exactly that.
我碰巧知道答案，但假设我没有。
I do happen to know the answer, but suppose I didn't.
让我继续，将“ Ron”更改为全部大写，仅仅是因为。
Let me go ahead and change "Ron" to all caps, just because.
可能是人类按下了Caps Lock键，
Maybe the human, the Caps Lock key was on,
然后他们有点草率地打字。
and they typed it in a little sloppily.
让我继续进行，不要进行其他更改。
Let me go ahead and make no other changes.
请注意，我将仅使用大写字母R保留原始数组。
Notice that I'm leaving the original array alone with only a capital R.
让我重新制作该程序，命名为./names。
Let me remake this program, make name, ./names.
瞧，他仍然被发现了。
And voila, he's still, in fact, found.
支持。
Stand by.
哦好的。
Oh, OK.
Caleb，您刚刚帮助我发掘了一个错误
Caleb, you have just helped me unearth, a bug that
在前面的示例中是潜在的。
was latent in the previous example.
你们都不应该接受这个事实
None of you should have accepted the fact
以前的程序与“ RON”一起使用，因为我没有
that the previous program worked with "RON," because I didn't
从字面上练习我的讲道。
practice literally what I'm preaching.
卡莱布，请稍等片刻，以便我可以倒带一点
So Caleb, hold that thought for just a moment so I can rewind a little bit
并修复我的明显错误。
and fix my apparent bug.
因此确实发现了“ RON”。
So "RON" was indeed found.
但是没有找到他，因为找到了“ RON”。
But he wasn't found because "RON" was found.
我在这里做了一些愚蠢的事情。
I did something stupid here.
而且也许在教学上更合适
And it's perhaps all the more pedagogically appropriate
现在强调一下。
now to highlight that.
因此，该程序如何说“ Ron”被找到，即使这次也
So how did this program say "Ron" was found, even though this time it also
说在所有大写字母中都找到了“ RON”？
says "RON" was found in all caps?
你知道吗，让我在这里有点好奇。
And you know what, let me get a little curious here.
让我继续搜索，甚至不要搜索“罗恩”。
Let me go ahead and search for, not even "Ron."
我们如何搜索罗恩的妈妈“莫莉”？
How about we search for Ron's mom, "Molly"?
做名字。
Make names.
好的。
All right.
现在，为了说明我确实做了一些愚蠢的事情，。/ names。
And now, just to reveal that I really did do something stupid, ./names.
好吧，现在明显有问题吧？
OK, now something's clearly wrong, right?
我什至可以搜索父亲“亚瑟”（Arthur），命名为./name。
I can even search for the father "Arthur", make names, ./name.
看来我写了一个程序，该程序实际上总是说“找到”。
It seems that I wrote you a program that just literally always says "Found."
因此，我们不应该接受这种说法是正确的。
So we shouldn't have accepted this as correct.
到目前为止，谁能根据我的定义发现该错误？
Can anyone spot the bug based on my definition thus far?
任何人都可以发现该错误吗？
Can anyone spot the bug?
同时，这不是放鸭的好时机
In the meantime, this isn't really a bad time to open up the duck
并说：“你好，鸭子。
and say, "Hello, duck.
我遇到一个问题，我的程序始终在打印找到
I am having a problem whereby my program is always printing Found
即使有人不在阵列中。
even when someone is not in the array.
我可以继续向鸭子解释我的逻辑，
And I could proceed to explain my logic to the duck,
但希望索菲亚能比鸭子更快地指出解决方案。
but hopefully Sophia can point me at the solution even faster than the duck.
观众：您需要比较我们的价值
AUDIENCE: You need to compare the value that we
从strcmp收到的东西。
received from strcmp with something.
因此，我们需要将其与0进行比较，并确保
So we need to compare it with like 0 and make sure
我们得到了他们相等的价值。
that we receive the value that they're equal.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
所以我说了正确的事，但我确实没有做正确的事。
So I said the right thing, but I literally did not do the right thing.
如果我想检查是否相等，我会按字面意思
If I want to check for equality, I literally
比较名称括号i时需要检查返回值
need to check the return value when comparing names bracket i
反对“罗恩”等于0。
against "Ron" to equal 0.
因为仅在strcmp的返回值为0的情况下
Because only in the case when the return value of strcmp is 0
我真的有比赛吗？
do I actually have a match.
相反，如果函数返回负值或函数
By contrast, if the function returns a negative value or the function
返回一个正值，这意味着它不是一个匹配项。
returns a positive value, that means it's not a match.
这意味着一个名字应该先于另一个名字
That means that one name is supposed to come before the other
或之后。
or after the other.
但是，这里的速记语法并不总是适用
But the catch with my shorthand syntax here, which is not always
每当内部有布尔表达式时，都会使用不正确的语法
an incorrect syntax to use, whenever you have a Boolean expression inside
其中是这样的函数调用-
of which is a function call like this--
注意我整个布尔表达式
notice that the entirety of my Boolean expression
可以这么说，这只是给strcmp的电话。
is just a call, so to speak, to strcmp.
我传入了两个输入，名称括弧i和引号，取消引号“ Ron”。
I'm passing in two inputs, names bracket i and quote, unquote "Ron."
因此，我期望strcmp返回输出，即所谓的return
And therefore, I'm expecting strcmp to return output, a so-called return
价值。
value.
该返回值将是负数或正数或0。
That return value is going to be negative or positive or 0.
实际上，要明确的是，是否要搜索名字
And in fact, to be clear, if the first name being searched
对于“ Bill”和名称括号i或名称括号0
for is "Bill" and names bracket i or names bracket 0
是“比尔”，“比尔”逗号，“罗恩”实际上是什么
is "Bill," "Bill" comma "Ron" is effectively what
我的输入是在第一次迭代中。
my input is on the first iteration.
“帐单”，按字母顺序和ASCII，按字母顺序，
"Bill," alphabetically and ASCIIbetically,
在“罗恩”之前，这意味着它应该
comes before "Ron," which means it should
向我返回负值。
be returning a negative value to me.
在这种情况下，布尔表达式的问题在于
And the problem with Boolean expressions is, as implemented in this context,
是只有0为假。
is that only 0 is false.
根据定义，任何其他返回值都为true或“是”，
Any other return value is by definition true or a Yes answer,
无论是负数1还是正数1，负数100万
whether it's negative 1 or positive 1, negative 1 million
或正数100万-
or positive 1 million--
计算机语言（例如C）中的任何非零值
any non-zero value in a computer language like C
被认为是真实的，也被称为真实。
is considered true, also known as truthy.
任何值为0的值都被视为false，但仅
Any value that is 0 is considered false, but only
该值被认为是错误的。
that value is considered false.
真的，起初我很幸运，因为我的程序正在查找“帐单”，
So really, I was getting lucky at first, because my program was finding "Bill,"
但是我把“比尔”换成了“罗恩”。
but I was confusing "Bill" for "Ron."
然后，当我再次为Caleb做这件事时，我大写了“ Ron”，
Then when I did it again for Caleb and I capitalized "Ron,"
我变得不走运，因为突然之间我
I was getting unlucky, because suddenly I
知道大写的“ RON”不在数组中，
knew "RON" capitalized wasn't in the array,
但是我仍然说他被发现了。
and yet I'm still saying he's found.
但这是因为我没有按照索菲亚的发现去实践我所讲的道。
But that's because I didn't practice what I preach per Sophia's find.
因此，如果我将其实际与0进行比较-现在，Caleb，
And so if I actually compare this against 0-- and now, Caleb,
我们全盘回答您的问题-
we come full circle to your question--
我用make名称重建该程序，现在执行./names并搜索所有内容
I rebuild this program with make names, I now do ./names and search for all
大写“ RON”，幸运的是，现在我应该看到“未找到”。
caps "RON," I should now see, thankfully, "Not found."
所以我希望我可以说是故意的，但是因此
So I wish I could say that was deliberate, but thus
是bug的常见情况。
is the common case of bugs.
因此，在20年后的今天，我在代码中产生了错误。
So here I am 20 years later making bugs in my code.
因此，如果您本周遇到类似的问题，
So if you run up to a similar problem this week,
放心，它永远不会结束。
rest assured that it never ends.
但是希望你不会有几个人看着你
But hopefully you won't have several people watching you
在您本周解决问题时。
while you do your problem set this week.
好的。
All right.
那么，除了Caleb的问题之外，还有其他问题吗？
Any questions, then, beyond Caleb's?
卡勒布（Caleb）真是个好问题，答案是否定的。
So great question, Caleb, and the answer is no.
区分大小写。
It is case sensitive.
因此它找不到“ Rob”
So it does not find "Rob"--
“ RON。”
"RON."
有什么问题吗？
Any questions here?
对使用字符串进行线性搜索有任何疑问吗？
Any questions on linear search using strings?
不？
No?
好吧，让我们继续做一个最后的例子，我想，
All right, well, let's go ahead and do one final example, I think,
搜索。
with searching.
但是，让我们仅介绍另一个功能。
But let's introduce just one other feature.
而且这个实际上很酷而且功能强大。
And this one's actually pretty cool and powerful.
到目前为止，我们一直在使用C附带的数据类型
Up until now, we've been using data types that just come with C
或来自CS50，例如int，char，float等。
or come from CS50, like int, and char, and float, and the like.
现在您会看到实际上有时
And you'll see now that there's actually sometimes
您或我可能想要创建自己的自定义数据类型的原因，
reasons where you or I might want to create our own custom data types,
我们自己的类型，这些类型在发明C本身时就不存在。
our own types that didn't exist when C itself was invented.
例如，假设我想代表的不仅仅是
So for instance, suppose that I wanted to represent not just
一堆数字，而不仅仅是一堆名字，
a whole bunch of numbers and not just a whole bunch of names,
但是假设我想像完整的电话簿一样实施。
but suppose I want to implement like a full-fledged phone book.
电话簿当然包含名称和号码。
A phone book, of course, contains both names and numbers.
并假设我想将这两个想法结合在一起。
And suppose I want to combine these two ideas together.
如果我可以有一个数据结构，那会不会很好
Wouldn't it be nice if I could have a data structure that
是具有某种结构的数据类型，它实际上可以
is a data type that has some structure to it that can actually
一次存储两个？
store both at once?
实际上，如果C拥有一个名为person的数据类型，那会不会很好，
And in fact, wouldn't it be nice if C had a data type called person,
因此，如果我想代表一个人，例如电话簿中的人，
so that if I want to represent a person, like in a phone book, who
既有名字又有数字，我可以
had both a name and a number, I can actually
通过调用人员类型的变量来实现该代码？
implement that and code by calling that variable of type person?
现在，当然，C的设计师没有远见
Now, of course, the designers of C did not have the foresight
创建一个称为人员的数据类型。
to create a data type called person.
实际上，那将是一个湿滑的斜坡
And, indeed, that would be a slippery slope
如果您可以想到每个现实世界实体的数据类型。
if they had a data type for every real-world entity you can think of.
但是它们确实为我们提供了执行此操作的能力。
But they did give us the capabilities to do this.
因此，如果一个人在我们这里有限的电话簿中，
So if a person, in our limited world here of phone books,
既有名称又有数字，我们可能会这样认为：
has both a name and a number, we might think of it as follows--
名称和数字，均为string类型。
a name and a number, both of type string.
但是在这里快速检查。
But a quick check here.
为什么现在我有些自以为是地决定，
Why have I now decided, somewhat presumptuously,
也可以拨打电话号码字符串？
to call phone numbers strings as well?
我们一直在谈论这些门后面的整数。
We've been talking about ints behind these doors.
我们一直在寻找代码中的整数。
We've been searching for ints in code.
但是为什么我只想建议我们
But why did I just presume to propose that we instead
使用字符串作为名称和数字来实现电话簿？
implement a phone book using strings for names and numbers?
在这里有什么想法吗，库尔特？
Any thoughts here, Kurt?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
因为我们没有对此进行数学运算。
Because we're not doing math on it.
就像-电话号码可能就像我们关心的所有字母一样。
It's like-- a phone number could be, like, letters for all we care.
实际上，我的意思是，有时您会看到，
And in fact, I mean, sometimes you see, like,
1-800联系人或类似的内容，也许我们想允许它。
1-800 Contacts or something like that, and maybe we want to allow that.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，绝对如此。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, absolutely.
电话号码尽管有名字，但不一定只是一个数字。
A phone number, despite its name, isn't necessarily just a number.
可能是1-800个Contacts，这是一个英文单词。
It might be 1-800 Contacts, which is an English word.
它可能带有连字符或破折号。
It might have hyphens in it or dashes.
它可能带有括号。
It might have parentheses in it.
国家代码可能带有加号。
It might have a plus sign for country codes.
我们绝对有很多角色
There's a lot of characters that we absolutely
可以使用我们无法使用int在C中表示的字符串在C中表示。
can represent in C using strings that we couldn't represent in C using int.
的确如此，即使在现实世界中
And so indeed, even though in the real world
您和我会不时谈论这些“数字”，例如电话
there are these "numbers" that you and I talk about once in a while like phone
号码，例如美国社会保险号，信用卡号，
numbers, maybe in the US Social Security numbers, credit card numbers,
这些不一定是您要视为实际整数的值。
those aren't necessarily values that you want to treat as actual integers.
实际上，你们中那些发生信用问题的人
And in fact, those of you who did the credit problem
并尝试验证信用卡号
and tried to validate credit card numbers
可能会很长一段时间用信用来表示挑战
may very well have run into challenges by using a long to represent a credit
卡号。
card number.
回想起来也许很好
It probably in retrospect might very well
您可以更轻松地将信用卡号视为字符串。
have been easier for you to treat credit card numbers as strings.
当然，要抓住的地方是您还没有
The catch, of course, by design is that you didn't yet
至少在C语言中，您的词汇表中包含字符串。
have strings in your vocabulary, at least in C yet.
所以假设我要创建自己的自定义数据
So suppose I want to create my own custom data
如果可以的话，它封装两种不同类型的值。
type that encapsulates, if you will, two different types of values.
此后，一个人将是一个名字和一个数字。
A person shall be henceforth a name and a number.
事实证明，C在这里为我们提供了这种语法。
It turns out that C gives us this syntax here.
这是除了那些花括号之外唯一的多汁的新语法
This is the only juicy piece of new syntax besides those curly braces
不久之前，我们今天将在C中看到typedef。
a moment ago that we'll see today in C, typedef.
顾名思义，
And as the name rather succinctly suggests,
这使您可以定义类型。
this allows you to define a type.
类型将是某种结构。
And the type will be a structure of some sort.
因此，一种编程语言中的数据结构
So a data structure in a programming language
通常是具有某种结构的数据类型。
is typically a data type that has some structure to it.
我们所说的“结构”是什么意思？
What do we mean by "structure"?
它通常在其中具有一个或多个值。
It typically has one or more values inside of it.
因此，使用typedef，然后使用struct关键字，
So using typedef, and in turn using the struct keyword,
我们可以创建自己的自定义类型
we can create our own custom types that's
一个结构，由多个其他数据类型组成。
a structure, a composition of multiple other data types.
因此，如果我们想让人们在一起作为他们自己的自定义数据类型，
So if we want to keep persons together as their own custom data type,
语法在这里有点晦涩难懂。
the syntax is a little cryptic here.
您实际上是用typedef struct打开花括号的，
You literally do typedef struct open curly brace,
然后每行指定一个您想要的数据类型
then one per line you specify the data types that you want
以及您要为这些数据类型指定的名称，
and the names that you want to give to those data types,
例如名称和编号。
for instance name and number.
然后在右花括号外面，
And then outside of the closing curly brace,
如果您确实是数据类型，则应直接输入“人”一词
you literally put the word "person," if that's indeed the data type
您想发明的。
that you want to invent.
那么我们如何才能更有效地使用它呢？
So how can we use this more powerfully?
好吧，让我们继续前进，以错误的方式做事，而不先使用此功能，
Well, let's go ahead and do things the wrong way without this feature first,
从而激发它的存在。
so as to motivate its existence.
让我继续将此文件另存为phonebook.c。
Let me go ahead and save this file as phonebook.c.
让我像往常一样从包含cs50.h开始。
And let me start, as always, with includes cs50.h.
然后让我继续并包含stdio.h。
And then let me go ahead and include stdio.h.
最后，让我也包含string.h，
And then lastly, let me also include string.h,
因为我知道我稍后会处理一些字符串。
because I know I'm going to be manipulating some strings in a moment.
现在让我继续前进，在我的主要职责范围内，让我继续前进
Let me go ahead now, and within my main function, let me go ahead
首先给我自己，作为该程序的第一个版本，
and give myself initially, for the first version of this program,
一堆名字。
a whole bunch of names.
具体来说，“布莱恩”逗号“大卫”怎么样？
Specifically, how about "Brian" comma "David"?
我们将其简短，以便仅关注思想而非实际数据
We'll keep it short, just so as to focus on the ideas and not the actual data
他们进来了。
they're in.
然后我和Brian都有电话号码。
Then Brian and I each have phone numbers.
因此，让我们继续将它们存储在一个数组中-
So let's go ahead and store them in an array--
数字等于，再次像以前一样使用花括号，以及+ 1-617-495-1000--
numbers equals, again the curly braces as before, and +1-617-495-1000--
实际上，按照库尔特（Kurt）的评论，已经有动机使用字符串，
and indeed, there's already motivation, per Kurt's comment, to use strings,
因为那里有一个加号和几个破折号-
because we've got a plus and a couple of dashes in there--
然后是我的电话号码
and then my number here.
因此，我们将做+ 1-949-468-2750右花括号，分号。
So we'll do +1-949-468-2750 close curly brace, semicolon.
因此，我继续声明了两个数组，其中一个称为名称，
So I've gone ahead and declared two arrays, one called names,
一个叫数字。
one called numbers.
我将要达成某种握手协议
And I'm just going to have sort of a handshake agreement
名称中的名字对应于数字中的名字，
that the first name in names corresponds to the first number in numbers,
名称中的第二个名称对应于数字中的第二个数字。
the second name in names corresponds to the second number in numbers.
您可以想象只要您不犯任何错误，就能很好地工作，
And you can imagine that working well so long as you don't make any mistakes,
而且每个数字都有正确的数字
and you have just the right number in each.
现在让我继续并做int我等于0，我小于2--
Now let me go ahead and do int i equals 0, i less than 2--
我现在将仅对硬编码进行演示。
I'm going to keep that hardcoded for now just to do the demonstration.
然后在这个循环中，让我继续搜索我的电话号码，
And then inside of this loop, let me go ahead and search for my phone number,
例如，即使我碰巧在最后。
for instance, even though I happen to be at the end.
所以如果名字括号的strcmp我等于-
So if strcmp of names bracket i equals--
逗号“ David”等于0
rather, comma "David" equals equals 0--
所以我不会再犯这个错误了。
so I'm not going to make that mistake again.
让我在此循环内，在此条件内继续进行。
Let me go ahead inside of this loop, inside of this condition here.
我将继续进行以下操作-打印出我发现的内容，
And I'm going to go ahead and do the following-- print out that I found,
例如我的电话号码。
for instance my number.
我要插入它。
And I'm going to plug that in.
所以数字括起来。
So numbers bracket i.
然后像以前一样，我将继续并返回0。
And then as before, I'm going to go ahead and return 0.
如果所有这些都没有解决，而我碰巧不在这个数组中，
And if none of this works out, and I happen not to be in this array,
我将继续打印，并像以前一样用分号打印“未找到”。
I'll go ahead and print out as before "Not found" with a semicolon.
然后我将任意返回1。
And then I'll return 1 arbitrarily.
我可以返回负1，我可以返回一百万，负一百万。
I can return negative 1, I could return a million, negative million.
但是人类的惯例通常会让您从0变到1到2变到3
But human convention would typically have you go from 0 to 1 to 2 to 3
继续，如果您有那么多可能的错误情况。
on up, if you have that many possible error conditions.
好的。
All right.
因此，我基本上在C中实现了各种电话簿。
So I essentially have implemented in C a phone book of sorts.
我们在第0周以口头方式进行了此操作。
We did this verbally in week 0.
现在，我正在用代码来做。
Now I'm doing it in code.
这是一本有限的电话簿。
It's a limited phone book.
它只有两个名字和两个数字。
It's only got two names and two numbers.
但我当然可以实施这本电话簿
But I could certainly implement this phone book
通过使用两个数组，两个并行数组，如果您愿意的话，
by just using two arrays, two parallel arrays, if you will,
通过仅使用第一个元素和名称行的荣誉系统
by just using the honor system that the first element and names lines
与第一个元素和数字，依此类推。
up with the first elements and numbers and so forth.
现在希望，如果我不做任何错别字，
Now hopefully, if I don't make any typos,
让我继续制作电话簿。
let me go ahead and make phonebook.
好的。
All right.
它编译OK。 ./phonebook，然后发现那里似乎是我的电话号码。
It compiled OK. ./phonebook, and it found what seems to be my number there.
因此，它似乎正常工作，尽管我已尝试将其拉到您的身上
So it seems to work correctly, though I've tried to pull that one over you
前。
before.
但是我敢肯定，这实际上是可以正常工作的。
But I'm pretty sure this one actually works correctly.
因此，我们找到了我的名字和依次的号码。
And so we found my name and in turn number.
但是，为什么此代码的设计不一定是最好的？
But why is the design of this code not necessarily the best?
诚然，这开始变得越来越微妙。
This is starting to get more subtle, admittedly.
而且我们已经看到我们可以以不同的方式进行操作。
And we've seen that we can do this differently.
但是，什么使您对这里的错误方式感到困惑呢？
But what rubs you the wrong way about here?
这是我们称为“代码气味”的另一个示例。
This is another example of what we might call "code smell."
就像，这里有点时髦，像，啊，这个
Like, something's a little funky here, like, ah, this
长期来看，尼克可能不是最好的解决方案，您怎么看？
might not be the best solution long term Nick, what do you think?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
所以我猜是
So what I'm guessing is that--
例如，您知道在新数据结构之前如何制作数据框，
like, you know how you made the data frame before the new data structure,
这两件事在哪里联系在一起？
where the two things were linked together?
在这种情况下，我们只是依靠事实
In this case, we're just banking on the fact
我们不会搞砸并且无意间取消链接
that we don't screw something up and unintentionally unlink them
来自相同的索引。
from the same index.
因此，它们之间没有内在的联系，这可能不是-
So they're not intrinsically linked, which might not be--
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：这是正确的本能。
DAVID MALAN: That's exactly the right instinct.
总的来说，就像您渴望成为一名程序员一样伟大，
In general, as great as a programmer as you're maybe aspiring to be,
你还不是全部。
you're not all that.
就像，您将要犯错误。
And like, you're going to make mistakes.
而且，您可以编写更多的自卫代码，
And the more you can write code that's self-defensive,
保护您免受自己伤害，您将获得更好的生活，
that protects you from yourself, the better off you're going to be,
您的代码越正确，
the more correct your code is going to be,
而且您将更容易成功地进行协作，
and the more easily you're going to be able to collaborate successfully,
如果您在现实世界中选择，在现实世界中的编程项目中，
if you so choose in the real world, on real-world programming projects,
是否用于研究项目，全职工作，个人项目
whether for a research project, a full-time job, a personal project
或类似的东西。
or the like.
一般来说，您不应该信任自己或其他人
Generally speaking, you should not trust yourself or other people
与您一起编写代码的人
that-- with whom you're writing code, you
应该沿着这些路线建立尽可能多的防御机制。
should have as many defense mechanisms in place exactly along these lines.
所以是的，我所做的一切都没有错
So yes, there's nothing wrong with what I have done in the sense
这是正确的。
that this is correct.
但是如前所述，如果您搞砸了，也许您因一个错误而失败了-
But as noted, if you screw up, and maybe you get an off by one error--
也许您调换了两个名字或两个数字。
maybe you transpose two names or two numbers.
我的意思是，假设您有很多名字和数字，
I mean, imagine if you've got dozens of names and numbers,
数百个名称和数字，其中数千个
hundreds of names and numbers, thousands of them
您或某人将订单弄乱的几率
the odds that you or someone messes the order up at some point
可能太高了。
is just probably going to be too, too high.
因此，如果我们可以将相关数据保持在一起，那就太好了。
So it would be nice, then, if we could sort of keep related data together.
只是在荣誉系统上说，我的阵列排列整齐，
This is kind of a hack, to just on the honor system say, my arrays line up,
我只是要确保它们的长度相同。
I'm just going to make sure to keep them the same length.
我们可以做得更好。
We can do better.
让我们将相关数据保持在一起，并对其进行更简洁的设计。
Let's keep related data together and design this a little more cleanly.
我可以通过定义自己的类型来做到这一点
And I can do this by defining my own type
例如，我将称呼一个人。
that I'll call for instance, a person.
因此，在此文件的开头，在main之前，我是
So at the top of this file, before main, I'm
继续在内部定义一个结构
going to go ahead and typedef a structure, inside
我关心的是两种类型的数据，
of which are the two types of data that I care about,
字符串名称和字符串编号，与以前一样。
string name and string number, just as before.
但是请注意，这里我所做的并不是给自己一个数组。
Notice, though, here that what I have done here is not give myself an array.
我给自己起了一个名字和一个号码。
I've given myself one name and one number.
在花括号之外，我将提供此数据类型
Outside of this curly brace, I'm going to give this data type
一个名字，我可以称之为“人”。
a name, which I could call "person."
我可以叫它任何我想要的东西，但是人
I could call it anything I want, but person
在这种情况下似乎很合理。
seems pretty reasonable in this case.
现在，在这里，我将继续进行一些更改。
And now down here, I'm going to go ahead and change this code a little bit.
我要继续给自己一个数组，
I'm going to go ahead and give myself an array still,
但是这次我要给自己一些人。
but this time I'm going to give myself an array of persons.
我将以某种调皮的方式将其称为“人”，
And I'm going to call that array, somewhat playfully, "people,"
因为我想在这个程序中有两个人，两个人，我和布莱恩。
because I want to have two persons, two people, in this program, me and Brian.
现在，我要继续并填充此数组。
Now I want to go ahead and populate this array.
也就是说，我想用值填充它。
That is, I want to fill it with values.
这个语法有点新，但这只是
And this syntax is a little new, but it's just
使我们能够将值实际存储在结构内部。
to enable us to actually store values inside of a structure.
如果我想索引到这个数组，有
If I want to index into this array, there's
与上周没什么不同。
nothing different from last week.
我将人括号设为0。
I do people bracket 0.
这会给我里面的第一人称变量，所以大概在哪里
That's going to give me the first person variable inside, so probably where
“布莱恩”应该走了。
"Brian" is supposed to go.
我需要的最后一句语法是如何
The one last piece of syntax I need is how do I
进入那个结构，那个人数据结构，
go inside of that structure, that person data structure,
并访问此人的名字？
and access the person's name?
我实际上只是做一个点。
I literally just do a dot.
因此，人员括号0使我成为人员数组中的第一个人。
So people bracket 0 gives me the first person in the people array.
然后，点表示进入其中并获取person变量。
And then the dot means, go inside of it and grab the person variable.
我将继续将该名称设置为引号，取消引号“ Brian”。
I'm going to go ahead and set that name equal to quote, unquote "Brian."
现在，他的名字的语法几乎是相同的-
The syntax now for his name is almost identical--
人括号0点号等于引号，取消引号“ + 1-617-495-1000”
people bracket 0 dot number equals quote, unquote "+1-617-495-1000"
分号。
semicolon.
同时，如果我想自己访问一个位置，
Meanwhile, if I want to access a location for myself,
我要继续将它放在位置1
I'm going to go ahead and put it at location 1, which
是第二个位置。
is the second location.
名称将用引号引起来，而不用引号“ David”。
Name will be, quote, unquote "David."
然后在这里，我将把方括号1点号等于
And then over here, I'm going to do people bracket 1 dot number equals
引号，取消引号“ + 1-949-468-2750”，引号，分号。
quote, unquote "+1-949-468-2750" close quote, semicolon.
诚然，这有点冗长。
So it's a bit verbose, admittedly.
但是您可以想象，如果我们让我们的思想超越自我
But you could imagine, if we just let our thoughts run ahead of ourselves
在这里，如果您使用了get_string，可以自动执行此操作。
here, if you used get_string, could sort of automatically do this.
如果您使用了命令行参数，也许您可以填充其中的一些。
If you used command line arguments, maybe you could populate some of this.
我们不仅需要硬编码，也就是写下我的姓名和电话号码
We don't just have to hardcode, that is, write my name and number
布赖恩（Brian）进入了这个计划。
and Brian's into this program.
您可以想象更动态地执行此操作
You can imagine doing this more dynamically
从第一周开始，使用我们的一些技术，使用get_string等。
using some of our techniques, using get_string and so forth, from week 1.
但是现在，这只是为了演示。
But for now, it's just for demonstration's sake.
所以现在如果我要搜索这个新的数组，这个新的单个数组的人，
So now if I want to search this new array, this new single array of people,
我认为我的for循环可以保持不变。
I think my for loop can stay the same.
而且我认为我仍然可以使用strcmp。
And I think I can still use strcmp.
但是现在我需要进入的不是名字而是人，
But now I need to go inside of not names but people,
并查找点名称字段。
and look for the dot name field.
因此，数据结构内部具有字段或变量。
So data structures have fields or variables inside of them.
所以我将在此处使用点符号，
So I'm going to use the dot notation there,
同样，进入人员阵列中的第i个人，
too, go into the i-th person in the people array,
并将该名称与引号，未引号“ David”进行比较。
and compare that name against, for instance, quote, unquote "David."
然后，如果我自己找到了“大卫”，
And then if I have found "David," in this case myself,
继续并再次访问人员数组，但使用printf打印
go ahead and access the people array again, but print out using printf
数字。
the number.
同样，点运算符是唯一的新语法
So again, the dot operator is the only new piece of syntax
这让我们进入了称为数据结构的新功能。
that's letting us go inside of this new feature known as a data structure.
如果我在进行了这些更改之后继续制作电话簿，
If I go ahead and make phonebook again after making those changes,
一切都很好。
all is well.
它编译OK。
It compiled OK.
而且，如果我运行./phonebook，现在希望可以再次找到我的电话号码。
And if I run ./phonebook, I now have hopefully found my number again.
所以这似乎是无用的练习，因为
So here is a seemingly useless exercise, in that all
我真正要做的是使用更多的代码行来重新实现同一程序
I really did was re-implement the same program using more lines of code
并使它变得更加复杂。
and making it more complicated.
但是现在它的设计更好了。
But it's now better designed.
还是朝着更好的设计迈出了一步，因为现在我已经
Or it's a step toward being better designed, because now I've
将所有内容封装在一个变量内，例如，人括号0，
encapsulated all inside of one variable, for instance, people bracket 0,
人括号1，我们关心的有关Brian的所有信息，
people bracket 1, all of the information we care about with respect to Brian,
或我，或者我们可能会加入此程序的其他任何人。
or me, or anyone else we might put into this program.
的确，这就是程序，这就是Google的世界，
And indeed, this is how programs, this is how Googles, of the world,
世界各地的Facebook将大量信息存储在一起。
Facebooks of the world store lots of information together.
考虑一下您的任何社交媒体帐户（例如Instagram），
Consider any of your social media accounts like Instagram,
或Facebook，或Snapchat等。
or Facebook, or Snapchat and the like.
您有多个关联的数据
You have multiple pieces of data associated
与您在所有这些平台上合作-不只是您的用户名
with you on all of those platforms-- not just your username
还有您的密码，您的帖子历史记录，
but also your password, also your history of posts,
还有你的朋友和追随者之类的。
also your friends and followers and the like.
因此，有很多信息表明这些公司，不管情况好坏，
So there's a lot of information that these companies, for better for worse,
正在收集我们所有人。
are collecting on all of us.
您能想象他们是否只有一个包含我们所有用户名的大型阵列，
And can you imagine if they just had one big array with all of our usernames,
一个包含我们所有密码的大型阵列，一个包含我们所有朋友的大型阵列？
one big array with all of our passwords, one big array with all of our friends?
就像，您可以肯定地想像一下，
Like, you can imagine certainly at scale,
要相信这肯定是一个糟糕的设计
that's got to be a bad design, to just trust
您将正确处理所有这些事情。
that you're going to get the ordering of all of these things right.
他们不那样做。
They don't do that.
相反，他们用某种语言编写的代码以某种方式封装
They instead write code in some language that somehow encapsulates
与我和布莱恩有关的所有信息
all the information related to me and Brian
和您进入某种数据结构。
and you inside of some kind of data structure.
那就是他们放入数据库或其他服务器的内容
And that's what they put in their database or some other server
在他们的后端。
on their back end.
因此，这种封装是我们现在使用C的一项功能。
So this encapsulation is a feature we now have in terms of C.
它允许我们创建自己的数据结构，然后可以使用
And it allows us to create our own data structures that we can then use
为了使相关数据保持在一起。
in order to keep related data together.
好吧，关于数据结构的任何问题，或者更多
All right, any questions, then, on data structures, or more
特别是typedef和struct，C关键字
specifically typedef and struct, the C keywords
使用它可以创建自己的自定义类型
with which you can create your own custom types
本身就是数据结构？
that themselves are data structures?
贝斯利？
Besley?
听众：嗨。
AUDIENCE: Hi.
因此，通常在main之外定义新的数据结构，例如
So is it typical to define the new data structure outside of main, like
在标题中？
in a header?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
在main之外定义新的数据结构是否很典型？
Is it typical to define a new data structure outside of main?
通常是的。
Quite often yes.
在这种情况下，这无关紧要，因为我只有
In this case, it's immaterial, because I only have
这个程序的一个功能是main。
one function in this program, main.
但是正如我们将在本周，下周及以后看到的那样，
But as we'll see this week and next week and onward,
我们的程序将开始变得更加复杂
our programs are going to start to get a little more complicated by nature
只是具有更多功能。
of just having more features.
并且，一旦拥有更多功能，您可能就会拥有更多功能。
And once you have more features, you probably have more functions.
而且，当您拥有更多功能时，您就需要数据结构
And when you have more functions, you want your data structure
可供所有这些功能使用。
to be available to all of those functions.
因此，我们将开始看到其中一些结构的定义，
And so we'll begin to see definition of some of these structures being,
确实，超出了我们自己的职能范围。
indeed, outside of our own functions.
彼得，交给你。
Peter, over to you.
听众：哦，是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, yeah.
稍后我们将在头文件中定义新的类吗？
Will we define new classes in header files later,
还是我们会继续在main之外定义它们？
or will we keep defining them outside of main?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
我们可以在头文件中定义自己的类型和数据结构吗？
Might we define our own types and our own data structures in header files?
是的。
Yes.
最终，我们也会这样做。
Eventually we'll do that, too.
到目前为止，您和我仅使用了其他人编写的头文件。
Thus far, you and I have only been using header files that other people wrote.
我们一直在使用C的作者创建的stdio.h，string.h。
We've been using stdio.h, string.h, that the authors of C created.
您一直在使用我们工作人员写的cs50.h。
You've been using cs50.h which we the staff wrote.
事实证明，您还可以创建自己的头文件，自己的.h文件，
It turns out, you can also create your own header files, your own .h files,
其中包含您要在多个文件中共享的代码段
inside of which are pieces of code that you want to share across multiple files
你自己。
of your own.
我们还没到那儿。
We're not quite there yet.
但是是的，彼得，这将是解决这个问题的方法
But yes, Peter, that would be a solution to this problem
通过将其放在一个中央位置。
by putting it in one central place.
Thiago，交给您。
Thiago, over to you.
听众：我是-
AUDIENCE: I was--
我当时在想，这门课程确实需要足够的信息来解决问题，
I was thinking, this course really takes enough information to solve the sets,
因为我感觉缺少信息。
because I feel there is missing information.
我是大一新生，我正在服用-
I am a freshman, and I was taking--
我是如此专心，无法继续前进。
I was so concentrating, and I can't go on, go ahead on the sets.
有什么我想念的吗？
Is there anything that I'm missing?
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：这是一个非常好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: It's a really good question.
而且很公平。
And quite fair.
诚然，我们的行动确实非常快。
We do move quite quickly, admittedly.
所以确实，从第0周起回想起消防水带的隐喻
So indeed, recall from week 0 the fire hose metaphor
是我从麻省理工学院的饮水机借来的。
that I borrowed from MIT's water fountain.
确实，情况确实如此。
Indeed, that's very much the case.
有很多新的语法，一次有很多新的想法。
There's a lot of new syntax, a lot of new ideas all at once.
但是当涉及到问题集中的个别问题时，
But when it comes to individual problems in the problem sets,
确实意识到您应该逐步采取这些措施。
do realize that you should take those step by step.
而且，它们总是从较不复杂到较复杂的工作。
And invariably, they tend to work from less complicated to more complicated.
在每个讲座和每个示例中
And throughout each of the lectures and each of the examples
我们所做的，无论是现场直播还是通过示例
that we do, either live or via the examples that
已在课程的网站上预先制作，以供您审核，
are premade on the course's website for your review,
您总是可以找到一些线索，提示或示例。
there's always little clues or hints or examples that you can then do.
当然，通过其他资源（例如实验室等），
And certainly, by way of other resources like labs and the like,
您还会看到其他构建基块吗？
will you see additional building blocks as well.
因此，随时可以联系更多个人。
So feel free to reach out more individually afterword.
很高兴为您指出其中的一些资源。
Happy to point you at some of those resources.
实际上，最近，您也会在该课程的网站上注意到这一点吗？
In fact, most recently, too, will you notice on the course's website
我们所说的“短裤”是指制作的较短的视频
what we call "shorts," which are shorter videos made
我的另一位同事CS50的道格·劳埃德（Doug Lloyd）
by another colleague of mine, CS50's own Doug Lloyd, which are literally
有关特定主题的简短视频。
short videos on very specific topics.
所以从今天起，您将看到Doug的短片
So after today, you'll see short videos by Doug
对线性搜索，二进制搜索有不同的看法，
with a different perspective on linear search, on binary search,
以及许多其他算法。
and on a number of other algorithms as well.
好问题。
Good question.
索菲娅，回到你身边。
Sophia, back to you.
听众：我很想知道返回值
AUDIENCE: I was wondering, with the return values
对于不同的错误情况，我们会-
that we have for different error cases, would that be--
就像，我们将用它做什么的一个例子？
like, what's an example of what we would use that for?
如果以后有几种不同的情况，那是为了以后
Is that for later if there are like several different cases
我们想以某种方式跟踪它们？
and we want to somehow keep track of them?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：正是后者。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly the latter.
所以说实话，这有点愚蠢
So right now, honestly, it's kind of stupid
我们甚至不愿意花时间返回0或返回1。
that we're even bothering to spend time returning 0 or returning 1.
就像，我们真的不需要这样做，因为我们不是
Like, we don't really need to do that, because we're not
使用信息。
using the information.
但是我们正在努力做的是奠定基础
But what we're trying to do is lay the foundation
对于更复杂的程序。
for more complicated programs.
实际上，在本周，下周及以后，
And indeed, this week and next week and beyond,
随着您自己的程序花费更长的时间，并且随着我们课程的进行，
as your own programs get a little longer, and as we, the course,
开始为您提供入门代码或分发
start providing you with starter code or distribution
代码，即工作人员和我写给您的代码行
code, that is, lines of code that the staff and I write that you then
必须建立，这将是一个非常有用的机制
have to build upon, it's going to be a very useful mechanism
以便能够表明这是错误的或另一件事是错误的。
to be able to signal that this went wrong or this other thing went wrong.
所以我们要做的就是为这种必然性做准备，
So all we're doing is preparing for that inevitability,
即使目前看来，这似乎并没有an痒。
even if right now it doesn't really seem to be scratching an itch.
安东尼？
Anthony?
听众：我只是想很快问一下，
AUDIENCE: I was just going to ask really quickly,
显然，在此代码中，我们有“ Brian”和您的名字“ David”。
obviously in this code we have "Brian" and your name, "David."
那是两个人。
And that's two people.
假设我们有10或20甚至30个人。
So let's say we had 10 or 20 or even 30 people.
我知道这是聊天中的问题，但我只是
I know it was a question in the chat, but I just
我也想为自己澄清。
wanted to clarify for myself, too.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：“如果”将发生什么变化？
DAVID MALAN: And the "what if" being what would change?
还是那个问题的结尾是什么？
Or, what was the end of that question?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
代码会发生什么变化？
What would change in the code?
还是我们为解决该问题所做的工作？
Or what we do exactly to address that problem?
戴维·马兰：好的，好的。
DAVID MALAN: Ah, OK.
好问题。
Good question.
因此，如果我们要使用更多的名称，例如第三名或第十名或类似名称，
So if we were to have more names, like a third name or a tenth name or the like,
在此版本的程序中，我们唯一需要更改的就是
the only things that we would have to change in this version of the program
首先是第14行，数组的大小。
is first, on line 14, the size of the array.
因此，如果我们要有10个人，我们需要
So if we're going to have 10 people, we need
提前决定我们将要有10个人。
to decide in advance that we're going to have 10 people.
更好的是，例如，我可以在这里分配一个常数。
Better still, I could, for instance, allocate myself a constant up here.
所以让我实际上上去，就像我们一样
So let me actually go up here, just like we
在上一课中做了类似的工作-const int NUMBER。
did in a previous class, where we did something like this-- const int NUMBER.
我将其初始化为10。
And I'll just initialize this to 10.
记得const表示常量。
And recall that const means constant.
这意味着该变量不能更改。
That means this variable can't change.
Int，当然意味着它是一个整数。
Int, of course means it's an integer.
我大写的事实只是人类的惯例
The fact that I've capitalized it is just a human convention
为了使人在视觉上清楚一点，这是
to make a little visually clear that this is
一个常数，这样您就不会忘记。
a constant, just so you don't forget.
但是它没有功能性作用。
But it has no functional role.
然后，当然，这只是要分配给NUMBER的值。
And then this, of course, is just the value to assign to NUMBER.
然后我可以在第16行下到这里并插入该变量
Then I could go down here on line 16 and plug in that variable
这样我就不必硬编码人们会做什么
so that I don't have to hardcode what people would
称为“魔数”，这只是一个数字
call a "magic number," which is just a number that
似乎无处不在。
appears seemingly out of nowhere.
现在，我已将所有特殊编号放在文件的顶部，
Now I've put all of my special numbers at the top of my file,
或文件顶部，现在我在这里使用此变量。
or toward the top of my file, and now I'm using this variable here.
然后我能做的-以前我只是在口头上提到过这一点-
And then what I could do-- and I alluded to this only verbally before--
例如，我绝对可以开始进行硬编码
I could absolutely start hardcoding in, for instance,
蒙塔古（Montague）的名字和编号，里斯维克（Rithvik）和本尼迪克特（Benedict）以及科迪（Cody）
Montague's name and number, and Rithvik's and Benedict's, and Cody's
和别的。
and others.
但说实话，如果您只是硬编码，这似乎有点愚蠢
But honestly, this seems kind of stupid if you're just hardcoding
所有这些名称和数字。
all of these names and numbers.
再过几周，我们将看到您如何实际
And in a few weeks, we'll see how you can actually
将所有相同的信息存储在电子表格中，
store all of the same information in like a spreadsheet,
或所谓的CSV文件-
or what's called a CSV file--
逗号分隔的值-甚至在适当的数据库中，Facebook都使用
Comma Separated Values-- or even in a proper database, which the Facebooks
世界各地的Google都会使用。
and Googles of the world would use.
但是我现在能做的就是这样。
But what I could do for now is something like this.
因为int我得到0，所以我少于人数，即i ++。
For int i gets 0, i less than the number of people, i++.
也许我可以做这样的事情-
And maybe I could do something like this--
括号中的点名称等于get_string，“名称是什么”
people bracket i dot name equals get_string, "What's the name"
问号。
question mark.
然后在这里我可以将括号括起来，点号等于
And then here I could do people bracket i dot number equals
get_string，“他们的电话号码是多少？”
get_string, "What's their number?"
我也可以问这个问题。
And I could ask that question, too.
因此，现在程序的设计变得更好了。
So now the program's getting to be a little better designed.
我不是随便对我和Brian进行硬编码。
I'm not arbitrarily hardcoding just me and Brian.
现在它是动态的。
Now it's dynamic.
从技术上讲，电话簿目前仅支持10个人，
And technically, the phone book only supports 10 people at the moment,
但我也可以使它充满活力。
but I could make that dynamic, too.
我也可以叫get_int。
I could also call get_int.
或者，就像您上周所做的一样，使用命令行参数
Or, like you did this past week, use a command line argument
并参数化代码，以便它实际上可以
and parameterize the code so that it can actually
适用于2个人，10个人-无论您想要什么，
be for 2 people, 10 people-- whatever you want,
该程序可以为您动态地适应它。
the program can dynamically adapt to it for you.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
在结构上，在类型上还是类似的？
On structs, on types, or the like?
不？
No?
好的。
All right.
那我们怎么到这里的？
So how did we get here?
回想一下我们从搜索这个问题开始，
Recall that we started with this problem of searching,
因此我们只想在门口找人。
whereby we just want to find someone in the doors.
我们只想在数组中找到一个人。
We just want to find someone in the array.
我们很快就将事情升级了
We've sort of escalated things pretty quickly
不仅要查找数字或名称，而且要查找
to finding not just numbers or names but now
这些数据结构形式的带有数字的名称。
names with numbers in the form of these data structures.
但是要有效地做到这一点，实际上需要一个更智能的算法
But to do this efficiently really requires a smarter algorithm
像二进制搜索一样。
like binary search.
到目前为止，尽管回想起，我们仅在C代码线性搜索中使用过，
Up until now, we've only used in C code linear search, even though, recall,
我们确实拥有用于二进制搜索的伪代码。
that we did have at our disposal the pseudocode for binary search.
但是，使用二进制搜索时，我们将需要对数据进行排序。
But with binary search, we're going to need the data to be sorted.
因此，如果您想获得搜索的速度优势
And so if you want to get the speed benefits of searching
通过对数字进行排序可以更快地找到某人
more quickly by having sorted numbers, somehow someone
必须为我们做到这一点。
is going to have to do that for us.
例如，乔为我们整理了所有这些数字。
Joe, for instance, sorted behind the curtain all of these numbers for us.
但是他使用什么算法将打开
But what algorithm did he use is going to open up
关于如何有效地对数字进行排序的一堆蠕虫。
a whole can of worms as to how we can sort numbers efficiently.
实际上，如果您是Google和Facebook
And indeed, if you're the Googles and the Facebooks
以及全世界数以百万计的Instagram，
and the Instagrams of the world, with millions,
数十亿条数据和用户，您当然可以
billions of pieces of data and users, you surely
想保持数据排序，大概是，
want to keep that data sorted, presumably,
这样您就可以使用二进制搜索等算法
so that you can use algorithms like binary search
在您搜索朋友或内容时快速查找信息。
to find information quickly when you're searching for friends or for content.
但是，让我们继续，这里需要休息五分钟。
But let's go ahead and here take a five-minute break.
当我们回来时，我们将考虑一些算法
And when we come back, we'll consider a few algorithms
进行排序，这将使我们能够执行我们刚才讨论的所有事情。
for sorting that's going to enable us to do everything we've just now discussed.
五分见。
See you in five.
好的。
All right.
我们回来了。
We are back.
回顾一下，我们有两种不同的搜索算法，线性搜索
So to recap, we have a couple different algorithms for searching, linear search
和二进制搜索。
and binary search.
到目前为止，二元搜索显然是所有指标中的赢家。
Binary search is clearly the winner from all measures we've seen thus far.
问题是数据需要按顺序进行高级排序
The catch is that the data needs to be sorted in advanced in order
应用该算法。
to apply that algorithm.
所以让我们给自己一个工作模型
So let's just give ourselves a working model
整理东西的意思。
for what it means to sort something.
好吧，一如既往，如果您认为这只是要解决的另一个问题，
Well, as always, if you think of this as just another problem to be solved,
它具有输入和输出，目标是获取输入
it's got input and output, and the goal is to take that input
并产生该输出。
and produce that output.
好吧，输入的是什么？
Well, what's the input?
这将是一大堆未排序的值。
It's going to be a whole bunch of unsorted values.
当然，目标是获得排序后的值。
And the goal, of course, is to get sorted values.
因此，该过程中有趣的部分正在进行
So the interesting part of the process is going
成为中间的任何东西。
to be whatever there is in the middle.
但是更具体地说，如果我们现在就这个未分类的问题进行思考
But just to be even more concrete, if we think now in terms of this unsorted
输入是输入数组-因为毕竟，
input as being an array of input-- because after all,
这可能是迄今为止我们所见过的最有用的机制，
that's perhaps the most useful mechanism we've seen thus far,
只需使用一个变量名即可一次传递一堆值-
to pass around a bunch of values at once using just one variable name--
我们可能有一个像这样的数组6 3 8 5 2 7 4 1
we might have an array like this, 6 3 8 5 2 7 4 1, which seems to be, indeed,
随机排序，即未排序。
randomly ordered, that is unsorted.
我们想将其转换为仅1 2的等效数组
And we want to turn that into an equivalent array that's just 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8。
3 4 5 6 7 8.
所以这次是八个数字，而不是七个。
So eight numbers this time instead of seven.
但是，这次的目的不是要搜索它们本身，而是要对其进行排序。
But the goal this time is not to search them, per se, but to sort them.
但是在我超越自己之前，有人
But before I get ahead of myself, could someone
退缩整个智力活动
push back on this whole intellectual exercise
我们将要首先进行排序吗？
we're about to do with sorting in the first place?
有人可以争论为什么我们不这样做
Could someone make an argument as to why we might not
想打扰使用排序数组，为什么我们不
want to bother using a sorted array, why we might not
想打扰元素排序，等等，让我们只使用线性搜索
want to bother sorting the elements, and heck, let's just use linear search
寻找一些元素-
to find some element--
无论是门后面的数字，还是数组中的名称。
whether it's a number behind a door, a name in an array.
就像，什么时候我们可能只想使用线性搜索而不理会排序？
Like, when might we want to just use linear search and not bother sorting?
索菲娅，你觉得呢？
Sophia, what do you think?
观众：我们在排序时可能会遇到错误，
AUDIENCE: We could encounter errors in sorting,
并可能导致错误，例如，
and that might cause errors, like, unpredictability in terms of,
就像，如果我们能找到一些东西。
like, if we can find something.
与线性搜索相比，我们知道可以找到它。
Versus linear search, we know we can find it.
戴维·马兰：好的，很公平。
DAVID MALAN: OK, quite fair.
我承认，我们已经实现了二进制搜索，而不是伪代码。
I will concede that implementing binary search, not in pseudocode, which we've
已经完成，但是在代码中实际上更困难，
already done, but in code is actually more difficult,
因为你必须处理四舍五入，特别是
because you have to deal with rounding, especially
如果您有奇怪数量的门，例如奇数门
if you've got a weird number of doors, like an odd number of doors
而不是偶数门或这些长度的阵列。
versus an even number of doors or an array of those lengths.
老实说，您必须处理这些极端情况，
Honestly, you've got to deal with these corner cases,
如四舍五入或四舍五入，因为任何时候
like rounding down or rounding up, because anything time
将某物除以2，可能会得到一个分数
you divide something by 2, you might get a fractional value
否则您可能会得到一个整数。
or you might get a whole number.
因此，我们必须做出一些决定。
So we've got to make some decisions.
因此，它是完全可解决的。
So it's totally solvable.
几十年来，人类一直在编写实现二进制搜索的代码。
And humans for decades have been writing code that implements binary search.
这是完全可能的。
It's totally possible.
有可以使用的库。
There's libraries you can use.
但这绝对是更具挑战性的，您需要承担风险。
But it's definitely more challenging, and you open yourselves up to risk.
但是让我规定那是可以的。
But let me stipulate that that's OK.
在我漂亮的进步中，我现在已经足够好了
I am good enough at this point in my progression where I'm pretty
确保我可以正确实施它。
sure I can implement it correctly.
因此，正确性与我无关。
So correctness is not my concern.
还有什么可能使我无法对元素数组进行排序？
What else might demotivate me from sorting an array of elements?
是什么促使我去做啊，只要使用线性搜索即可。
And what might motivate me to, ah, just use linear search.
很简单
It's so simple.
有人可以提出为什么吗？
Can anyone propose why?
奥利维亚，你怎么看？
Olivia, what do you think?
观众：如果游戏的名字是效率，
AUDIENCE: If the name of the game is efficiency,
并且您有足够小的数据集，那么
and you have a small enough data set, then
您最好只是搜索而不是排序
you might as well just search it versus sort
它，这将是额外的费用。
it, which would be an extra expense.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，说得很好。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really well said.
如果您的数据集相对较小，
If you've got a relatively small data set,
您的计算机以每秒十亿次的速度运行，
and your computer operates at a billion operations per second,
例如，我的上帝，谁在乎您的代码是否糟透了，而且速度有点慢？
for instance, my God, who cares if your code sucks and it's a little bit slow?
只是以低效的方式来做。
Just do it the inefficient way.
为什么？
Why?
因为可能要花几分钟才能实施更简单的方法
Because it's going to take you maybe a few minutes to implement the simpler
像线性搜索这样的算法，即使它需要花费更长的时间
algorithm like linear search, even though it's going to take longer
运行，而这可能要花费您数十分钟甚至一小时的时间
to run, whereas it might take you tens of minutes, maybe an hour
左右，不仅可以编写而且可以调试某些东西
or so, to not only write but debug something
像是更高级的算法，例如二进制搜索
like a fancier algorithm, like binary search, at which point
您可能比您花费了更多的时间来编写代码，更快的代码
you might have spent more time writing the code, the faster code, than you
本来只运行较慢的代码。
would have just running the slower code.
我可以亲自谈一谈。
And I can speak to this personally.
回到研究生院，我正在做的一些研究
Back in grad school, some of the research I was doing
涉及非常大的数据集的分析。
involved analysis of very large data sets.
而且我必须编写代码才能分析这些数据。
And I had to write code in order to analyze this data.
我本来可以花数小时，数天甚至
And I could have spent hours, days, even,
编写我可以分析的最佳设计算法
writing the best designed algorithm I could to analyze
尽可能高效地处理数据。
the data as efficiently as possible.
或者，坦率地说，我可以编写糟糕的代码版本，
Or, frankly, I could write the crappy version of the code,
睡了八个小时，我的代码只会
go to sleep for eight hours, and my code will just
早上产生我想要的输出。
produce the output I want by morning.
这是一个非常现实的，合理的权衡。
And that is a very real-world, reasonable trade-off to make.
实际上，在接下来的几周中，这将成为主题
And indeed, this is going to be thematic in the weeks that
在过程中继续进行权衡。
proceed in the course, where there's going to be this trade-off.
很多时候，权衡是
And quite often, the trade-off is going to be
时间，复杂性或您正在使用的空间或内存量。
time, or complexity, or the amount of space or memory that you're using.
作为一名优秀的计算机科学家的一部分艺术，
And part of the art of being a good computer scientist,
然后程序员试图确定该行在哪里。
and in turn programmer, is trying to decide where the line is.
您是否会付出更多的努力来使自己变得更好，更快，更高效
Do you exert more effort upfront to make a better, faster, more efficient
算法，或者您可能偷偷摸摸地走了
algorithm, or do you maybe cut some corners
在那里，您可以专注于自己最宝贵的资源，人的时间，
there so that you can focus your most precious resource, human time,
还有其他更具根本挑战性的问题吗？
on other, more fundamentally challenging problems?
因此，我们针对该课程的问题集和实验
So we for the course's problem sets and labs
将始终规定最重要的内容。
will always prescribe what's most important.
但是在几个星期的时间里，我们遇到了一个问题
But in a few weeks' time, with one of our problem
设置您将实现自己的拼写检查器。
sets will you implement your very own spell checker.
在那个拼写检查器的目标中
And among the goals of that spell checker
将尽量减少时间
are going to be to minimize the amount of time
您的代码需要运行，并且还可以最大程度地减少空间或内存量
your code is taking to run, and also to minimize the amount of space or memory
您的程序在运行时正在执行的操作。
that your program is taking while running.
因此，我们将开始更加欣赏这些折衷。
And so we'll begin to appreciate those trade-offs ever more.
但是确实如此-我真的很喜欢Olivia的表述-
But indeed, it's the case-- and I really like Olivia's formulation of it--
如果您的数据集很小，则可能不值得
if your data set is pretty small, it's probably not worth
编写尽可能最快，设计最好的算法。
writing the fastest, best designed algorithm as possible.
只需以简单的方式，正确的方式编写，
Just write it the simple way, the correct way,
并迅速得到答案，然后继续前进。
and get the answer quickly, and move on.
但是，我敢说，这不会出现很多问题。
But that's not going to be the case for a lot of problems, dare I say,
生活中的大多数问题。
most problems in life.
如果您要建立Facebook或Instagram或Whatsapp，
If you're building Facebook or Instagram or Whatsapp,
或获得数以百万计的当今任何最受欢迎的服务
or any of today's most popular services that are getting thousands, millions
一次存储新数据，您不能只是
of new pieces of data at a time, you can't just
有效地线性搜索您在LinkedIn上的所有朋友或联系。
linearly search all of your friends or connections on LinkedIn efficiently.
您不能只线性搜索数十亿个网页
You can't just linearly search the billions of web pages
Google和Microsoft在其搜索引擎中建立索引。
that Google and Microsoft index in their search engines.
您必须对此更加精明。
You've got to be smarter about it.
毫无疑问，您的程序越成功
And undoubtedly, the more successful your programs are
和您的代码或网站，无论您的应用是什么情况，
and your code are, or websites, your apps, whatever the case may be,
更重要的设计确实发挥了作用。
the more important design does come into play.
因此，确实，让我们现在规定，目标是不要一次搜索这些门；
So indeed, let's stipulate now that the goal is not to search these doors once;
目标是不要一次搜索这些灯泡；
the goal is not to search these light bulbs once;
目标不是一次搜索电话簿，而是再次搜索
the goal is not to search the phone book once, but rather again
一遍又一遍。
and again and again.
如果是这种情况，那么我们可能
And if that's going to be the case, then we probably
应该花更多的时间和更多的前期复杂性
should spend a little more time and a little more complexity upfront
得到我们的代码，不仅正确而且高效，
getting our code, not only right but also efficient,
这样我们就可以一次又一次地从这种效率中受益
so that we can benefit from that efficiency again and again
再一次，随着时间的流逝。
and again, over time.
那么我们应该如何对一些数字进行排序。
So how might we go about sorting some numbers.
所以实际上，让我看看，如果可以的话，
So in fact, let me see, to do this, if we can maybe
从布莱恩那里得到帮助。
get a hand from Brian in back.
布莱恩，您介意协助分类吗？
Brian, do you mind helping with sorting?
布莱恩：是的，绝对如此。
BRIAN: Yeah, absolutely.
因此，我现在这里有八个数字，所有数字似乎都没有排序。
So I've got eight numbers here right now that all seem to be in unsorted order.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
布赖恩，您可以继续吗，您能为我们对这八个数字进行排序吗？
And Brian, could you go ahead, and could you sort these eight numbers for us?
布莱恩：是的，我将它们整理好。
BRIAN: Yeah, I'll put them in order.
因此，我们将采用这些，并且-
So we'll take these and--
嗯，好吧。
um-- and all right.
我认为这些现在已经排序了。
I think these are now in sorted order.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, indeed.
我同意。
I agree.
现在，让我们从听众中进行一些评论，进行一些观察。
And now let's take some critique from the audience, some observations.
有人介意解释Brian是如何对这8个数字进行排序的吗？
Would someone mind explaining how Brian just sorted those eight numbers?
为了达到最终结果，Brian只是一步一步地做了什么？
What did Brian just do, step by step, in order to get to that end result?
输入未排序，现在输出已排序。
The input was unsorted, the output now is sorted.
他做了什么？
So what did he do?
彼得，您看到了什么？
Peter, what did you see happen?
听众：他一步一步地经历了他们。
AUDIENCE: He went through them step by step.
如果他们的顺序在增加，他会翻转他们，
And if they were in increasing order, he flipped them,
并继续这样做，直到他们都正确[听不清]。
and kept doing it until they were all in the correct [INAUDIBLE]..
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
他一步一步地寻找小价值
He kept step by step kind of looking for small values
然后将它们向左移动，并寻找更大的价值
and moving them to the left, and looking for big values
并将它们向右移动，以便有效地选择
and moving them to the right, so effectively selecting
一次编号，并将其放置在正确的位置。
numbers one at a time and putting it into its right place.
因此，让我们看看，如果可能的话，这可能是慢动作，布莱恩。
So let's see this is, maybe in more slow motion, if you will, Brian.
而且，如果您可以做些古怪的话
And if you could be a little more pedantic
并确切说明您在做什么。
and explain exactly what you're doing.
我看到您已经将数字重设为其原始的，未排序的顺序。
I see you've already reset the numbers to their original, unsorted order.
我们为什么不继续有条不紊地开始呢？
Why don't we go ahead and start a little more methodically?
您能继续前进吗？对我们来说，这次比较缓慢，
And could you go ahead and for us, more slowly this time,
选择最小值。
select the smallest value.
因为我确实认为，按照彼得的说法，
Because I do think, per Peter, it's going
需要结束在最左边。
to need to end up at the far left.
布莱恩：是的，当然。
BRIAN: Yeah, sure.
所以我在看数字，而1是最小的数字。
So I'm looking at the numbers, and the 1 is the smallest.
所以我现在的价值最小。
So I now have the smallest value.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
因此，您确实很快地做到了。
So you did that really quickly.
但是我觉得你像是自由自在
But I feel like you took the liberty of being
可以同时俯瞰所有事物的人。
a human who can kind of have this bird's eye view of everything all at once.
但是，如果可以的话，可以像计算机一样。
But be a little more computer-like, if you could.
而且如果这8个数字在技术上是排列在一起的，
And if these eight numbers are technically in an array,
有点像我在这里的七个门
kind of like my seven doors out here, such
一次只能看一个数字，你能否变得更有条理
that you can only look at one number at a time, can you be even more methodical
并仔细地告诉我们您如何找到最小的
and deliberate this time in telling us how you found the smallest
放置多少？
number to put into place?
布莱恩：当然。
BRIAN: Sure.
我猜，由于计算机一次只能看到一个数字，
I guess, since the computer can only look at one number at a time,
我将从这个数组的左侧开始
I would start at the left side of this array
然后按照正确的方式工作，一次查看每个数字。
and work my way through the right, looking at each number one at a time.
所以我可能会从6开始，然后说，好的，现在
So I might start with the 6 and say, OK, this right now
是到目前为止我查看过的最小的数字。
is the smallest number I've looked at so far.
但是，我看下一个数字，它是3，小于6。
But then I look at the next number, and it's a 3, and that's smaller than a 6.
所以现在3，这是我到目前为止发现的最小数字。
So now the 3, that's the smallest number I found so far.
因此，我会记住这一点并继续寻找。
So I'll remember that and keep looking.
8比3大，所以我不必担心。
The 8 is bigger than the 3, so I don't need to worry about that.
5比3大。
The 5 is bigger than the 3.
2小于3，所以现在是
The 2 is smaller than the 3, so that now is
到目前为止我发现的最小的数字。
the smallest number I've found so far.
但是我还没有完成。
But I'm not done yet.
所以我会继续寻找。
So I'll keep looking.
7大于2，4大于2。
The 7 is bigger than the 2, the 4 is bigger than the 2.
但是1小于2。
But the 1 is smaller than the 2.
因此，现在我一直走到阵列的尽头。
So now I've made my way all the way to the end of the array.
我可以说1是我找到的最小数字。
And 1, I can say, is the smallest number that I found.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以我听到的是您正在做所有这些比较，
So what I'm hearing is you're doing all of these comparisons,
也与彼得的暗示相似，您不断检查，
also similar to what Peter implied, and you keep checking,
这个小一点，这个小一点，这个小一点，
is this smaller, is this smaller, is this smaller,
您是否正在跟踪所看到的当前最小数字？
and you're keeping track of the currently smallest number you've seen?
布莱恩：是的，听起来不错。
BRIAN: Yeah, that sounds about right.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
所以你找到了。
So you found it.
我认为这是一开始的事情。
And I think it belongs at the beginning.
那么，我们现在如何将其落实到位？
So how do we put this into place now?
布莱恩：是的，所以我想放在开头。
BRIAN: Yeah, so I want to put it at the beginning.
确实没有空间。
There's not really space for it.
因此，只要将这些数字移开，我就可以腾出空间。
So I could make space for it, just by shifting these numbers over.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
等等。
Wait, wait.
但是我觉得您只是-现在您的工作量翻了一番。
But I feel like you're just-- now you're doubling the amount of work.
我觉得-不要那样做。
I feel like-- don't do all that.
感觉您将要做的步骤比我们需要的更多。
That feels like you're going to do more steps than we need.
我们在这里还能做什么？
What else could we do here?
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: OK.
因此，另一种选择是，它需要进入该位置，
So the other option is, it needs to go in this spot,
像阵列中的第一个点。
like this first spot in the array.
所以我可以把它放在那里。
So I could just put it there.
但是，如果我这样做，我将不得不拿现在的6
But if I do that, I'm going to have to take the 6 which is there right now
并拉出6。
and pull the 6 out.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，但是我认为是-
DAVID MALAN: All right, but I think that's--
布莱恩：所以1在正确的位置，但是6在不正确的位置。
BRIAN: So the 1 is in the right place, but the 6 isn't.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，我同意。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I agree.
但是我认为可以，对吗？
But I think that's OK, right?
因为这些数字是随机开始的，所以6放在错误的位置
Because these numbers started randomly, and so the 6 is in the wrong place
反正。
anyway.
我认为，仅将其移至其他位置不会使问题变得更糟。
I don't think we're making the problem any worse by just moving it elsewhere.
实际上，我想，交换两个数字要快得多，
And indeed, it's a lot faster, I would think, to just swap two numbers,
将一个移动到另一个，反之亦然，然后
move one to the other and vice versa, then
在所有这些数字之间移动。
shift all of those numbers in between.
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
所以我在最后一刻从头寸中取出了1
So I took the 1 out of the position at the very end
阵列的所有位置，一直到右侧。
of the array, all the way on the right-hand side.
所以我想我可以拿6放到那里，
So I guess I could take the 6 and just put it there,
因为那是一个可以放置数字的开放空间。
because that's where there's an open space to put the number.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
而且它并不完全在正确的空间中，但同样，情况也不会更糟。
And it's not exactly in the right space, but again, it's no worse off.
所以我喜欢。
So I like that.
好的。
All right.
但现在，事实是1的位置正确-实际上，
But now, the fact that the 1 is in the right place-- and indeed,
您已将其照亮以表示尽可能多的内容-
you've illuminated it to indicate as much--
我觉得我们几乎可以忽略以后的1
I feel like we can pretty much ignore the 1 henceforth
现在只需选择下一个最小的元素。
and now just select the next smallest element.
那你能带我们经历一下吗？
So can you walk us through that?
布莱恩：是的，所以我想我会重复同样的过程。
BRIAN: Yeah, so I guess I'd repeat the same process.
我将从3开始。
I'd start with the 3.
这是我到目前为止发现的最小数字。
That's the smallest number I've found so far.
我一直在寻找。
And I keep looking.
8大于3，5大于3。
The 8 is bigger than the 3, the 5 is bigger than the 3.
2小于3。
The 2 is smaller than the 3.
所以我会记得2。
So I'll remember that 2.
到目前为止，这是我所见过的最小的东西。
That's the smallest thing I've seen so far.
然后，我只需要检查是否有小于2的东西。
And then I just need to check to see if there's anything smaller than the 2.
我看一下7、4和6
And I look at the 7, the 4, and the 6.
这些都不比2小。
None of those are smaller than the 2.
因此，我可以说2是数组的下一个最小数字。
So the 2, I can say is the next smallest number for the array.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
那你该放在哪里呢？
And where would you put that then?
布莱恩：那需要排在第二位。
BRIAN: That needs to go in the second spot.
因此，我需要将3个拉出。
So I need to pull the 3 out.
我想我可以拿3放到这个空旷的地方
And I guess I can take the 3 and just put it into this open spot, where
有可用空间。
there's available space.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
我觉得它开始变得清晰起来
And I feel like it's starting to become clear
我们处于某种循环之中，因为您几乎被告知
that we're inside some kind of loop, because you pretty much told
同样的故事，但数字不同。
the same story again but with a different number.
您介意将算法继续到底吗
Do you mind just continuing the algorithm to the end
然后选择下一个最小，下一个最小，下一个最小的
and select the next smallest, next smallest, next smallest,
并得到排序？
and get that sorted?
布莱恩：当然。
BRIAN: Sure.
所以我们得到了8。
So we got the 8.
5小于该值，3小于该值。
5 is smaller than that, 3 is smaller than that.
然后其余的数字是7、4、6。
And then the rest of the number is 7, 4, 6.
这些都更大。
Those are all bigger.
因此，这里的3将进入排序位置。
So the 3, that's going to go into sorted position here.
我将拿8交换它。
And I'll take the 8 and swap it.
现在我来看看5。
Now I'm going to look at the 5.
8和7都更大。
8 and 7 are both bigger.
4比5小，但6大。
The 4 is smaller than the 5, but the 6 is bigger.
因此，这是我到目前为止所看到的最小的数字4。
So the 4, that's the smallest number I've seen so far.
因此，将要安装的4，我将与5交换它。
So the 4, that's going to go into place, and I'll swap it with the 5.
现在我有了8。
And now I've got the 8.
7小于8，因此我会记住这一点。
The 7 is smaller than the 8, so I'll remember that.
5小于那个。
5 is smaller than that.
6更大。
The 6 is bigger.
因此，下一个数字是5。
So the 5, that's going to be the next number.
现在我剩下了7。
And now I'm left with 7.
8更大，所以7仍然是我所见过的最小的。
8 is bigger, so 7 is still the smallest I've seen.
但是6较小，因此下一个6。
But 6 is smaller, so 6 goes next.
现在我只剩下最后两个了。
And now I'm down to the last two.
在最后两个数字8和7之间，则7较小。
And between the last two, the 8 and the 7, the 7 is smaller.
因此7将会在这个位置上。
So the 7 is going to go in this spot.
至此，我只剩下一个号码了。
And at this point, I've only got one number left.
因此，该数字必须位于已排序的位置。
So that number must be in sorted position.
现在，我要说的是这是一组排序的数字。
And now I would say that this is a sorted array of numbers.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
因此，这绝对是正确的。
So it definitely seems to be correct.
感觉有点慢。
It felt a little slow.
但是，当然，计算机可以更快地完成此任务
But of course, the computer could do this much faster
比我们，使用一个实际的数组。
than we, using an actual array.
如果您不介意我的观察，
And if you don't mind my making an observation,
看起来如果我们有八个数字开头，或者更一般地，n
it looks like if we have eight numbers to begin with, or n more generally,
看起来您基本上进行了n减1的比较，
it looks like you essentially did n minus 1 comparisons,
因为您一直在继续比较数字-实际上，没有进行过n次比较。
because you kept comparing numbers again-- actually, did n comparisons.
您看了第一个数字，然后
You looked at the first number, and then you
一遍又一遍地将其与所有其他可能值进行比较
compared it again and again and again at all of the other possible values
为了找到最小的元素。
in order to find the smallest element.
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
因为对于数组中的每个数字，我必须进行比较才能看到，
Because for each of the numbers in the array, I had to do a comparison to see,
它比我到目前为止所见的最小物体还小吗？
is it smaller than the smallest thing that I've seen so far?
如果它更小，则比我需要记住的要小。
And if it is smaller, than I needed to remember that.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
因此，在每个通行证中，您都会考虑每个数字，因此首先要考虑n个数字。
So in each pass you considered every number, so a total of n numbers first.
因此，您找到了将数字1放在它的位置，
And so you found the number 1 you put it in its place,
这样一来，您便可以清楚地得到n减1的数字。
and that left you to be clear with n minus 1 numbers thereafter.
然后，n减2个数字，n减3个数字，点，
And then after that, n minus 2 numbers, n minus 3 numbers, dot,
点，点，一直到最后一个数字。
dot, dot, all the way down to one final number.
所以我认为这是正确的。
So I think this is correct.
我认为这是一种非常刻意的方式
And I think that's a pretty deliberate way
这些元素的排序比您的第一种方法更故意，
of sorting these elements, a little more deliberately than your first approach,
布赖恩（Brian），我可能会形容为更加有机。
Brian, which I might describe as a little more organic.
你有点喜欢-
You kind of did it like--
更像人类，只是一种盯着眼睛的东西和动人的东西
more like a human, just kind of eyeballing things and moving things
大约。
around.
但是如果我们将其翻译成代码，
But if we were to translate this into code,
回想一下，我们必须如此精确。
recall that we have to be ever so precise.
因此，让我一起考虑一下，我们到底可以如何翻译布莱恩
And so let me consider altogether how exactly we might translate what Brian
最终还是要伪代码。
did ultimately to, again, pseudocode.
因此，他所做的实际上是一个具有名称的算法。
So what he did is actually an algorithm that has a name.
这称为选择排序。
It's called selection sort.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，它最终是对元素进行排序。
Well, it's sorting the elements ultimately.
这是通过让Brian或真正的计算机来实现的，
And it's doing so by having Brian, or really the computer,
一遍又一遍地选择最小的元素。
select the smallest elements again and again and again.
一旦找到每个如此小的元素，
And once you found each such small element,
您将获得忽略它的额外好处。
you get the added benefit of just ignoring it.
确实，每次Brian点亮数字时，
Indeed, every time Brian lit up a number,
他不需要一直比较它，所以他正在做的工作量
he didn't need to keep comparing it, so the amount of work he was doing
在减少每次迭代-n个数字，然后n减1，
was decreasing each iteration-- n numbers, then n minus 1,
然后n减2，n减3，依此类推。
then n minus 2, n minus 3, and so forth.
所以我们可以考虑一下该算法的运行时间
And so we can think about the running time of this algorithm
作为在其实际伪代码中的清单。
as being manifest in its actual pseudocode.
那么我们如何定义伪代码呢？
So how might we define the pseudocode?
好吧，让我建议我们这样考虑-
Well, let me propose that we think of it like this--
因为我从0到n减去1。
for i from 0 to n minus 1.
现在，无疑这可能是最神秘的
Now, undoubtedly this is probably the most cryptic
在屏幕上三行伪代码中查找一行。
looking line of the three lines of pseudocode on the screen.
但是同样，这是那种
But again, this is the kind of thing that
随着时间的流逝，它应该成为死记硬背的内存，或者仅仅是代码的本能。
should become rote memory over time, or just instincts with code.
我们已经在C语言中看到了如何编写for循环。
We've seen in C how you can write a for loop.
按照惯例，对于循环而言，通常从0开始计数。
For loops typically, by convention, start counting at 0.
但是，如果您有n个元素，则您不想累加n个元素。
But if you have n elements, you don't want to count up through n.
您要计数最多n或等效地直到n减去1，
You want to count up to n or equivalently up through n minus 1,
所以从0到n减去1。
so from 0 to n minus 1.
好的。
All right.
现在，我接下来要做什么-
Now what do I want to do on the next--
在第一次迭代？
on the first iteration?
在第i个项目和最后一个项目之间找到最小的项目。
Find the smallest item between the i-th item and the last item.
乍一看，这并不是很明显。
So this is not quite obvious, I think, at first glance.
但是，我确实认为这是Brian所做的事情的合理描述。
But I do think it's a fair characterization of what Brian did.
因为如果我初始化为0，那就像Brian指向
Because if i is initialized to 0, that was like Brian pointing
他的左手放在架子最左边的第一个数字上。
his left hand at the first number on the very left of the shelf.
然后他做的就是发现第i个元素之间的最小元素，
And what he then did was he found the smallest element between the i-th item,
第一项为0，最后一项为。
the first item 0, and the last item.
所以这是一种非常奇特的说法，
So that's kind of a very fancy way of saying,
Brian，在所有n个元素中找到最小的元素。
Brian, find the smallest elements among all n elements.
然后他所做的就是将最小的物品换成第i个物品。
Then what he did was swapped the smallest item with the i-th item.
所以他只是做了那个switcheroo，以至于没有
So he just did that switcheroo, so as to not have
浪费时间转移一切。
to waste time shifting everything over.
相反，他只是通过交换为它腾出了空间
He instead just made room for it by swapping it
带有错误位置的价值。
with the value that was in its wrong place.
但是现在，在此循环的下一个迭代中，请考虑for循环的工作方式。
But now in the next iteration of this loop, consider how a for loop works.
您可以使用伪代码隐式地执行i ++。
You do an i++ implicitly in pseudocode.
这就是这里发生的事情。
That's what's happening here.
所以现在我等于1。
So now i equals 1.
在第i个项目（索引为1 0的项目）之间找到最小的项目，
Find the smallest item between the i-th item, item 1 0 indexed,
和最后一个项目。
and the last item.
所以这是一种奇特的说法，布莱恩，检查所有n个元素
So this is a fancy way of saying, Brian, check all of the n elements
再次，除了第一个，因为现在你是
again, except for the first, because now you're
从位置1而不是位置0开始。
starting at location 1 instead of location 0.
现在算法继续进行。
And now the algorithm proceeds.
所以你可以用不同的方式写这段代码
So you could write this code in different ways
在英语中就像伪代码，但这似乎
in English like pseudocode, but this seems
是该算法的合理表述。
to be a reasonable formulation of exactly that algorithm.
但是现在让我们更直观地看待它，
But let's see it a little more visually now,
却没有人类在数字周围移动的所有切换。
without all of the switching around of the humans moving around the numbers.
让我继续使用此可视化。
Let me go ahead and use this visualization.
我们将在课程的网站上放置一个链接
And we'll put a link on the course's website
如果您也想与此一起玩。
if you'd like to play with this as well.
这只是某人对数字数组的可视化。
This is just someone's visualization of an array of numbers.
但是这次，不是将数字表示为符号，十进制数字，
But this time, rather than represent the numbers as symbols, decimal digits,
现在此人正在使用垂直条，例如条形图。
now this person is using vertical bars, like a bar chart.
这意味着小条就像是一个小数字，
And what this means is that a small bar is like a small number,
一个大酒吧是一个很大的数目。
and a big bar is a big number.
因此，此处的目标是这些条形图，这些条形图同样可能是数字，
So the goal here is to these bars, which equivalently might as well be numbers,
从短条到高条，从左到右。
from short bars over to tall bars, left to right.
我要继续。
And I'm going to go ahead.
在这里的顶部，我可以选择我的排序算法。
And along the top of the here, I can choose my sorting algorithm.
回想一下，我们刚才描述的是选择排序。
And the one we just described, recall, was selection sort.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
请注意，我想花点时间来整理一下您的想法
And notice, it takes a moment, I think, to wrap your mind
围绕这里发生的事情。
around what's happening here.
但是请注意，这条粉红色的线是从左到右，因为那是
But notice that this pink line is going from left to right, because that's
本质上是Brian在做什么。
essentially what Brian was doing.
他来回走动，来回走动，来回走动
He was walking back and forth, back and forth, back and forth
在那组数字中，寻找下一个最小的数字，
through that shelf of numbers, looking for the next smallest number,
他一直将最小的数字放在左边。
and he kept putting the smallest number over on the left where it belongs.
的确，这就是为什么在此可视化中
And indeed, that's why in this visualization
您会看到左侧开始放有少量数字
you see the small numbers beginning to be put into place on the left
随着我们不断突袭。
as we keep swooping through.
但请注意，彩色条形会越来越迟地开始显示，
But notice, the colored bar keeps starting later and later,
越来越向右，也越来越向右，就像布莱恩没有追回自己的脚步一样。
more rightward and more rightward, just like Brian was not retracing his steps.
一旦他点亮了数字，他就让他们一个人呆着。
As soon as he lit up the numbers, he left them alone.
瞧，所有这些数字现在都已排序。
And voila, all of these numbers are now sorted.
因此，这只是考虑相同算法的一种图形方式。
So that's just a graphical way of thinking about the same algorithm.
但是那有效率还是低效率？
But how efficient or inefficient was that?
好吧，让我们看看是否可以在此处应用一些数字。
Well, let's see if we can apply some numbers here.
但是也有一些方法可以更直观地做到这一点
But there's also ways to do this a little more intuitively
随着时间的流逝，我们也会这样做。
over time, which we'll do, too.
因此，如果是第一次通过数字架子，他
So if the first time through the shelf of numbers, he
有八个数字可供使用-他必须查看所有八个数字
had eight numbers at his disposal-- he had to look at all eight numbers
以便确定其中哪一个最小。
in order to decide which of these is the smallest.
因此，这最初是n步。
So that's n steps initially.
下次他穿过书架时，
The next time he did a pass through the shelf,
他忽略了灯火通明的数字1，因为它已经
he ignored the brightly lit number 1, because it was already
根据他已经做过的事情定义。
in place by definition of what he had already done.
所以现在他只有n负1步要走。
So now he had n minus 1 steps to go.
然后他又执行了n减2步，然后n减3，n减4，n减5，
Then he did another n minus 2 steps, then n minus 3, n minus 4, n minus 5,
点，点，点，一直到最后一步，他只是
dot, dot, dot, all the way down to the final step, where he just
必须找到并留下数字8
had to find and leave alone the number 8,
因为那是最大的数字，所以只需一步。
because that was the biggest number, so one single step.
因此，这是数学上的某种系列。
So this is some kind of series here, mathematically.
您可能会在数学书的背面回忆起类似的内容
You might recall something like this in, like, the back of your math book
或在高中时，或在物理教科书或类似书籍的背面。
or in high school, or back of your physics textbook or the like.
事实证明，这实际上是这里的公式-
It turns out that this actually sums up to this formula here--
n乘以n加1除以2。
n times n plus 1 divided by 2.
如果不熟悉，您将不会记住，没什么大不了的。
And if that's not familiar, you don't remember that, no big deal.
让我规定一下我们用来计算的数学公式
Just let me stipulate that the mathematical formula with which we
开始时，我们得到n的序列，加上n减去1，再加上n减去2，
began, where we had the series of n, plus n minus 1, plus n minus 2,
加n减3，点，点，点，最终简单地求和
plus n minus 3, dot, dot, dot, simply sums up ultimately
到更简洁的n乘以n加1除以2。
to the more succinct n times n plus 1 divided by 2.
当然，如果将其相乘，将得到n平方加n除以2。
This, of course, if we multiply it out, gives us n squared plus n divided by 2.
我现在建议，这就是给我们……
And this now, I will propose, gives us just this--
n平方除以2加n / 2。
n squared divided by 2 plus n/2.
因此，如果我们真的想挑剔，这
So if we really wanted to be nit-picky, this
是步骤或操作或秒的总数，
is the total number of steps, or operations, or seconds,
但是我们要测量Brian的跑步时间。
however we want to measure Brian's running time.
因此，这似乎是精确的数学公式。
This seems to be the precise mathematical formula therefore.
但是在本周初，我们再次考虑，
But at the beginning of this week, we considered again,
一种大O表示法。
the sort of Big O notation.
挥挥手，我们更在乎数量级
With a wave of the hand, we care more about the order of magnitude
在其上运行算法。
on which an algorithm operates.
我真的不在乎这些除以2和n / 2。
I really don't care about these divided by 2 and n/2.
因为随着n变大，这些因素中的哪一个将变得重要？
Because which of these factors is going to matter as n gets big?
电话簿越大，我们拥有的门就越多，
The bigger the phone book gets, the more doors we have,
我们拥有的灯泡越多，货架上的数量就越多，
the more light bulbs we have, the more numbers we have on the shelf,
n将越来越大。
n is going to keep getting bigger and bigger and bigger.
鉴于此，主要因素是什么？
And given that, which is the dominant factor?
容欣如果我们可以在这里请人，请问以下哪些因素，
Rongxin, if we could call on someone here, which of these factors,
从长远来看，n平方除以2或n除以2
n squared divided by 2, or n divided by 2, really matters in the long run
随着我们的问题越来越大，随着n越来越大？
as our problems get bigger and bigger, as n gets bigger and bigger?
数学上哪些因素占主导地位？
Which of those factors mathematically dominates?
阿妮卡？
Anika?
听众：哦，是Anika，但是-
AUDIENCE: Oh, it's Anika, but--
DAVID MALAN：Anika。
DAVID MALAN: Anika.
听众：没问题。
AUDIENCE: It would be the-- no problem.
这将是n平方。
It would be the n squared.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，n为平方。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, n squared.
正确的。
Right.
如果您将n取任何数字并将其平方，
If you take any number for n and you square it,
从长远来看，肯定会更大
that's going to be bigger, certainly in the long run,
而不是只做n除以2。
than just doing n divided by 2.
因此，使用Big O符号，我们可以描述运行时间
And so with our Big O notation, we could describe the running time
布赖恩（Brian）的选择排序实现的公式，啊，它的n平方的数量级。
of Brian's selection sort implementation as, ah, it's on the order of n squared.
是的，我忽略了一些数字，是的，如果我们真的
Yes, I'm ignoring some numbers, and yes, if we really
想要挑剔，并计数每一步
wanted to be nit-picky and count up every single step
是布莱恩接受的，是n的平方除以2加n / 2。
that Brian took, yes, it's n squared divided by 2 plus n/2.
但是再说一次，如果您随着时间的流逝思考问题，
But again, if you think about the problem over time and n
变得非常大，有点像Facebook大小，Twitter大小，
getting really large, sort of Facebook-sized, Twitter-sized,
Google大小，真正在数学上占主导地位
Google-sized, what's really going to dominate mathematically
这是更大的因素吗？
is this bigger factor here.
那就是要使总步数的方式
That's what's going to make the total number of steps way
比那些较小的订单条款更大。
bigger than just those smaller order terms.
因此，在大O表示法中，选择排序将
So in Big O notation, selection sort would
似乎是n平方的量级。
seem to be on the order of n squared.
因此，如果我们考虑之前的图表
So if we consider our chart from before where
我们在搜索算法上设置了上限，
we had the upper bounds on our searching algorithms,
线性和二进制，不幸的是，
both linear and binary, this one, unfortunately,
实际上是此特定运行时间列表的最顶端。
is at really the tip top of this particular list of running times.
还有无限的更多。
And there's infinitely many more.
这些只是更常见公式的一个子集
These are just a subset of the more common formulas
计算机科学家可能会使用和思考的东西。
that a computer scientist might use and think about.
选择排序是列表的顶部。
Selection sort is kind of a top of the list.
并且在此列表上排名第一是不好的。
And being number one on this list is bad.
n平方肯定比说慢得多，
n squared is certainly much slower than, say,
1的大O，这当然是固定时间或一步。
big O of 1, which, of course, was constant time or one step.
所以我想知道我们是否可以-
So I wonder if we could be--
如果我们能做得更好。
if we could do a little better.
我想知道我们是否可以做得更好。
I wonder if we could do a little better.
彼得实际上确实早先说了别的话，
And Peter actually did say something else earlier,
这就像共享两个数字并解决问题一样。
which was about like sharing two numbers and fixing problems.
如果可以的话，让我
And if I can kind of run with that, let me
建议Brian，请您回过头来看看一种算法，
propose that we, Brian, return to you for a look at an algorithm that
可能被称为泡沫排序，泡沫排序
might be called instead bubble sort, bubble sort
是一种不同的算法，
being a different algorithm, this one that
尝试更本地解决问题。
tries to fix problems more locally.
所以事实上，布莱恩，如果你看一下数字，
So in fact, Brian, if you look at the numbers that
在您的面前，您已将其重置
are in front of you, which you've kindly reset
到他们原来未分类的位置，我真的是这样，
to their original, unsorted location, I feel like this really,
如果我们只关注数字对，那就是很多小数字。
if we focus on just pairs of numbers, it's just a lot of small numbers.
像上次一样，我们试图解决大问题
Like last time, we tried to solve the big problem
并整理整个东西。
and sorting the whole thing.
如果我们只看彼此相邻的数字对，那该怎么办？
What if we just look at pairs of numbers that are adjacent to one another?
我们可以做一些小的调整并从根本上改变我们的算法吗？
Can we maybe make some little tweaks and change our algorithm fundamentally?
举例来说，六岁和三岁的布莱恩（Brian），您能为我们做些什么观察？
So for instance, Brian, 6 and 3, what observation can you make there for us?
布莱恩：是的，当然。
BRIAN: Yeah, sure.
所以6和3就是数组中的第一对数字。
So 6 and 3 that's, the first pair of numbers in the array.
如果我想对数组进行排序，我希望较小的数字
And if I want the array to be sorted, I want the smaller numbers
在左边，更大的数字在右边。
to be on the left and the bigger numbers to be on the right.
因此，只要看一下这对货币对，我就可以告诉您6和3还是乱序。
So just looking at this pair, I can tell you that the 6 and 3 or out of order.
3应该在左边，而6应该在右边。
The 3 should be on the left, and the 6 should be on the right.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
所以，让我们继续前进，然后继续前进
So let's go ahead and do that, and go ahead
并通过交换这两个来解决。
and fix that by swapping those two.
并解决一个小问题。
And just fix a small little problem.
现在让我们重复这个过程，对吗？
And now let's repeat this process, right?
在我们的许多算法中，循环似乎无处不在。
Loops seem to be omnipresent in a lot of our algorithms.
所以6和8是下一个这样的对。
So 6 and 8 is the next such pair.
您想要什么-您如何看待这些？
What you want-- what do you think about those?
布莱恩：那对特别好，因为6较小，而且已经
BRIAN: That particular pair seems OK, because the 6 is smaller and already
在左侧。
on the left side.
所以我想我可以不理this这对。
So I think I can leave this pair alone.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
8和5呢？
How about 8 and 5?
布莱恩：8比5大。
BRIAN: The 8 is bigger than the 5.
所以我将交换这两个。
So I'm going to swap these two.
5应该在8的左边。
The 5 should be on the left of the 8.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
还有8和2？
And 8 and 2?
布莱恩：同样，这8个更大。
BRIAN: Same thing here, the 8 is bigger.
因此8将与2交换。
So the 8 is going to be swapped with the 2.
DAVID MALAN：好的，分别是8和7。
DAVID MALAN: All right, 8 and 7.
布莱恩：8大于7，所以我应该将8换成7。
BRIAN: The 8 is bigger than the 7, so the 8 I should switch with the 7.
大卫·马兰：好吧8和4？
DAVID MALAN: All right 8 and 4?
布莱恩：8和4，是同一件事，比4大。
BRIAN: 8 and 4, same thing, it's bigger than the 4.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：还有8和1。
DAVID MALAN: And 8 and 1.
布莱恩：我最后一次可以做到。
BRIAN: I can do it one last time.
8比1大，我认为仅此而已。
The 8 is bigger than the 1, and I think that's all.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：
DAVID MALAN: And with a nice dramatic flourish,
如果您走到一边，瞧-
if you step off to the side, voila--
没有排序。
not sorted.
实际上，它看起来并没有那么好。
In fact, it doesn't really look all that much better.
但是我确实认为Brian在这里做了一些聪明的事情。
But I do think Brian's done something smart here.
布赖恩，您能否谈谈至少一些边际改进
Brian, can you speak to at least some of the marginal improvements
你做的？
that you've made?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
因此，至少有一些改进。
So there are some improvements, at least.
1最初是一路走到尽头，然后又退了一位。
The 1 originally was all the way at the very end, and it moved back one spot.
我认为另一个改进是，最初的8
And the other improvement, I think, is that the 8 originally
在数组左侧某处的此处。
was way over here on the left side of the array somewhere.
但是因为8是最大的数字，我
But because the 8 is the biggest number, I
不断地反复切换，直到成功为止
kept switching it over and over again until it made it
一路走到尽头。
all the way to the end.
所以现在实际上，我认为这8位置正确。
And so now actually, I think this 8 is in the correct place.
这是最大的数字，最终一路走来
It's the biggest number, and it ended up moving its way all the way
在数组的右侧。
to the right side of the array.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
这就是我们稍后将看到其余算法的地方
And this is where this algorithm that we'll see the rest of in just a moment
得名，泡沫排序-
gets its name, bubble sort--
暗示着一个事实，即最大的数字开始冒泡
alludes to the fact that the biggest numbers start bubbling their way up
在列表的顶部或列表的右侧
to the top of, or the end of, the list, at the right-hand side
正如Brian所说的那样。
of the shelf as Brian notes.
但是请注意，就像Brian一样，数字1只能移至一个位置。
But notice, as Brian does, too, the number 1 only moved over one position.
因此，显然还有更多工作要做。
So there's clearly more work to be done.
从其他顺序错误的数据中也可以明显看出这一点。
And that's obvious from the other numbers being misordered as well.
但是，我们已经改善了。
But we have improved things.
8就位，而1更接近就位。
The 8 is in place, and the 1 is closer to being in place.
那么下一步我们该怎么做？
So how might we proceed next?
好吧，布莱恩，让我们继续解决一些小问题。
Well, Brian, let's continue to solve some small bite-sized problems.
让我们从头开始。
Let's start at the beginning again.
3和6？
3 and 6?
布莱恩：当然。
BRIAN: Sure.
3和6，似乎是按顺序排列的，因此我将不理会它们。
The 3 and the 6, those seem to be in order, so I'll leave those alone.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：6和5。
DAVID MALAN: 6 and 5.
布莱恩：6和5或顺序不对，所以我继续进行6
BRIAN: 6 and 5 or out of the order, so I'll go ahead and take the 6
并放在右边。
and put it to the right.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：6和2。
DAVID MALAN: 6 and 2.
布莱恩：那些也是乱序的，所以我将2和6换掉。
BRIAN: Those are out of order as well, so I'll swap the 2 and the 6.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：6和7。
DAVID MALAN: 6 and 7.
布莱恩：6和7可以。
BRIAN: 6 and 7 are OK.
他们是有秩序的。
They're in order.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：7和4。
DAVID MALAN: 7 and 4.
布莱恩：那些乱七八糟，所以我将4和7切换。
BRIAN: Those are out of order, so I'll switch the 4 and the 7.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：7和1。
DAVID MALAN: 7 and 1.
布莱恩：那两个也乱七八糟，所以我将其交换。
BRIAN: And those two are out of order as well, so I'll swap those.
现在，我认为7也已升至排序位置。
And now I think the 7 has made its way to the sorted position as well.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
所以现在我们正在取得一些进展。
So now we're making some progress.
7冒泡到列表的顶部，在8之前停止
7 has bubbled its way up to the top of the list, stopping just before the 8,
而1则继续前进到正确的位置。
whereas the 1 has continued its advance to its correct location.
所以，我敢打赌，布莱恩，如果我们继续一遍又一遍地这样做
So I bet, Brian, if we keep doing this again and again
再一次，只要列表中的部分内容未排序，
and again, so long as the list remains in part unsorted,
我认为我们可能会到达终点。
I think we'll probably get to the finish line.
您要从这里拿走剩下的东西吗？
Do you want to take it from here and sort the rest?
布莱恩：是的，当然。
BRIAN: Yeah, sure.
因此，我再次重复该过程。
So I just repeat the process again.
3和5都可以。
The 3 and the 5 are OK.
2和5乱序，所以我将其交换。
The 2 and the 5 are out of order, so I'll swap them.
5和6，可以很好地配对使用。
The 5 and the 6, those are fine as a pair.
6和4彼此相对乱序，因此我将其切换。
The 6 and the 4, out of order relative to each other, so I'll switch those.
而6和1也一样，因此我将它们交换了一下。
And the 6 and the 1, those are out of order as well, so I'll swap those.
现在，我可以说6是正确的位置。
And now the 6, that I can say is in its correct position.
我会再重复一次。
And I'll repeat it again.
3和2乱序，所以它们被切换了。
The 3 and the 2 are out of order, so those get switched.
3和5都可以。
The 3 and the 5 are OK.
5和4乱序，所以它们被交换了。
The 5 and the 4 are out of order, so those get switched.
然后也需要切换5和1。
And then the 5 and the 1 need to be switched as well.
因此，有5个处于排序位置。
So there's the 5 in sorted position.
现在我剩下这四个了。
And now I'm left with these four.
2和3正常，3和4正常。
The 2 and the 3 are OK, the 3 and the 4 OK.
但是4和1出故障了。
But the 4 and the 1 are out of order.
这样就可以切换了，而现在这四个就可以了。
So those get switched, and now the four, that's in its place.
2和3可以，但是3和1则不行，所以我将其交换。
The 2 and the 3 are OK, but the 3 and the 1 are not, so I'll swap those.
现在3进入其排序位置。
And now the 3 goes into its sorted place.
最后，要考虑的最后一对是2和1。
And then finally, the last pair to consider is just the 2 and the 1.
这些是乱序的，所以我将交换它们，现在2到位了。
Those are out of order, so I'll swap those, and now the 2 is in place.
还有1是唯一剩余的数字，所以我可以说那个也已经到位。
And 1 is the only remaining number, so I can say that that one's in place, too.
现在，我认为我们有一个排序数组。
And now I think we have a sorted array.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
所以感觉这是一种根本不同的方法，
So it felt like this was a fundamentally different approach,
但是我们仍然到达了相同的终点。
but we still got to the same end point.
因此，现在确实引发了有关是否存在气泡或是否存在气泡的问题。
So that really now invites the question as to whether bubbles or it was
更好或更坏，也许没有什么不同。
better or worse or maybe no different.
但也请注意，我们从根本上不同地解决了相同的问题。
But notice, too, that we've solved the same problem fundamentally differently.
第一次，我们采用了更人性化的自然直觉，
The first time, we took the more human natural intuition of just,
找到最小的元素。
find the smallest element.
好吧，再做一次，再做一次，再做一次。
All right, do it again, do it again, do it again.
这次，我们通过不同的角度看待问题。
This time, we sort of viewed the problem through a different lens.
我们考虑了一下，这是怎么回事
And we thought about, it would seem, what does it
列表未排序的意思是什么？
mean for the list to be unsorted?
正如Peter所指出的，这是事情出现故障的时候。
As Peter noted, it's when things are out of order.
就像那个非常基本的原始图元
Like that very basic primitive where something is out of order
建议以这种方式解决问题的机会。
suggests an opportunity to solve the problem that way.
只需解决所有微小的问题即可。
Just fix all of the tiny bite-sized problems.
似乎如果使用循环，如果我们重复这种直觉，
And it would seem that using a loop, if we repeat that intuition,
最终将通过固定，固定，固定来获得回报，
is going to pay off eventually by fixing, fixing, fixing,
解决所有小问题，直到大问题解决
fixing all of the little problems until the big one itself
似乎会消失。
would seem to go away.
好吧，让我从以前回到可视化，重新随机化这些条形-
Well, let me return to the visualization from before, re-randomize the bars--
短条是小数字，大条是大数字。
short bar is small number, big bar is big number.
让我继续运行气泡排序算法，
And let me go ahead and run the bubble sort algorithm,
这次有了这种可视化。
this time with this visualization.
您会注意到现在从左向右扫过的是两个彩色条，
And you'll notice now sweeping from left to right are two colored bars that
一次又一次地表示两个相邻数字的比较。
represent the comparison of two adjacent numbers again and again and again.
这次您会看到标杆变得有点聪明了，
And you'll see this time that the bars are being a little smart,
他们并没有每次都走到尽头
and they're not going all the way to the end every time,
就像布莱恩照亮了数字并停下来一样
just like Brian illuminated the numbers and stopped
观察8、7和6到位后的状态。
looking at the 8 and the 7 and the 6 once they were in place.
但是他和这种可视化确实的确回到了开始，
But he and this visualization do indeed keep returning to the beginning,
做另一遍，另一遍和另一遍。
doing another pass, another pass, and another pass.
因此，如果我们考虑一下该算法的分析，
So if we think ahead to the analysis of this algorithm,
有点邀请我们考虑，总共有多少个比较
it sort of invites us to consider, well, how many total comparisons are there
这次？
this time?
似乎是第一次穿过酒吧，
It would seem that the very first time through the bars,
或等效地第一次上架，布莱恩
or equivalently the very first time through the shelf, Brian
而且这种可视化效果确实像n减1的比较。
and this visualization did like n minus 1 comparisons.
所以从左到右n减1比较
So n minus 1 comparisons from left to right, out
的n个元素中，您可以比较n个负1邻接关系。
of n elements you can compare n minus 1 adjacencies.
之后，它是n减2，n减3，n减4，
After that it was n minus 2, n minus 3, n minus 4,
n减5，直到只剩下两个或一个，此时您已完成。
n minus 5, until just two or one remain, and at that point you're done.
因此，即使该算法从根本上采取了不同的方法
So even though this algorithm fundamentally took a different approach
并且达到了相同的目标，它成功地对元素进行了排序。
and achieved the same goal, it sorted the elements successfully.
让我们考虑一下它是如何在代码中实现的
Let's consider how it was implemented in code
以及实际上是快还是慢。
and whether it's actually a little faster or a little slower.
实际上，让我们设置一个最后的标准。
And let's set one final bar, in fact, too.
之前，我们仅考虑了选择排序的上限，
Earlier, we considered only the upper bound on selection sort,
只是为了让我们有一些东西可以与之进行比较。
just so that we have something to compare this against.
让我们再考虑一下运行时间是多少
Let's also consider for a moment what the running time is
选择范围的下限-最佳情况。
of selection sort in terms of a lower bound-- best case scenario.
对于选择排序，如果您有n个元素，
With selection sort, if you have n elements,
然后，您一次又一次地寻找下一个最小的元素
and you keep looking for the next smallest element, again and again
事实证明，选择排序并不是我们的真正朋友。
and again, it turns out that selection sort is not really our friend.
例如，这是我们从欧米茄表示法上停止的图表
Here's, for instance, the chart of where we left off in terms of omega notation
前。
before.
线性搜索和二进制搜索可能很好
Linear search and binary search could very well
幸运的话，只要碰巧打开一扇门，就迈出一步
get lucky and take just one step if you happen to open a door
瞧，您要查找的电话号码已经存在。
and, voila, the number you're looking for is already there.
但是随着选择排序的实现，
But with selection sort, as we've implemented it,
通过Brian和可视化，
both with Brian and with the visualization,
不幸的是，下限并不是那么好。
unfortunately it's none so good with the lower bound.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，Brian天真地天真，每次他搜索一个数字时，
Well, Brian pretty naively, every time he searched for a number,
从左边开始，一直到右边，从左边开始，
started at the left and went all the way to the right, started at the left,
一路向右走。
went all the way to the right.
公平地说，他确实忽略了已经存在的数字。
To be fair, he did ignore the numbers that were already in place.
所以他没有一直看1
So he didn't keep looking at the 1, he didn't keep looking at the 2
一旦到位。
once they were in place.
但是他确实不断地重复自己，触摸
But he did keep repeating himself again and again, touching
这些数字分别多次。
those numbers multiple times each.
再说一次，即使你和我，人类，可以看那些数字
So again, even though you and I, the humans, could look at those numbers
就像，显然有1，显然有
and be like, obviously there's the 1, obviously there's
2，显然有3，布莱恩
the 2, the obviously there's the 3, Brian
必须更加有条理地做到这一点。
had to do it much more methodically.
实际上，即使该数字列表得到了很好的排序，
And in fact, even if that list of numbers were perfectly sorted,
他会浪费很多时间。
he would have wasted just as much time.
实际上，布莱恩，如果您不介意的话，您能
In fact, Brian, if you don't mind, could you quickly
再次对所有八个数字进行排序？
sort all eight numbers again?
布赖恩，如果我们从排序列表开始，
And Brian, if we start with a sorted list,
如果您愿意的话，这是一个不错的变态算法。
this is kind of a nice perversion to consider, if you will, algorithmically.
分析算法时，有时您
When analyzing an algorithm, sometimes you
想考虑最好的情况和最坏的情况。
want to consider best cases and worst cases.
而且似乎没有什么比这更好的了，列表已经
And there would seem to be nothing better than, heck, the list is already
排序，您很幸运，实际上没有任何工作可以完成。
sorted, you got lucky, there's really no work to be done.
最糟糕的情况是，列表可能完全倒退了，
The worst case is the list is maybe completely backwards,
这是大量的工作要做。
and that's a huge amount of work to be done.
不幸的是，选择排序并没有真正针对那种幸运的情况进行优化
Unfortunately, selection sort doesn't really optimize for that lucky case
他们已经被排序的地方。
where they're already sorted.
因此，布莱恩，我看到您从左到右使用了我们的数字。
So Brian, I see you've resorted the numbers for us from left to right.
如果我们要像以前一样重新执行选择排序，
If we were to re-execute selection sort as before,
您将如何寻找最小的数字？
how would you go about finding the smallest number?
布莱恩：所以我们早些时候决定，要找到最小的数字，
BRIAN: So we decided earlier that, to find the smallest number,
我需要从左看所有数字
I need to look at all the numbers from left
在阵列中的右边，每次检查看是否找到了东西。
to right in the array and each time check to see if I found something.
较小。
smaller.
所以我将从1开始。
So I would start with the 1.
到目前为止，这是我所见过的最小的东西。
That's the smallest thing I've seen so far.
但我必须继续寻找，因为也许
But I would have to keep looking, because maybe there's
以后为0或负数。
a 0 or a negative number later on.
我需要检查是否有更小的东西。
I need to check to see if there's anything smaller.
所以我会检查，2较大，3，4，5，6，7，8。
So I would check, the 2 is bigger, the 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
他们都更大。
They're all bigger.
事实证明，我一直都是对的。
So it turns out I was right all along.
1是最小的数字，并且已经存在。
The 1 was the smallest number, and it's already in place.
所以现在这个数字到位了。
So now that number is in place.
DAVID MALAN：然后找到下一个最小的数字，
DAVID MALAN: And then to find the next smallest number,
你会怎么做？
what would you have done?
布莱恩：我会做同样的事情。
BRIAN: I would do the same thing.
2是我到目前为止发现的最小数字。
2 is the smallest number I found so far.
然后我会仔细检查其余的所有内容
And then I would look through all the rest
看看是否有小于2的东西。
to see if there's anything smaller than the 2.
我会看3、4、5、6、7、8。
And I would look at 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
没有比2小的了。
Nothing's smaller than the 2.
所以我回到两者，然后说，好的，这个数字现在必须
So I go back to the two and say, OK, that number must now
处于排序位置。
be in its sorted position.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
这个故事对于3、4和5来说都是一样的。
And that story would be the same for the 3, for the 4, and for the 5.
就像，无处选择伪代码或实际代码
Like, nowhere in selection sort pseudocode or actual code
如果已经对数字进行了排序，那么有没有什么情报，
is there any sort of intelligence of, eh, if the numbers are already sorted,
辞职。
quit.
就像，没有机会短路和中止
Like, there was no opportunity to short circuit and abort
较早的算法。
that algorithm earlier.
Brian实际上会做同样的工作，
Brian would literally be doing the same work,
是否一开始就将它们分类
whether they're all sorted from the get-go
或完全未分类，甚至倒退。
or completely unsorted, and even backwards.
因此，选择排序的效果并不是很高。
And so selection sort doesn't really perform very highly.
因此，现在我们希望确实可以进行气泡排序。
So now we're hoping bubble sort, indeed, does.
因此，为此，我们来看看一些拟议的伪
So toward that end, let's take a look at some proposed pseudo
冒泡排序的代码，假设输入是任何东西。
code for bubble sort, assuming that the input is anything.
不管是排序还是未排序，伪代码
Whether sorted or unsorted, the pseudocode
总是看起来像这样。
is always going to look like this.
重复直到排序。
Repeat until sorted.
对于i从0到n减去2--
For i from 0 to n minus 2--
现在，这是什么意思？
now, what does this mean?
0到n减1从第一个元素到最后一个元素。
0 to n minus 1 goes from the first element to the last.
所以0到n减去2从第一个元素到第二个元素到最后一个元素。
So 0 to n minus 2 goes from the first element to the second to last.
我为什么要这么做？
Why am I doing that?
待会儿我们会看到。
We'll see in just a moment.
如果第i个和第i个加第1个元素，则此循环内的条件是
The condition inside of this loop is, if the i-th and the i plus 1th elements
乱了，换掉它们。
are out of order, swap them.
这就是我有点聪明。
So this is me being a little clever.
如果您认为所有这些数字都在数组中
If you think about all of these numbers as being in an array
或在门后，如果您从0迭代到n减去2，
or behind doors, if you iterate from 0 to n minus 2,
就像从第一扇门到第二扇门再到最后一扇门。
that's like going from the first door to the second to last door.
但这很好，因为我的状况是正在检查i号门和i + 1号门。
But that's good, because my condition is checking door i and i plus 1.
所以，如果我从这里的起点开始，而我只迭代到这扇门，
So if I start at the beginning here, and I only iterate up to this door,
这是好事。
that's a good thing.
因为当我比较门我和我加1时，
Because when I compared door i and i plus 1, at the very end
我要比较1号门和1号门。
I'm going to compare door i and i plus 1.
我不想做的是将此门我与门我进行比较
What I don't want to do is compare this door i against door i
加1，甚至不存在。
plus 1, which doesn't even exist.
确实，这将是一个错误，可能所有人
And indeed, that's going to be an error that probably all of you
在某个时候-
make at some point--
超越数组的边界，触及内存
going beyond the boundary of an array, touching memory
这会使数组中的空格超出一个或多个空间，
that is going one or more spaces too far in the array,
即使您没有为其分配内存。
even though you didn't allocate memory for it.
因此，这避免了这种可能性。
So this hedges against that possibility.
因此，这似乎是一个非常聪明的算法。
So this would seem to be a pretty smart algorithm.
但是按照书面形式，它实际上并没有理想的性能。
But as written, it's not actually as performant as might be ideal.
对于冒泡排序，假设列表已完全排序。
With bubble sort, suppose the list were entirely sorted.
布赖恩，不要让您对数字进行过多的排序和重复操作。
Brian, not to make you sort and resort numbers too many times.
您介意再给我们一个排序的清单吗？
Do you mind giving us a sorted list one more time real quick?
片刻之后，我想看看是否我们考虑与
In a moment, I want to see, if we consider that same sorted list as
以前，这次用泡沫排序，我们能从根本上做得更好吗？
before, this time with bubble sort, can we do fundamentally better?
我有这段代码说，重复直到排序。
I have this code saying, repeat until sorted.
那么，这种变化将如何呢？
So how might this change?
所以Brian，您又得到了排序后的数字。
So Brian, you've got the sorted numbers again.
这应该是一个很好的情况。
This should be a good case.
但是选择排序并没有从此输入中受益，
But selection sort did not benefit from this input,
即使我们本来可以很幸运。
even though we could have gotten lucky.
冒泡排序，您的思考过程将在这里进行吗？
Bubble sort, what would your thought process be here?
布莱恩：关于泡沫排序的思考过程
BRIAN: So the thought process for bubble sort
一次要经历每一对
was to go through each of the pairs one at a time
并查看是否需要为该特定对进行交换。
and see if I need to make a swap for that particular pair.
因此，我将看一下1和2。
So I'd look at the 1 and the 2.
那两个没关系，我不需要交换它们。
Those two are OK, I don't need to swap them.
2和3都可以。
The 2 and the 3 are OK.
我不需要在那里交换。
I don't need to make a swap there.
3和4都可以。
The 3 and the 4 are OK.
4和5都可以。
The 4 and the 5 are OK.
与5和6、6和7、7和8相同。
Same with the 5 and the 6, and the 6 and the 7, and the 7 and the 8.
所以我遍历了整个数组，
So I made my way through all the entire array,
而且我不需要进行任何交换，因为我看过的每一对，
and I never needed to make any swap, because every pair that I looked at,
他们彼此之间已经处于正确的顺序。
they were already in the correct order relative to each other.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
因此，这次这将是愚蠢的，如此明显
And so it would be foolish and so obvious this time
如果Brian从字面上回溯了这些步骤并做到了
if Brian literally retraced those steps and did it
再次使用n减去1个元素，然后再次使用n减去2个元素。
again with n minus 1 elements, and then did it again with n minus 2 elements.
我的意思是，如果他没有做任何工作，那么任何人都会在第一关中互换掉，
I mean, if he didn't do any work, any swaps the first pass,
他甚至在浪费自己的时间，甚至
he's literally wasting his own time by even
做另一遍或另一遍。
doing another pass or another pass.
因此，这在伪代码中是隐式的，重复此操作直到将其排序为止。
And so that's kind of implicit in the pseudocode, this repeat until sorted.
即使它不能完美地转换为for循环
Even though it doesn't translate perfectly into a for loop
或C中的while循环，有点直观地说明了他应该做什么-
or a while loop in C, it kind of says intuitively what he should do--
重复直到排序。
repeat until sorted.
布赖恩已经天生就认出了事实
Brian has already identified the fact, by nature of him
没有进行任何交换，该列表已排序。
not having made any swaps, that this list is sorted.
因此，他可以停下来，而此循环不会
Therefore, he can just stop, and this loop does not
必须一次又一次地继续。
have to continue again and again.
我们可以更明确地将其映射到类似C的代码。
We can map this to C-like code a little more explicitly.
默认情况下，我们可以说以下n次减1次。
We can by default say, do the following n minus 1 times.
因为在n个元素中，您可以从左看n减去1对总数
Because among n elements, you can look at n minus 1 total pairs from left
向右走而不会太远。
to right without going too far.
但是请注意，我可以在此处添加其他代码行
But notice, I can add an additional line of code here
这可能表示，如果没有交换，则完全退出该算法。
which might say, if no swaps, quit from the algorithm altogether.
所以，只要Brian跟踪多少交换
So, so long as Brian is keeping track of how many swaps
他通过或未通过，例如使用称为counter的变量
he made or didn't make through one pass, as with a variable called counter
或其他任何事情，他都可以提早中止该算法，当然
or whatever, he can simply abort this algorithm early and certainly
然后为我们节省一些时间。
then save us some time.
因此，让我们考虑一下
So with that said, let's consider for just a moment what
气泡排序的运行时间可能是一个上限，
the running time of bubble sort might be in terms of an upper bound,
如果您愿意，在最坏的情况下。
in the worst case, if you will.
好吧，如果是冒泡排序，请注意伪代码
Well, in the case of bubble sort, notice with the pseudocode
我们在做n负1次的事情，
where we're doing something n minus 1 times,
在里面，我们正在做n负1次。
and inside of that we're doing something n minus 1 times.
再一次，按字面意思重复n减1次
So again, repeat n minus 1 times literally
说，做下面的n减1次。
says, do the following n minus 1 times.
这里的for循环，这只是伪代码中的另一种方式
The for loop here, which is just a different way in pseudocode
表达类似的想法，但是这次给我们一个变量，因为我从0开始
of expressing a similar idea but giving us a variable this time, for i from 0
至n减去1--
to n minus 1--
n减2，是n减1比较的总数。
n minus 2, is a total number of n minus 1 comparisons.
所以这是重复中的n减1的东西，
So this is an n minus 1 thing inside the repeat,
重复序列外为n减1。
and an n minus 1 outside the repeat.
所以我认为给我的是n减1倍n减1倍。
So I think what that gives me is n minus 1 things times n minus 1 times.
所以现在如果我只是喜欢这种方式，那是在高中
So now if I just kind of FOIL this, sort of in high school
或中学数学，n平方减去1n减去1n加1。
or middle school math, n squared minus 1n minus 1n plus 1.
我们可以将类似的项组合在一起，即n平方减去2n加1。
We can combine like terms, n squared minus 2n plus 1.
但是，根据我们前面的讨论，嗯，这确实正在杂草之中。
But per our discussion earlier, ugh, this is really getting into the weeds.
谁在乎2n或1n？
Who cares about the 2n or the 1?
当n变大时，主导因素肯定是n的平方。
The dominant factor as n gets large is definitely going to be the n squared.
因此，如果您实际上
So it would seem that bubble sort, if you actually
算出数学和公式，将有一个n的上限
do out the math and the formulas, is going to have an upper bound of n
平方，或者说，是n平方阶的数量级。
squared, or rather, on the order of n squared steps.
因此，从某种意义上讲，它等同于选择排序。
So in that sense, it is equivalent to selection sort.
从根本上说没有更好的选择。
It is no better fundamentally.
这就是我们所说的渐近等效。
It's what we would say ask asymptotically equivalent.
也就是说，当n变得很大时，此公式
That is, as n gets really large, this formula
就所有意图和目的而言，等同于选择排序
is, for all intents and purposes, equivalent to the selection sort
公式，即使它们略有不同
formula, even though they differed slightly
就其较低阶而言。
in terms of their lower order terms.
出于所有意图和目的，啊，它们的均n平方。
For all intents and purposes, ah, they're on the order of n squared both.
但是，如果我们考虑一个下限，
But if we consider a lower bound, perhaps,
即使冒泡排序具有相同的上限运行时间，
even though bubble sort has the same upper bound running time,
如果我们考虑下限（如此更聪明的代码），那么Brian可能会
if we consider a lower bound, as with this smarter code, where Brian might
其实有足够的钱要注意，请稍等，我没有进行任何调换，
actually have the wherewithal to notice, wait a minute, I didn't do any swaps,
我将尽早退出此循环-
I'm just going to exit out of this looping pretty much early--
甚至不是过早而是早期，因为它
not even prematurely but early, because it
继续做越来越多的工作是徒劳的-
would be fruitless to keep doing more and more work--
然后，我们可以减少运行时间。
we can then whittle down this running time.
我认为-不如欧米茄1的恒定时间好-
I think-- not quite as good as omega of 1, which was constant time--
像这样，除非您没有明确的结论，否则不能确定数组已排序
like, you cannot conclude definitively that an array is sorted unless you
至少一次查看所有元素。
minimally look at all of the elements once.
因此，固定时间是完全天真且不切实际的。
So constant time is completely naive and unrealistic.
您看不到一个或两个或三个元素，然后说是的，这是已排序的。
You can't look at one element, or two or three, and say, yes, this is sorted.
您显然必须至少一次查看所有元素。
You've got to obviously look at all of the elements at least once.
因此，这似乎暗示着它的欧米茄符号
So this would seem to suggest that the omega notation for it, that
是，气泡排序运行时间的下限，
is, the lower bound on bubble sort's running time,
如果我们很聪明并且不必不必要地追溯我们的步骤，则以n的欧米茄表示。
if we're clever and don't retrace our steps unnecessarily, is in omega of n.
或者从技术上讲，这是n减1步，对吧？
Or technically, it's n minus 1 steps, right?
因为如果您有n个元素并且您进行比较
Because if you've got n elements and you compare
这两个，这两个，这两个，这两个，
these two, these two, these two, these two,
这是n减去1个总比较。
that's n minus 1 total comparisons.
但是谁在乎负1？
But who cares about the minus 1?
在这里，它的数量级为n或n的欧米茄。
It's on the order of n, or omega of n notation here.
因此，回顾一下，选择排序一次又一次地选择了下一个最小的元素
So to recap, selection sort selects the next smallest element again and again
然后再次。
and again.
不幸的是，基于伪代码和实际代码的实现方式
Unfortunately, based on how it's implemented in pseudocode and actual
代码，它在n的大O平方中。
code, it's in Big O of n squared.
但这也是n平方的欧米茄，
But it's also an omega of n squared, which
意味着它将总是渐近地花费相同的时间，也就是说，
means it's always going to take the same amount of time asymptotically, that is,
随着n变大。
as n gets large.
不幸的是，气泡排序似乎也不是更好，
Unfortunately, too, bubble sort is no better, it would seem,
在上限方面。
in terms of the upper bound.
它也将采取多达n个平方的步骤。
It's going to take as many as n squared steps, too.
但是在使用某些东西方面至少要好一点
But it's at least marginally better when it comes to using something
就像已经排序的输入一样。
like an input that's already sorted.
它可以短路而不浪费时间。
It can short circuit and not waste time.
但老实说，n平方是不好的。
But honestly, n squared is bad.
就像，n平方真的会很快相加。
Like, n squared is really going to add up quickly.
如果您有n个平方，并且n是一百万或n是十亿，我的意思是，
If you've got n squared and n is a million or n is a billion, I mean,
我的上帝，那是很多0。
my God, that's a lot of 0's.
这是算法总运行时间的许多步骤。
That's a lot of steps in the total running time of your algorithm.
我们可以做得更好吗？
Can we do better?
事实证明我们可以做到。
And it turns out we can.
而且，我们今天将考虑一种最终的算法，该算法在根本上会做得更好。
And we'll consider one final algorithm today that does fundamentally better.
就像在第0周一样，我们有点陷入了二进制搜索的局面，而今天又再次陷入困境-
Just like in week 0, we sort of latched onto binary search and again today--
从根本上说，它比线性搜索好一个数量级，
it's just fundamentally better than linear search by an order of magnitude,
可以这么说。
so to speak.
它的图片表示形式根本不同。
Its picture representation was fundamentally different.
我认为我们可以从根本上胜过泡沫排序和选择排序。
I think we can do fundamentally better than bubble sort and selection sort.
因此，虽然气泡排序和选择
And so while both bubble sort and selection
可能是我在读研究生时使用的那种东西
sort might be the sort of thing that I was using in grad school
只是为了快速整理代码然后入睡，
just to rip up the code quickly and then go to sleep,
对于非常大的数据集，它不能很好地工作。
it's not going to work well for very large data sets.
坦白说，它不会做得很好
And frankly, it wouldn't have worked well
如果我不想只是解决问题。
if I didn't want to just sleep through the problem.
相反，我们希望一开始就尽可能高效地做事。
Rather, we want to do things as efficiently as we can from the get go.
我建议我们利用一种技术-
And let me propose that we leverage a technique--
这是一种几乎可以在任何编程中使用的技术
and this is a technique that you can use in almost any programming
语言，其中的C
language, C among them--
称为递归。
known as recursion.
简单来说，递归就是函数调用自身的能力。
And recursion, quite simply, is the ability for a function to call itself.
到目前为止，我们还没有看到任何示例。
Up until now, we have not seen any examples of this.
我们已经看到了调用其他函数的函数。
We've seen functions calling other functions.
Main继续调用printf。
Main keeps calling printf.
Main已开始致电strlen。
Main has started to call strlen.
今天早些时候，主要称为strcmp，进行比较。
Main called strcmp, compare, earlier today.
但是我们从来没有见过main main。
But we've never seen main call main.
人们不这样做，所以那不会解决问题。
And people don't do that, so that's not going to solve the problem.
但是我们可以实现我们自己的功能并拥有
But we can implement our own functions and have
我们自己的功能称呼自己。
our own functions call themselves.
现在，原则上这似乎是一个坏主意。
Now, this would seem to be a bad idea in principle.
如果函数调用了自己，我的天哪，它在哪里结束？
If a function calls itself, my God, where does it end?
它似乎永远会做某事，
It would seem to just do something forever,
然后可能会发生一些不好的事情。
and then something bad probably happens.
而且可以。
And it could.
这就是使用递归的危险。
And that's the danger of using recursion.
您可以轻松地将其拧紧。
You can screw it up easily.
但这也是一项非常强大的技术，因为它
But it's also a very powerful technique, because it
让我们思考潜在的解决方案
allows us to think about potential solutions
以一种非常有趣且敢于优雅的方式解决问题。
to problems in a very interesting, and daresay elegant, way.
因此，我们不仅能够实现正确性，而且还能更好地
So we're not only going to be able to achieve correctness but also better
设计，因为效率更高，似乎在这里。
design, because of better efficiency, it would seem, here.
因此，让我提出这个建议。
So let me propose this.
记得从第0周开始的这段代码，这是寻找某人的伪代码
Recall this code from week 0, which was the pseudocode for finding someone
在电话簿中。
in a phone book.
并回想一下，在此伪代码的功能中，
And recall that, among the features of this pseudocode,
这些行是“回到第3行”吗？
were these lines here, "Go back to line 3."
我们将第0周的那些描述为循环的代表，
And we describe those in week 0 as being representative of loops,
一遍又一遍的编程构造。
a programming construct that has something happen again and again.
但是您知道吗，此伪代码中有一个错失的机会
But you know what, there's a missed opportunity here in this pseudocode
使用一种称为递归的技术。
to use a technique known as recursion.
我们将这种实现称为迭代。
This implementation is what we would call iterative.
它是纯粹基于循环的。
It is purely loop based.
它从字面上告诉我，回到这一行，回到这一行，
It tells me literally, go back to this line, go back to this line,
回到这条线。
go back to this line.
没有打电话给自己。
There's no calling yourself.
但是，如果我将第0周的伪代码更改为更多，该怎么办
But what if I changed week 0's pseudocode to be a little more
像这样？
like this?
让我继续摆脱，不仅是那一行，而是两行
Let me go ahead and get rid of, not just that one line but two lines
在这两种情况下。
in both of those conditions.
我要简单地说，而不是开放
And let me quite simply say, instead of open
到书的左半部分的中间，然后回到第3行，
to the middle of the left half of the book and then go back to line 3,
或打开到书的右半部分的中间，然后回到第3行，
or open to the middle of the right half of the book and then go back to line 3,
我为什么不更优雅地说，搜索书的左半部分，
why don't I just more elegantly say, search left half of book,
搜索书的右半部分？
search right half of book?
现在，我可以立即将代码缩短一点。
Now, immediately I can shorten the code a little bit.
但我声称，只说搜索左半边书，然后搜索右半边
But I claim that by just saying search left half of book and search right
一半的书，我声称这是足够的信息
half of book, I claim that this is enough information
实现完全相同的算法
to implement the very same algorithm.
但是它本身并没有使用循环。
But it's not using a loop per se.
它会诱使我成为人类或我成为计算机
It's going to induce me the human or me the computer
一次又一次地做某事。
to do something again and again.
但是还有其他方式可以一遍又一遍地做事-
But there's other ways to do things again and again--
而不是通过for循环，while循环或do while循环，
not by way of a for loop, or a while loop, or a do while loop,
或重复的方块，或永远的方块-
or a repeat block, or a forever block--
您实际上可以使用递归。
you can actually use recursion.
再说一次，递归就是这种技术，函数可以调用它自己。
And recursion, again, is this technique where a function can call itself.
毕竟，如果我们考虑的是伪代码，
And if we consider, after all, the pseudocode we are looking at
是用于搜索的伪代码。
is the pseudocode for searching.
现在在第7行和第9行，我的意思是说：“搜索书的左半部分”
And on line 7 and 9 now, I am literally saying, "Search left half of book,"
和“搜索书的右半部分”，即使是伪代码形式也是如此，
and "Search right half of book," this is already, even in pseudocode form,
递归的例子。
an example of recursion.
我在11行代码中有一个算法或函数
Here I have in 11 lines of code an algorithm or a function
搜索电话簿。
that searches a phone book.
在第7和9行中，我有几行代码，字面意思是：搜索
In lines 7 and 9, I have lines of code that literally say, search
电话簿，但更具体地说，搜索一半的电话簿。
a phone book, but more specifically, search half of the phone book.
这就是递归真正发挥作用的地方。
And that's where recursion really works its magic.
这将是愚蠢的，不正确的，完全会适得其反
It would be foolish and incorrect and completely counterproductive
只是使用相同的输入进行函数调用，
to just have a function call itself with the same input,
使用相同的输入，使用相同的输入，因为您会
with the same input, with the same input, because you'd
必须有点疯狂以期望获得不同的输出
have to be kind of crazy to expect different output
如果输入始终相同。
if the input is constantly the same.
但这不是我们在第0周所做的事情，也不是我们现在正在做的事情。
But that's not what we did in week 0, and that's not what we're doing now.
如果您使用相同的函数或等效算法，
If you use the same function, or equivalently algorithm,
但将输入变得越来越小，
but change the input to be smaller and smaller and smaller,
函数调用自身可能没关系，
it's probably OK that a function is calling itself,
只要您至少有一行代码
so long as you have at least one line of code in there
很有智慧地说，如果你不在屋外，
that very intelligently says, if you're out of doors,
如果您不在电话簿页面中，请退出。
if you're out of phone book pages, quit.
您需要有一个所谓的基本案例。
You need to have a so-called base case.
您需要注意以下几行代码，请稍等片刻，
You need some line of code that's going to notice, wait a minute, there's
没有更多要解决的问题，请立即退出。
no more problem to be solved, quit now.
那么我们如何将其映射到实际代码？
And so how can we map this to actual code?
好吧，让我们考虑一下从第一周开始就非常熟悉的事情。
Well, let's consider something very familiar from week 1.
回想一下当您重建马里奥的金字塔之一时。
Recall when you reconstructed one of Mario's pyramids.
看起来有点像这样。
It looked a little something like this.
让我们考虑一下，这是一个由金字塔构成的金字塔，
And let's consider that this is a pyramid of blocks,
砖的高度为4。
of bricks, that's of height 4.
为什么是4？
Why 4?
好吧，从上到下依次为1、2、3、4块砖。
Well, there's 1, then 2, then 3, then 4 bricks from top to bottom.
所以这里的总高度是4。
So the total height here is 4.
但是，让我天真地问一个问题，您如何去创造，
But let me ask the question, a little naively, how do you go about creating,
或如何打印高度为4的金字塔？
or how do you go about printing a pyramid of height 4?
好吧，事实证明，这个简单的马里奥金字塔
Well, it turns out that this simple Mario pyramid, that's
如果我们摆脱了不必要的背景，就会更加清楚，
ever more clear if we get rid of the unnecessary background,
是某种递归结构。
is a recursive structure of some sort.
这是递归的物理结构。
It's a recursive physical structure.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，请注意，这个结构，这个砖头，这个金字塔，
Well, notice that this structure, this brick, this pyramid,
是根据自身定义的。
is kind of defined in terms of itself.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，您如何制作高度为4的金字塔？
Well, how do you make a pyramid of height 4?
我会有点令人讨厌地，有点循环地争论，好吧，
I would argue, a little obnoxiously, a little circularly, well,
您创建一个高度为3的金字塔，然后
you create a pyramid of height 3, and then
您添加了另一排积木。
you add an additional row of bricks.
好的。
All right.
好吧，让我们继续这个逻辑。
Well, let's continue that logic.
好吧好吧
All right, fine.
您如何建造高度为3的金字塔？
How do you build a pyramid of height 3?
好吧，你微笑着说，好吧，你建造了一座高度为2的金字塔
Well, you sort of smile and say, well, you build a pyramid of height 2,
然后再添加一层。
and then you add one more layer.
好吧好吧
All right, fine.
您如何建造高度为2的金字塔？
How do you build a pyramid of height 2?
好吧，您将建立一个高度为1的金字塔，然后再添加一层。
Well, you build a pyramid of height 1, and then you add one more layer.
那么，您如何建造高度为1的金字塔？
Well, how do you build a pyramid of height 1?
好吧，你只是放下愚蠢的砖头。
Well, you just put the stupid brick down.
您有一个基本案例，您可以在其中陈述明显的情况
You have a base case, where you sort of state the obvious
并只做一次。
and just do something once.
您对逻辑进行硬编码。
You hardcode the logic.
但是请注意，这是什么心智弯曲或
But notice what's kind of mind bending, or kind
在人类互动中令人讨厌，
of obnoxious in a human interaction, like,
您只是根据自身定义答案。
you're just defining the answer in terms of itself.
我一直在说同样的话。
I keep saying the same thing.
但这没关系，因为金字塔越来越小
But that's OK, because the pyramid keeps getting smaller and smaller and smaller
直到我能处理那一种特殊情况。
until I can handle that one special case.
所以我们可以做些有趣的事情，用这些小纸板砖
And so we can do this just for fun with these little cardboard bricks
例如，在这里。
here, for instance.
如果我想建造一个高度为4的金字塔，该怎么做？
If I want to build a pyramid of height 4, how do I do it?
好吧，我可以建造一个高度为3的金字塔。
Well, I can build a pyramid of height 3.
好吧，让我继续前进，建造一个高度为3的金字塔。
All right, let me go ahead and build a pyramid of height 3.
如何建立高度为3的金字塔？
How do I build a pyramid of height 3?
好吧，我建立了一个高度为2的金字塔，然后添加了它。
All right, well, I build a pyramid of height 2, and then I add to it.
好了，我该如何建造一个高度为2的金字塔？
OK, how do I build a pyramid of height 2?
好吧，您将建立一个高度为1的金字塔。
Well, you build a pyramid of height 1.
我怎么做？
How do I do that?
好吧，你只是放下砖头。
Well, you just put the brick down.
因此，这里是一些触底反弹的地方，
And so here's where things kind of bottom out,
并且不再是周期性的论点。
and it's no longer a cyclical argument.
您最终只会做一些实际的工作。
You eventually just do some actual work.
但是在我看来，我必须记住您刚才给我的所有说明，
But in my mind, I have to remember all of the instructions you just gave me,
或者我给了我自己。
or I gave myself.
我必须建造一个高度为4的金字塔。不，3;不，2;不，1。
I had to build a pyramid of height 4; nope, 3; nope, 2; nope, 1.
现在，我实际上正在这样做。
Now I'm actually doing that.
所以这是一个高度为1的金字塔。
So here's a pyramid of height 1.
我现在如何建造高度为2的金字塔？
How do I now build a pyramid of height 2?
好吧，倒带故事吧。
Well, rewind in the story.
要构建高度为2的金字塔，您可以构建高度为1的金字塔。
To build a pyramid of height 2, you build a pyramid of height 1,
然后再添加一层。
and then you add one more layer.
所以我想再增加一层，我基本上需要这样做。
So I think to add one more layer, I essentially need to do this.
好的。
All right.
现在我有一个高度为2的金字塔。
Now I have a pyramid of height 2.
但是请稍等。
But wait a minute.
故事开始于，我如何建造一个高度为3的金字塔？
The story began with, how do I build a pyramid of height 3?
好吧，您拿起一个高度为2的金字塔，我在这里，
Well, you take a pyramid of height 2, which I have here,
然后添加一个附加层。
and you add an additional layer.
所以我必须建立这个额外的层。
So I've got to build this additional layer.
我要继续给自己一个层次，一个层次，一个层次。
I'm going to go ahead and give myself the layer, the layer, the layer.
然后，我将原始的高度金字塔放在其顶部。
And then I'm going to put the original pyramid of height to on top of it.
瞧，这是现在高度3的金字塔。
And voila, it's a pyramid of height 3 now.
好吧，我怎么到这里的？
Well, how did I get here?
好吧，让我继续回顾故事。
Well, let me keep rewinding in the story.
我问自己的第一个问题是，
The very first question I asked myself was,
您如何建造高度为4的金字塔？
how do you build a pyramid of height 4?
好吧，答案是建造一个高度为3的金字塔。
Well, the answer was build a pyramid of height 3.
太好了！
Great, that's done.
然后再添加一层。
Then add one additional layer.
如果我有更多的双手，我可以做得更优雅一些，
And if I had more hands, I could do this a little more elegantly,
但让我继续，然后将其布局。
but let me go ahead and just lay this out.
这是新的高度3。
Here's the new level of height 3.
现在我要走了
And now I'm going to go--
宽度4。
of width 4.
现在我要去把高度为3的金字塔放在上面，直到瞧，
Now I'm going to go and put the pyramid of height 3 on top of it, until voila,
我在这里有马里奥金字塔的这种形式。
I have this form here of Mario's pyramid.
因此，这是周期性的，每次我
So it's a bit cyclical in that, every time I
问自己要建造一个一定高度的金字塔，
asked myself to build a pyramid of a certain height,
我有点，说，不，要建一个如此高的金字塔。
I kind of punted and said, no, build a pyramid of this height.
不，建造这个高度的金字塔。
No, build a pyramid of this height.
但是该算法的魔力在于
But the magic of that algorithm was that there was constantly
这个，做更多的工作，建立一层，做更多的工作，
this, do a little more work, build a layer, do a little more work,
建立一层。
build a layer.
它是在一层又一层的隐式构建中
And it's in that implicit building of layer after layer after layer
实际上金字塔本身就是最终目标。
that the pyramid itself, the end goal, actually emerges.
因此，您可以使用for循环或while循环实现相同的操作。
So you could implement the same thing with a for loop or a while loop.
坦白说，你做到了。
And frankly, you did.
问题集1的形状略有不同
It was a slightly different shape for problem set 1,
但是您使用循环做了同样的事情。
but you did the same thing using a loop.
而且您至少必须按照我们的规定那样进行。
And you kind of had to do it that way, at least as we prescribed it.
因为使用printf，您必须从屏幕顶部进行打印
Because with printf, you have to print from the top of the screen
至底部。
to the bottom.
就像，我们还没有向您展示一种打印图层的技术
Like, we haven't shown you a technique yet to print a layer
然后回到最上面。
and then go back on top.
所以我有点在这里获得一些现实世界的自由
So I'm kind of taking some real-world liberties here
通过提起这些东西并移动它们。
by lifting these things up and moving them around.
您必须在代码上更加聪明。
You'd have to be a little more clever in code.
但是想法是一样的。
But the idea is the same.
因此，即使像这样的物理对象也可以
And so even physical objects like this can
对它们有一些递归定义。
have some recursive definition to them.
因此，我们提出了这种愚蠢的例子，
And so we present this sort of goofy example,
因为这种递归概念是一种基本的编程技术
because this notion of recursion is a fundamental programming technique
您现在可以利用它来解决问题
that you can leverage now to solve problems
以根本不同的方式。
in a fundamentally different way.
我想为此，我们需要对合并排序进行最后的可视化处理，
And I think for this, we need one final visualization of merge sort,
在Brian的帮助和计算机的帮助下。
with both Brian's help and the computer's.
敢于说，合并排序将是一种算法，其伪代码为
And merge sort is going to be an algorithm whose pseudocode is, daresay,
到目前为止，我们所见过的最简单的方法，但是看似简单。
the simplest we've seen thus far, but deceptively simple.
很简单，用于合并排序的伪代码是-
The pseudocode for merge sort, quite simply, is this--
对数字的左半部分进行排序，对数字的右半部分进行排序，
sort the left half of numbers, sort the right half of numbers,
合并排序的两半。
merge the sorted halves.
请注意，即使乍一看，这种感觉还是不公平的。
And notice, even at first glance this feels kind of unfair.
就像，这是一个排序算法，但是我
Like, here's an algorithm for sorting, and yet I'm
字面上是在我的算法中使用“ sort”一词进行排序的。
literally using the word "sort" in my algorithm for sorting.
就像是英语，如果要求您定义一个单词，
It's like in English if you're asked to define a word,
并且您实际上在定义中使用了该词。
and you literally use the word in the definition.
就像这样，这种情况很少会发生，因为您只是在做一个循环的论点。
Like, that rarely flies, because you're just making a circular argument.
但是在代码中，没关系，只要有一个特殊的步骤在做某事
But in code, it's OK, so long as there's one special step that's doing something
稍有不同，只要问题一直存在
a little differently, and so long as the problem keeps
越来越小。
getting smaller and smaller.
确实是这样。
And indeed it is.
这个伪代码不是说要对数字排序，对数字排序，
This pseudocode is not saying, sort the numbers, sort the numbers,
某种数字。
sort of numbers.
不，它将问题分成两半，然后解决另一半
No, it's dividing the problem in half and then solving the other half
也一样
as well.
因此，它可以缩小每次迭代的问题。
So it's shrinking the problem on each iteration.
现在，我将否认我们将再次需要这种所谓的基本情况。
Now, I will disclaim we're going to need that so-called base case again.
我将不得不做一些愚蠢的事情，但有必要，
I'm going to have to do something stupid, but necessary,
并说，如果只有一个数字，请退出。
and say, if there's only one number, quit.
已排序。
It's sorted.
这就是所谓的基本情况。
That's the so-called base case.
递归的情况是函数调用自身。
The recursive case is where the function calls itself.
但这确实是我们的第三个也是最后一个排序算法，称为合并排序。
But this is, indeed, our third and final sorting algorithm called merge sort.
我们将在这里真正专注于最有趣的部分，
And we'll focus here really on the juiciest pieces,
一，合并的概念。
one, this notion of merging.
所以事实上，布莱恩，我们可以过来找你吗
So in fact, Brian, can we come over to you
如此一来，我们就可以在定义合并排序算法本身之前进行定义，
just so we can define, before we look at the merge sort algorithm itself,
当我们说合并排序的两半时，我们什至是什么意思？
what do we even mean when we say merge sorted halves?
例如，Brian在这里的架子上有两个大小为4的阵列。
So for instance, Brian has on his shelf here two arrays of size 4.
在左侧的第一个数组中，有四个整数3、5、6、8。
In the first array on the left are four integers, 3, 5, 6, 8.
在右边，在另一个大小为4的数组中
And in the right side, in another array of size 4,
也是四个数字1,2,4,7
are four numbers, too, 1, 2, 4, 7.
左边和右边都被排序。
Both the left is sorted and the right is sorted.
但是现在，布莱恩，我希望您将这些分类的两半合并。
But now, Brian, I would like you to merge these sorted halves.
告诉我们这意味着什么。
Tell us what that means.
布莱恩：当然。
BRIAN: Sure.
因此，如果我有一个左半部分从最小的排序
So if I have a left half that sorted from smallest
到最大和右边的一半（也从最小到最大）排序，
to largest and a right half that's also sorted from smallest to largest,
我想将它们合并到一个具有所有相同数字的新列表中
I want to merge them into a new list that has all of the same numbers
也从最小到最大。
also from smallest to largest.
我想我可以从这里开始的地方是最小的
And I guess where I could start here is that the smallest
组合数组的数量必须以最小的一个开始
number of the combined array needs to begin with either the smallest
左半部分的数目或右半部分的最小数目。
number of the left half or the smallest number of the right half.
所以在左边最小的数字是3，在右边
So on the left the smallest number is the 3, and on the right
最小的数字是1。
the smallest number is the 1.
在整个阵列中，这两个必须是最小的数字。
Of those two has got to be the smallest number for the entire array.
在3和1之间，1较小。
And between the 3 and the 1, the 1 is smaller.
所以我取那个1，这将是第一个数字，最小的
So I would take that 1, and that's going to be the first number, the smallest
合并后的两半的数量。
number, of the merged two halves.
然后我想我会再次重复该过程。
And then I guess I would repeat the process again.
在左侧，最小的数字是3。
On the left side the smallest number is the 3.
在右侧，最小的数字是2。
On the right side the smallest number is the 2.
并且在3和2之间，2较小。
And between the 3 and the 2, 2 is smaller.
因此，我将取2 [音频不清晰]，这将是下一个数字。
So I would take the 2 [INAUDIBLE] and that's going to be the next number.
所以我正在慢慢建立这个排序的数组
So I'm slowly building up this sorted array that
是两者结合的结果。
is the result of combining these two.
现在，我将左侧的3与右侧的4进行比较。
Now I'm comparing the 3 on the left to the 4 on the right.
在3和4之间，3较小。
Between the 3 and the 4, the 3 is smaller.
因此，我将采用3，然后将其放置到位。
So I'll take the 3, and we'll put that one into position.
现在，我将左侧的5与右侧的4进行比较。
Now I'm comparing the 5 on the left with the 4 on the right.
在5和4之间，4较小。
Between the 5 and the 4, the 4 is smaller.
这样就可以了。
So that one goes into position.
然后，我将左侧的5与右侧的7进行比较。
And then now I'm comparing the 5 on the left with the 7 on the right.
5较小，因此5紧随其后。
5 is smaller, so the 5 goes next.
接下来，我将比较左边的6和右边的7。
Next I'm comparing the 6 on the left with the 7 on the right.
6仍然较小，因此下一个将要使用。
The 6 is still smaller, so that one is going to go next.
现在，我比较8和7，只剩下两个数字。
Now I'm comparing the 8 and the 7, the only two numbers left.
7是两者中较小的一个。
The 7 is the smaller between the two.
因此，我将采用7并将其放置到位。
So I'll take the 7 and put that into place.
现在我只剩下一个数字
And now I'm only left with one number that
尚未纳入两个半的合并中，那就是数字8。
hasn't been put into the merging of the two halves, and that's the number 8.
因此，该数字将占据最终位置。
So that number is going to take up the final position.
现在我将它们分成两半，每个半按原先的顺序分类，
And now I've taken these to halves, each of which was originally sorted,
并制作了一个完整的数组，其中包含所有这些数字的排序顺序。
and made one complete array that has all of those numbers in sorted order.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
并考虑我们做了什么。
And consider what we've done.
从本质上讲，我们在口头和身体上都有
We've essentially verbally and physically kind of
定义了一个辅助函数，如果您愿意的话，可以使用我们自己的自定义函数，
defined a helper function, our own custom function if you will,
Brian定义了合并两个数组的含义-
whereby Brian has defined what does it mean to merge two arrays--
专门合并两个排序的数组。
specifically merge two sorted arrays.
因为为什么？
Because why?
好吧，这是我认为的基本要素
Well, that's a building block that I think
我们将要使用这种合并排序算法。
we're going to want in this merge sort algorithm.
因此，就像在实际的C代码中一样，
So just like in actual C code, you might have
定义了一个可以完成一些小任务的函数，
defined a function that does some small task,
因此，我们现在在口头和物理上是否定义了合并的概念。
so have we now verbally and physically defined the notion of merging.
这里的思想弯曲部分是“向左排序
The mind bending part here is that "Sort left
数字的一半”和“按数字的右半排序”
half of numbers" and "Sort right half of numbers"
是已经实施的一种。
is kind of already implemented.
Brian和我没有什么要定义的了。
There's nothing more for Brian or me to define.
剩下的就是让我们执行此算法，特别是专注
All that remains is for us to execute this algorithm, focusing especially
在这三行突出显示的代码行上。
on these three highlighted lines of code.
而且，让我否认我们到目前为止所研究的算法，
And let me disclaim that of the algorithms we've looked at thus far,
很有可能这将不是真的
odds are this will be the one that doesn't really
像其他人一样迅速陷入。
sink in as quickly as the others.
即使其他人可能花了您一点时间，一天，
Even if the others might have taken you a moment, a day,
一个星期安顿下来-也许您还没有到那儿，
a week to settle in-- or maybe you're still not quite there yet,
没关系 -
that's fine--
合并排序有点麻烦，
merge sort is a bit of a mind bending one,
因为它似乎神奇地工作。
because it seems to work magically.
但这确实可以更智能地工作。
But it really just works more intelligently.
而且您将开始对驾驭变得更加自在
And you'll begin to get more comfortable with harnessing
这些原始类型，以便我们最终可以确实解决问题
these kinds of primitives so that we can ultimately, indeed, solve problems
更有效率。
more efficiently.
因此，Brian好心地将数字重新放在了最顶层。
So Brian has kindly put the numbers again on the top shelf.
他将它们按照原始的，未分类的顺序放置，
And he has put them into their original, unsorted order,
就像选择排序和气泡排序一样。
just like for selection sort and bubble sort.
布赖恩，我现在想建议我们执行此合并排序算法。
And Brian, I'd like to propose now that we execute this merge sort algorithm.
而且，如果您不介意，我会先大声念出几个步骤。
And if you don't mind, I'll recite aloud first the few steps.
因此，这里是一个大小为8且未排序数字的数组。
So here is one array of size 8 with unsorted numbers.
目标是使用合并排序对这些数字进行排序。
The goal is to these numbers using merge sort.
回想一下，合并排序本质上只是三个步骤-
And recall that merge sort essentially is just three steps--
排序左半部分，排序右半部分，合并排序的两半。
sort left half, sort right half, merge sorted halves.
因此，布莱恩，看看那里的那些数字，
So Brian, looking at those numbers there,
您可以继续对数字的左半部分进行排序吗？
could you go ahead and sort the left half of numbers?
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
因此，共有八个数字。
So there are eight numbers.
左半部分是这四个数字，因此我将对它们进行排序。
The left half would be these four numbers, so I will sort those.
除非我不太确定如何对这四个数字进行排序。
Except I'm not really sure how do I now sort these four numbers.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
因此，我们已经看到了选择排序，我们已经看到了气泡排序。
So granted, we've seen selection sort, we've seen bubble sort.
但是我们不想回归那些较旧，较慢的算法。
But we don't want to regress to those older, slower algorithms.
布莱恩，我有点聪明。
Brian, I can kind of be a little clever here.
好吧，我给你一个排序算法。
Well, I'm giving you a sorting algorithm.
因此，现在您实际上遇到了一个较小的问题，即大小为4的数组
So now you effectively have a smaller problem, an array of size 4,
而且我很确定我们可以使用相同的算法，合并排序，
and I'm pretty sure we can use the same algorithm, merge sort,
通过排序左半部分，排序右半部分，
by sorting left half, sorting right half,
然后合并分类的两半。
and then merging the sorted halves.
那么，您可以继续对这四个数字的左半部分进行排序吗？
So could you go ahead and sort the left half of these four numbers?
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
所以我有这四个数字。
So I have these four numbers.
我想对左半部分进行排序。
I want to sort the left half.
这就是这两个数字。
That's these two numbers.
因此，现在我需要弄清楚如何对两个数字进行排序。
So now I need to figure out how to sort two numbers.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
现在，具有人类直觉的我们可能显然知道我们在这里要做的事情。
Now, us with human intuition might obviously know what we have to do here.
再说一次，让我们应用算法-左半排序，右半排序，
But again, let's apply the algorithm-- sort left half, sort right half,
合并排序一半。
merge sorted half.
Brian，您能对这个2号数组的右半部分进行排序吗？
Brian, could you sort the right half of this array of size 2?
布莱恩：所以我有两个数组，所以我先
BRIAN: So I've got the array of two, so I'll first
排序两个数组的左半部分，即6。
sort the left half of the array of two, which is the 6.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：这就是幻灯片上白色的基本情况
DAVID MALAN: And this is where the base case in white on the slide
发挥作用-
comes into play--
如果只有一个数字，请退出。
if only one number, quit.
所以Brian，我可以让你摆脱困境。
So Brian, I can let you off the hook.
那个编号为6的大小为1的列表已排序。
That list of size one with the number 6 is sorted.
这是完成的三个步骤之一。
So that's step one of three done.
布赖恩，你能排序那个大小为2的数组的右半部分吗？
Brian, could you sort the right half of that array of size two?
布莱恩：右半边是数字3。
BRIAN: The right half is the number 3.
它也只是一个数字，所以一个完成了。
It's also just one number, so that one is done.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：很好。
DAVID MALAN: Good.
因此，请考虑我们在故事中的位置。
So think about where we are on the story.
我们已经对左半部分进行了排序，并且已经开始对右半部分进行了排序，
We've sorted the left half, and we've started the right half,
即使看起来Brian和我都没有做任何有用的工作。
even though it looks like neither Brian nor I have done any useful work yet.
但是现在魔术发生了。
But now the magic happens.
Brian，您现在有两个大小为1的数组。
Brian, you now have two arrays of size 1.
您可以将它们合并在一起吗？
Could you merge them together?
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
所以我将把这两个合并在一起。
So I'm going to merge these two together.
在6和3之间，3较小。
Between the 6 and the 3, the 3 is smaller.
这样我就先放在那儿。
So that one I'll put there first.
然后我拿6，接着是那一个。
And then I'll take the 6, and that one goes next.
现在，我已经完成了大小为2的排序数组。
And now I have a sorted array of size 2 that is now done.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是您现在需要开始逐步记忆的地方
And this is where you now need to start remembering step by step sort
随着事物堆积而在您的大脑中产生作用。
of in your brain as the things pile up.
我们如何到达这一点？
How did we get to this point?
我们从大小为8的列表开始。
We started with a list of size 8.
然后，我们查看了左半部分，它是大小为4的数组。
We then looked at the left half, which was an array of size 4.
然后，我们查看其中的左半部分，它是大小为2的数组
We then looked at the left half of that, which was an array of size 2,
然后是两个大小为1的数组，然后我们将这两个排序的两半合并。
then two arrays of size 1, then we merged those two sorted halves.
所以我想现在，如果我回顾那个故事，布莱恩，
So I think now if I rewind in that story, Brian,
您需要对原始数字的左半部分的右半部分进行排序。
you need to sort the right half of the left half of the original numbers.
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
因此，左半部分是这四个部分。
So the left half is these four.
左半部分的右半部分将是这两个数字。
The right half of the left half is going to be these two numbers.
现在，对于那两个，我想我会再次重复该过程-
And so now to those two, I guess I would repeat the process again--
单独看数字。
look at the numbers individually.
我将看看这两个的左半部分，即8。
I would look at the left half of these two, which is the 8.
那个完成了。
That one is done.
而5，那也做完了。
And the 5, that one is done as well.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
因此，三分之三的步骤是将这两个排序的半部分合并。
So step three of three, then, is merge those two sorted halves.
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
因此，在8和5之间，5较小，因此第一个进入。
So between the 8 and the 5, the 5 is smaller, so that one will go in first.
8将在那之后。
And the 8 will go after that.
现在，我有了第二个大小为2的数组，该数组也已排序。
And now I have a second array of size 2 that is also now sorted.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
因此，这里又是您必须倒回头脑的地方。
So here's where, again, you have to rewind in your mind's eye.
我们刚刚对左半部分进行了排序，
We've just now sorted the left half, and we've
对左半部分的左半部分和右半部分进行排序。
sorted the left half and the right half of the left half.
因此，我认为故事的这一部分的第三步也是最后一步是布莱恩，
So I think the third and final step at this part of the story is, Brian,
合并那些已排序的两半，每个半的大小现在为2。
to merge those sorted halves, each of which now is of size 2.
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
我有两个大小为2的数组，每个数组都已排序，需要合并。
I have two arrays of size 2, each of which is sorted, that I need to merge.
因此，我将比较每个数字中的最小数字。
So I'm going to compare the smallest numbers from each.
我将比较3和5。
I'm going to compare the 3 and the 5.
3较小，因此第一个进入。
The 3 is smaller, so that one will go in first.
现在，在这两个数组之间，我有一个6和一个5进行比较。
Now between these two arrays, I have a 6 and a 5 to compare.
5较小，因此下一个将继续。
The 5 is smaller, so that one will go next.
在6和8之间，6较小。
Between the 6 and the 8, the 6 is smaller.
我只剩下8个。
And I'm left with just the 8.
所以，如果我们回到我正在排序的八个数字的原始故事，
So if we go back to the original story of eight numbers that I was sorting,
我想我现在已经对左四个数字的左半部分进行了排序
I think I have now sorted the left half of the left four numbers
从那个原始数组。
from that original array.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
因此，如果您在家中玩耍，请考虑
So if you're playing along at home, think
关于-您可能拥有所有这些想法
about-- you've got all these thoughts probably kind
在你脑海中堆积。
of piling up in your mind.
确实应该是这样。
That's indeed supposed to be the case.
诚然，很难跟踪所有这些信息。
And admittedly, it's hard to keep track of all of that.
因此，我们让Brian现在完全执行此操作
So we'll let Brian now execute this altogether
现在，通过对所有正确的一半进行排序，一起做同一件事
together doing the same thing now, by sorting the right half all
完成的方式。
the way to completion.
布莱恩，如果可以的话。
Brian, if you could.
布莱恩：好的。
BRIAN: All right.
所以右半部分，您有四个数字。
So the right half, you got four numbers.
我将从对右半部分的左半部分进行排序开始，即
I'm going to start by sorting the left half of the right half, which
这两个数字是这里吗
is these two numbers here.
为此，我将重复相同的过程-
To do that, I'll repeat the same process--
排序这两个数字的左半部分，即2。
sort the left half of these two numbers, which is just the 2.
完成一个，只有一个数字。
That one's done, it's only one number.
右半边也一样。
Same thing with the right half.
7只是一个数字，所以完成了。
The 7 is only one number, so it's done.
现在，我将分类的两半合并在一起。
And now I'll merge the sorted halves together.
在2和7之间，2较小，然后是7。
Between the 2 and the 7, the 2 is smaller and then the 7.
所以现在是右半部分的左半部分，大小为2的数组
So here now is the left half of the right half, an array of size 2,
那是排序的。
that is sorted.
我将在右半部分的右半部分做同样的事情，
And I'll do the same thing with the right half of the right half,
从左半数开始，即4。
starting with the left half, which is 4.
做完了
That's done.
1完成。
The 1 is done.
现在，将这两部分合并在一起，我将
And now to merge these two together, I'll
比较它们并说1较小。
compare them and say the 1 is smaller.
因此，我先将1放下，再将4放下。
So I'll put the 1 down and then the 4.
所以现在我有两个排序数组，每个数组的大小为2
So now I have two sorted arrays, each of size 2,
我现在需要回溯并合并在一起
that I now need to backtrack and now merge together
形成大小为4的数组。
to form an array of size 4.
因此，我将比较2和1。
So I'll compare the 2 and the 1.
在这两个之间，1较小。
Between those two, the 1 is smaller.
然后，我将2与4进行比较。
Then I'll compare the 2 with the 4.
2较小。
The 2 is smaller.
然后，我将7与4进行比较。
Then I'll compare the 7 with the 4.
4较小。
The 4 is smaller.
最后，我只取最后一个数字7
And then finally, I'll just take the 7, the last number,
并把它放在最后的位置。
and put that in the final spot.
现在，从最初的八个数字数组开始，
And so now from the original array of eight numbers,
现在，我对左半部分进行了排序，对右半部分进行了排序。
I've now sorted the left half, and I've sorted the right half.
DAVID MALAN：现在，我们进入了第三步，也是最后一步。
DAVID MALAN: And now that brings us to our third and very final step.
布赖恩，您可以将分类的两半合并吗？
Could you, Brian, merge the sorted halves?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
我认为这实际上是我们已经看到的一个例子。
And I think this is actually an example we've seen already.
为了这两个半，我要做的是
And what I'm going to do in order to these two halves
只是从每一半取较小的数字
is just take the smaller number from each half
并一遍又一遍地比较它们。
and compare them again and again.
因此，在3和1之间，即1是最小的数字。
So between the 3 and the 1, the 1, that's the smallest number.
这样就到位了。
So that goes into place.
然后在3和2之间，2较小，
Then between the 3 and the 2, the 2 is smaller,
所以我们将其放到位。
so we'll take that and put that into place.
现在，我将3与4进行比较。
Now I'm comparing the 3 with the 4.
3，接下来。
The 3, that goes next.
接下来，我将5与4进行比较。
Next I'm comparing the 5 with the 4.
4较小，因此接下来要放置4。
4 is smaller, so the 4 goes into place next.
现在，我将5与7进行比较。
Now I'm comparing the 5 with the 7.
5较小，因此一个就位。
5 is smaller, so that one goes into place.
接下来，将6与7进行比较，因此6较小。
And next, comparing the 6 with the 7, so the 6 is smaller.
接下来。
That goes next.
现在剩下两个数字，分别是8和7。
And now I'm left with two numbers, the 8 and the 7.
7是2中的较小者，因此下一个继续。
The 7 is the smaller of the 2, so that one goes next.
至此，我只剩下一个数字，即8。
And at this point, I only have one number left, which is the 8.
这样一个人就可以进入它的排序位置
And so that one's going to go into its sorted position
在数组的末尾。
at the end of the array.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
因此，即使感觉我们并没有真正做任何事情
So even though it felt like we weren't really doing anything
在那个故事的几个点上，
at several points in that story, it all sort of
当我们开始合并以及合并和合并这些列表时，他们走到了一起。
came together when we started merging and merging and merging these lists.
Brian使用多个架子并不是偶然的，
And it's not an accident that Brian was using multiple shelves,
将数字从上到下移动以使其清晰
moving the numbers from top to bottom, to make clear
他有效地将该列表划分了多少次。
just how many times he was effectively dividing that list up.
我们从八个列表开始
We started with a list of eight, and we essentially
将其带到大小为4的两个列表中，大小为2的四个列表中，大小为1的八个列表中。
took it to two lists of size 4, four lists of size 2, eight lists of size 1.
虽然不是完全按照这个顺序，
And while it wasn't exactly in that order,
如果您倒带并分析所有步骤，那的确是他所做的。
if you rewind and analyze all of the steps, that's indeed what he did.
他从8变为2的4到4 2到8的1。
He went from 8 to two 4's to four 2's to eight 1's.
这就是为什么他将这些数字从最上面的架子上调下三遍了-
And that's why he moved those numbers from the top shelf down three times--
从8到4，到2到1&#39;r。
from 8's, to 4's, to 2's, to 1'r.
那么他将数字移动了多少次？
So how many times did he move the numbers?
他总共搬了三遍。
He moved them three times total.
在每个架子上，他必须合并多少个数字？
And on each of those shelves, how many numbers did he have to merge together?
在每个架子上，他最终都触及了所有八个数字。
On each of those shelves, he ultimately touched all eight numbers.
他首先插入最小的数字，然后插入第二个最小的数字，然后
He first inserted the smallest number, then the second smallest, then
第三小。
the third smallest.
但是与选择排序不同的是，他已经巧妙地将这些一半进行了排序，
But unlike selection sort, he had smartly already sorted those halves,
所以他只是一次把它们摘下来。
so he was just plucking them off one at a time.
他没有来回走动，来回走动。
He wasn't going back and forth, back and forth.
从那一半的清单的开头开始，他一直在不断地取录。
He was constantly taking from the beginning of each of those half lists.
因此，在每个架子上，他都在做n步，
So on every shelf, he was doing, let's say, n steps,
因为他正在合并该架子的所有n个元素。
because he was merging in all n elements of that shelf.
但是他将n个元素合并了多少次？
But how many times did he merge n elements together?
好吧，他总共做了三遍。
Well, he did that three total times.
但是如果考虑二进制搜索，实际上是除法过程
But if you think about binary search, and really the process of divide
然后更普遍地征服，只要您将事物一分为二
and conquer more generally, anytime you divide something in half and half
一半，就像他从8到4到2到1一样。
and half, as he was doing from 8's to 4's to 2's to 1's.
这是一个对数。
That's a logarithm.
这是基于日志的2。
That's log base 2.
确实，这就是这个架子的高度。
And indeed, that is wonderfully the height of this shelf.
如果货架上有八个元素，则额外的货架数
If you have eight elements on the shelf, the number of additional shelves
布莱恩（Brian）使用3，正是通过对数进行2的数学对数后得出的结果。
Brian used, 3, is exactly what you get by doing the math log base 2 of 8.
就是说，布莱恩做了n次记录n次。
Which is to say, Brian did n things log n times.
再次挥手，计算机科学家
And again with a wave of the hand, computer scientists
不要打扰用Big O表示法提及基数。
don't bother mentioning the base with Big O notation.
只需说log n--
It suffices just to say log n--
布赖恩（Brian）做了n次记录n次。
Brian did n things log n times.
因此，如果我们考虑渐近复杂性
And so if we consider, then, the asymptotic complexity
该算法的运行时间，即该算法的运行时间，
of this algorithm, that is to say the running time of this algorithm,
在大O表示法方面，请注意，它的性能绝对好于
in terms of big O notation, notice that it performs strictly better then
选择排序和气泡排序
selection sort and bubble sort--
n次登录n。
n times log n.
再说一次，如果您对数有些生疏，请登录n，
And even, again, if you're a little rusty on logarithms, log n,
从二进制搜索的第0周开始，
we have seen as of week 0 in binary search,
肯定比n步快。
is definitely faster than n steps.
所以n的平方是n乘以n。
So n squared is n times n.
n log n是n乘以log n，这在数学上确实是
n log n is n times log n, which is indeed mathematically
最好然后n平方。
better then n squared.
但是，与合并排序一样，如果我们考虑下限，
As with merge sort, though, if we consider the lower bound,
注意气泡排序，是的，使我们低至n的欧米茄。
notice that bubble sort, yes, got us as low as omega of n.
原来合并排序有点像选择排序
Turns out merge sort is a little bit like selection sort
因为它不会自我优化，并且会让您尽早退出算法。
in that it doesn't optimize itself and get you out of the algorithm early.
它始终为n log n，因此它是n log n的下界ω。
It's always n log n, so it's lower bound omega of n log n.
这可能是不可接受的。
And that might not be acceptable.
有时您可能会有某些数据输入
Sometimes you might have certain data inputs
可能倾向于将其排序的地方，而您不想浪费时间。
where maybe it tends to be sorted and you don't want to waste time.
因此，也许您会选择冒泡排序的。
So maybe you'd be OK with bubble sort.
但说实话，当n变大时，
But honestly, as n gets large, the probability
您排序算法的输入只是偶然地被排序
that the input to your sorting algorithm is just by chance going to be sorted
可能是如此之低，以至于你变得更好
is probably so, so low that you're just better
通常情况下，使用诸如合并排序之类的算法
off in the general case using an algorithm like merge sort that's
n始终记录n。
n log n always.
我们也可以使用条形图直观地看到这一点。
We can see this visually using our bars, too.
请注意，就像Brian在分而治之一样
And notice, just as Brian was dividing and conquering
一半又一半又一半的问题，然后重新构成
the problem in half and half and half, and then reconstituting
通过合并这两个部分，您可以在此处直观地看到它。
the array by merging those halves, you can kind of see that visually here.
还有很多事情要做。
There's a lot more going on.
一会儿，一切似乎都变得神奇起来
And it's going to seem in a moment that everything just kind of magically
工作了。
worked.
但是您可以在褪色的紫色条中看到，确实
But you can see in the faded purple bars that, indeed, this
正在将事物分成两半，然后将这些两半合并在一起。
is sorting things in halves and then merging those halves together.
而且这种可视化有些不同。
And this visualization was a little different.
它没有三个架子的豪华。
It did not have the luxury of three shelves.
它只是从上到下，从上到下移动。
It just moved top to bottom, top to bottom.
老实说，Brian在那里可能会更好一些。
And honestly, Brian could have been a little more optimal there.
我们想弄清楚总共有多少个架子。
We wanted to make clear how many total shelves there were.
但说实话，没有理由他不能只是
But honestly, there's no reason he couldn't have just
将数字向下移动，然后向上备份，然后向下移动，然后向上备份。
moved the numbers down then back up, then back down then back up.
而且，的确是您通过合并排序支付的价格。
And, indeed that's the price you pay with merge sort.
即使n log n优于n平方和ergo
Even though n log n is better than n squared, and ergo
可以说，合并排序比选择排序和冒泡排序更好，
merge sort is arguably better than selection sort and bubble sort,
你付出代价。
you pay a price.
这证明了我之前提到的权衡。
And this speaks to the trade-off I mentioned earlier.
几乎总是，当您在代码中做得更好时
Almost always, when you do something better in code
或更聪明地解决问题，您已经付出了代价。
or solve a problem more intelligently, you have paid a price.
也许您花了更多的时间来编写代码，
Maybe you spent more time as the human writing the code,
因为它更难，而且更加复杂。
because it was harder and took more sophistication.
那是代价。
That is a cost.
也许您实际上必须使用更多的空间。
Maybe you had to use actually more space.
Brian必须至少有一个额外的架子才能实施合并排序。
Brian had to have at least one extra shelf in order to implement merge sort.
如果在代码和C中实现合并排序，
If implementing merge sort in code and C,
您将需要至少第二个数组以将数字临时放入其中
you will need at least a second array to temporarily put the numbers into as you
来回合并东西。
merge things back and forth.
如果要奢侈，可以有三个单独的阵列
If you want to be extravagant, you can have three separate arrays
或四个单独的阵列。
or four separate arrays.
但是，按照合并排序的图形表示就足够了，
But it's suffices, per the graphical representation of merge sort,
只使用第二个数组。
to just use a second array.
现在，这似乎没什么大不了的。
Now, that might not seem like such a big deal.
但是隐式地，您需要两倍的空间。
But implicitly, you need twice as much space.
那可能是一件大事。
And that might be a big deal.
如果您要分类一百万个东西，现在需要两个数组，
If you've got a million things to sort, and you now need two arrays,
那就是您需要的200万块内存。
that's 2 million chunks of memory that you need.
也许那是站不住脚的。
And maybe that's not tenable.
因此，这里也要进行权衡。
So there, too, there's going to be a trade-off.
也许虽然速度较慢，但选择有点像气泡，也许
And maybe while slower, selection sort of bubble sort, maybe
更好，因为空间效率更高。
it's better because it's a little more efficient with space.
这将取决于您在乎什么
It's going to depend on what you care about
以及您要优化的内容。
and what you want to optimize for.
老实说，金钱有时是一个因素。
And honestly, money is sometimes a factor.
在现实世界中，编写稍微慢一点的代码也许更好
In the real world, maybe it's better to write slightly slower code
这样您就不必购买两倍的服务器或两倍的内存
so that you don't have to buy twice as many servers or twice as much memory
为您的计算机。
for your computer.
这取决于哪种资源更重要-
It depends there on what resource is more important--
您的时间，计算机的时间，您的钱包或其他资源
your time, the computer's time, your wallet, or some other resource
共。
altogether.
因此，我们将继续看到这些折衷方案。
So we'll continue to see these kinds of trade-offs.
但是，也许我们在这里总结时可以做的最令人震惊的事情
But perhaps the most mind blowing thing we can do as we wrap up here
分享了这些算法实际比较的一些可视化效果。
is share a few visualizations of how these algorithms actually compare.
最后一个行话就是这个最后的希腊符号theta。
And one last piece of jargon is this one final Greek symbol, theta.
事实证明，由于选择排序和合并排序，
It turns out that, thanks to selection sort and merge sort,
我们实际上可以在这里再加上一个艺术术语，即theta符号。
we can actually apply one more term of art here, this theta notation.
任何时候算法都有相同的上限
Anytime an algorithm has both the same upper bound
作为其下限运行时间，您实际上可以
as its lower bound running time, you can actually
仅用一句话描述它，而不是用theta表示法描述两个句子。
describe it in just one sentence instead of two in terms of theta notation.
因此，因为选择排序同时处于n平方和omega的大O中
So because selection sort was in both big O of n squared and omega
的n平方，您实际上可以说，啊，它在n平方的theta中。
of n squared, you can actually just say, ah, it's in theta of n squared.
在上限或下限中总是n平方。
It's always n squared either in the upper bound or in the lower bound.
合并排序也一样。
Same thing for merge sort.
它在n log n的theta中。
It's in theta of n log n.
我们不能将theta用于冒泡排序或二进制搜索或线性搜索，
We cannot use theta for bubble sort or for binary search or for linear search,
因为它们的上下限不同。
because they had different upper and lower bounds.
好吧，让我现在开始准备最后的演示，
Well, let me go ahead now and prepare a final demonstration,
这次使用一些随机输入。
this time using some random inputs.
因此，您将在此处看到一个视频，其中比较了选择排序，气泡排序
So you'll see here a video comparing selection sort, bubble sort,
并合并排序在一起。
and merge sort all together.
它们全部以随机数据开始。
All three of them start with random data.
但是，让我们看看它对算法意味着什么
But let's just see what it means for an algorithm
在最坏的情况下为n平方或在这种情况下为n log n。
to be an n squared in the worst case or in n log n in this case instead.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
选择排序在顶部，气泡排序在底部，
Selection sort's on the top, bubble sort's on the bottom,
合并排序在中间。
merge sort's in the middle.
而且您会相信，合并排序已经完成。
And would you believe it, merge sort is already done.
[音乐强度]
[MUSIC INTENSIFIES]
同时，我们可以听一些非常时髦的音乐，
And meanwhile, we have some very trendy music we can listen to,
真的只是在分散我们的注意力
which is really just there to distract us
实际上，实际上n平方有多慢。
from the fact at how slow n squared actually is in practice.
注意，这里没有很多酒吧。
And notice, there's not that many bars here.
大概有一百多个酒吧。
There's maybe like a hundred or so bars.
例如，n为100。
Like, n is 100.
那什至没有太大的价值。
That's not even a big value.
当我们谈论Twitter，Facebook，Google
When we're talking about the Twitters, the Facebooks, the Googles
在世界范围内，这些都是微不足道的尺寸。
of the world, these are trivial sizes.
但是，天哪，我们仍在等待选择排序和冒泡排序
And yet, my God, we're still waiting for selection sort and bubble sort
完成。
to finish.
因此，您可以在这里看到一点点运动确实很重要
And so you can see here that it really matters when you exercise a little bit
更聪明，并且您可以利用更高效的算法-
more cleverness, and you leverage a more efficient algorithm--
最后，选择排序完成，气泡排序仍在进行
and finally, selection sort is done, bubble sort still taking
在这里再多一点。
a little longer here.
这将取决于输入。
And this is going to depend on the input.
有时，您可能会感到幸运或不幸。
Sometimes you can get lucky or unlucky.
但我认为在这种情况下合并排序已获成功令人信服。
But I think it's convincing that merge sort has won in this case.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]